um
excuse me sir it's not recording it would
be is it gonna be cool yes let me record it
it's going to be recorded machine over there
yeah right there i don't see it yeah right
there behind behind those gentlemen
so
wow
thank you so much
um
we respectfully request the sangha of great
virtues for the sake of disassembly and all
living beings please turn the wonderful damn
will to teach and guide us how to end birth
and death leave suffering and attain bliss
and quickly realized known birth content [Music]
[Music]
new [Music]
[Applause] oh
how much of the blessed noble and perfectly
enlightened
foreign
the unsurpassed profound subtle and wonderful
dharma in a hundred thousand million eons
is difficult to encounter now that i'm able
to see in here i will receive and maintain
it i vow to fathom the dust come on through
in actual principles [Music]
[Music]
hello everyone today is the 23rd october 2021
uh we gathered here to start discussing the
sixth patriarch sutra one of the
most important document buddhist scripture
on the sudden teaching okay which is a distinctive
characteristics of the chan school of mahayana
all right so the full name is the six patriarchs
dharma jewel platform sutra okay
and on slide let's see we are redoing this
because we did this like four years ago four
plus years ago and when we first started for
our for over four years ago uh we uh my intention
was the honor of my late chinese teacher master
XuanHua and so who was hiding under his shadow
and tried to explain to simply try to elaborate
what he meant was my intention and now the
the condition change a little bit so now we
try to explain the sutra from the american
mahayana perspective instead of chinese mahayana
perspectives so uh that's why we we are uh
and we i we feel that it's worthwhile to do
it again and explain it in a way for people
in the 21st century especially western educated
people i'm not chinese but but i try i'm sort
of a hybrid person i try to bridge the gap
between the east eastern culture and the western
culture and luckily for us we have a lot of
very competent chinese speaking people as
well so and taiwanese as well no disrespect
intended to the taiwanese people
so so it is a collaborative effort i i hope
you all pitch in and we will each other we
learn from each other and and make this a
richer and more rewarding experience in particular
this is a very auspicious because uh we also
have the korean audience as well korean is
a culture a buddhist culture that emphasizes
chan meditation in particular the HuaTou they
put a lot of emphasis on that and and so this
is a in a small way a liberal contribution
to their chain culture and they call seon
seon culture as well okay so welcome all of
you thank you very much okay god when you
get on your knees like that
is it me thank you all right like so uh six
uh that's uh jump right into it uh the sixth
patriarch is the six patriarch from a chinese
lineage the first patriarch was indian there's
a venerable great master Mahākāśyapa so
there is a first patriarch of the orthodox
line lineage of of orthodox buddhism so the
very important thing here we need to take
away from this is that this is uh where if
you want to learn buddhism if you want to
learn mahayana this is where you should go
and look for good teachers these patriarchs
all right so it started in india and then
eventually it was transferred from india to
china and and to via venerable great master
Bodhidharma and the 28th patriarch okay is
there a question on JMT or just my imagination
because the sign keeps on flashing that you
know or is it just uh malcolm who cannot decide
uh uh between uh uh seoul and and uh and and
JMT huh anyway is it you malcolm yeah i recognize
his flaming hair
yeah now today yesterday is that uh it's in
seoul and today is in at uh jewel mountain
temple yeah hello yeah the world traveler
[Laughter]
all right so so the venerable great master
bodhidharma brought the mahayana transferred
mahayana from india to china because that's
at the time that's where the next competent
students would be found this is a problem
with patriarch they need to go where the students
are so that they can teach them and train
them okay so at that time
venerable Bodhidharma had to go to india from
india to china he abandoned india his indian
disciples went cold turkey to china on his
own by himself no entourage okay and he went
there and and to transfer the indian mahayana
knowledge to the chinese uh the first patriarch
was so he became the first chinese patriarch
so he's like holding two hats indian patriarch
28th patriarch from india and first chinese
patriarch all right so and he transferred
it to the uh the second chinese patriarch
by the name of HuiKe okay so what did he transfer
they didn't quite say it but what he transferred
is had to be the sudden teaching mahayana
is about the sudden teaching if you don't
have sudden teaching you cannot teach mahayana
if you don't understand the sudden teaching
you cannot
really train the next generation at all
and that's a constraint and that's why uh
when we got to the sixth patriarch six chinese
patriarch we're in venerable HuiNeng okay
he was there around the 8th century a.d all
right so now it's light number four
in contrast if you look at the hinayana hierarchy
of buddhism then you have to you want to learn
hinayana then i have tremendous respect for
the thai people the thai buddhist system why
is that because they have a long history of
training people i met some of the recent the
recent head monks thai monks and they are
very good they are they are really uh pretty
good levels of arhats four-stage arhats and
therefore that system consistently passed
on that knowledge to the next generation this
is key to buddhism buddhism is about once
you have the knowledge once you have the wisdom
it is behooves upon you to pass it on the
next generation you cannot let it discontinue
at all so that knowledge about the sudden
teaching in mahayana must be passed on to
next generation okay and similarly in hinayana
they have a way of training people so that
they have a tremendous success they produce
a lot of four-stage arhats and probably pratyekabuddha
as well even though i haven't met any yet
okay so that's the distinctive characteristics
over there and
and uh uh so they have a lot of uh thai uh
uh jargon here they're they're big shots and
uh just between us uh don't say this don't
quote me okay among them are bodhisattvas
they're gonna be offended
i saw some of them are bodhisattvas okay you
know why it's important because the bodhisattvas
help defend them against the demonic perversion
in the system because they spot those things
and say no no no cut this off this is why
you call the doctor and cut off the limb this
is a bad limb cut it off cut it off okay otherwise
the system will be
what's the word Master XianJie
tainted what else
um i'm not sure what we're looking for right
now sorry
okay i'll
what is the more polite term for polluted
deteriorate it is too uh scholar scholarly
is it like corrupted corrupted thank you it's
very serious if you let corruption sneak in
that's the beginning of the end just like
speaking of uh governments and policy and
so forth you know we go to another country
and try to change government and change the
political system and all and you don't guard
against corruption in government that's it
it will never work never ever never happened
never work in vietnam for example okay never
work in any country as a matter of fact if
you have corruption in the system the system
will fall so what happened never mind about
politics and you know uh so what happened
is that in the thai system they have bodhisattva
disguising themselves as our hearts and they
are not in power they only serve in advisory
roles and and and that's why the system is
so healthy so strong because of that reason
they have protection because if you leave
alone it alone to the arhats the arhats can
still be fooled okay so so that's why that's
why in terms of hinayana i highly recommend
you want to learn my hinayana thing go to
thailand i highly recommend it okay and they
have a council I know briefly about it i met
the head guy from thai council yeah he is
a forth stage arhat for sure
and and uh he has spiritual penetrations as
well and so forth okay so these people for
real folks they're worth the worthy of our
offerings okay i would not hesitate to make
offerings though okay yeah uh and uh the supreme
patriarch is uh this uh great monk here Rattanakosin
okay uh since 2017 and so forth look how young
he is yeah young looking he is okay and uh
all right so so that's the buddhism right
there if you want you are a believer in hinayana
okay and you say mahayana not for me go to
thailand i i don't care whoever you are okay
it's a it's a great place to learn yes sir
yellow
be the more proper adjective corrupt yeah
corrupt yeah thank you thank you very much
all right i stand corrected i should be more
corrupt okay corrupted is is not quite correct
okay all right so so going back to our small
world of mahayana because in the west right
now Master XuanHua transmitted his knowledge
of the sudden teaching to this country already
okay meaning that the fact from a fresh from
a professional perspective the people here
are better recipients of that teaching then
the people back in his country as a fact okay
no disrespect intended for the taiwanese either
all right so so he had to go to this country
to the US to transfer the sudden teaching
dharma door okay so as americans here american
has no color skin color by the way as you
can look around you only hardly any white-color
skins here at all you see and that's a nature
of american buddhism american buddhism people
think american american is like you know it's
must be caucasian no american is a mixed you
know thing and and and uh and that's what
makes america superior in my in in my in my
mind is that the ability to absorb and embrace
everything that is the spirit mahayana right
there okay so he had to go to this country
master XuanHua okay brought this chinese mahayana
of the us in particular he brought the dharma
door of the sudden teaching okay sudden teaching
meaning that those of you who are not familiar
with this sudden teaching meaning that with
this teaching teaching meaning you have to
hear it you have to you have to someone has
to speak it okay okay and and with when you
hear this when you read this you can attain
enlightenment suddenly okay only in mahayana
can you have that okay and so this uh the
six patriarch taught this uh method of certain
enlightenment if you will okay and uh and
so uh this dharma door here actually has many
access access routes it leads to that door
called certain enlightenment but to get there
has many pathways if you will all right questions
this is very important this is a momentous
moment in china when my great master bodhidharma
went to china and decided ah i'm gonna teach
HuiKe great master HuiKe this sudden teaching
thing and then master HuiKe then transferred
it to the third patriarch who transferred
the fourth patriarch who transferred it to
the fifth patriarch master HongRen who then
transferred that sudden teaching to mastur
HuiNeng and we'll find out a little bit later
all right so this is very very important and
by the way okay as americans okay
the mindset should be that we should be grateful
to the chinese for this gift because you know
it's a gift that will have tremendous consequences
for us our generation as well our children's
generation and further further down the road
as well okay this is very very critical heritage
that we we are we are leaving behind okay
so so that's why we uh since since master
XuanHua didn't really elaborate that much
about the sudden teaching when he taught this
in how long ago i don't remember the the anyone
knows he he taught this he explains the sutra
explain the six patriarch sutra is one of
the popular explanations out there for in
mahayana a lot of people buddhists and non-buddhists
like would read up on his books they find
it very very interesting very insightful and
but but he never really elaborated that much
on the sudden teaching which is what venerable
HuiNeng specialized in doing okay so we'll
dwell more on that side right number eight
uh and at the time at the time buddhism uh
was there in china already okay but just like
nowadays just like typically what happens
that that people studied books studied scriptures
and did ceremonies and so what it's called
very superficial cultivation okay substance
is what mahayana is about okay it's a it's
uh it's uh it's about uh the core your core
your heart it's not it's not about appearances
not about temples it's not about fame reputation
all right go ahead korea
JMT
good morning from korea good morning um good
afternoon to you too good morning there and
good afternoon here [Laughter] master did
bodhidharma walk from walk all the way on
foot from india to china [Music] not true
it's uh it's a myth what actually happened
it sounded good but what should happen is
the chinese would like you to believe that
he walked but it's not true actually what
happened is he boarded a boat he didn't swim
either
and then he walked to vietnam that's true
yeah monks couldn't couldn't uh couldn't ride
horses they can't they can't ride horses only
for pets but not for riding uh that's how
they keep horses yes go ahead uh flaming
hair
uh master this is more of a comment there's
a there's a rapper i listened to and he he
wrote a book and bodhidharma was mentioned
and he's he was that's where i got that from
he walked from india to china and um he actually
mentioned chan in the book and then that zen
came from chan like the japanese zen so i
thought that was pretty cool that he they
um this is kind of a rap song so it's a rapper
that got me into the um the asian culture
a long time ago yeah i hear right you you
listen to rap not as much anymore good for
you [Laughter] i'm open-minded but there's
certain things i just can't stand
just kidding just kidding all right very good
yes wei mountain oh god i always get in trouble
when i joke too much master where did bodhidharma
went to vietnam in vietnam oh my my my province
Huế definitely central vietnam
no hesitation no doubt yes uh over here black
so it is the tradition story that bodhidharma
came to china um well actually while he was
trying in china he traveled well no sorry
i think when he came to china he um can buy
a piece of leaf and then no went across the
water right no no no no no no no you chinese
a nice try no no no no no no you're distorting
the fact you're china's china person no no
you can't you you can't sneak that in no no
no no no i think uh uh he boarded a boat i
think a viking boat yeah um it was it was
coded as an example of um you actually can
show um spiritual power as a chan master to
teach people when he was in china he did cross
a river on a leaf oh yeah see your chinese
history is so mixed i saw the indian ocean
i guess indian ocean is an ocean it's not
a river yeah yeah okay get your chinese facts
straight please all right yeah he did cross
actually that's very famous yeah there's there's
plenty of uh uh drawings of him on a leaf
yeah oh i think uh that's when uh they showed
up like yeah that's chinese he uh he came
from the north when after he talked with Emperor
Wu of Liang and then he pissed off the Emperor
Wu of Liang and then he left the northern
china to go to southern china i think that's
where the the story of the one leaf crossed
the river yeah he crossed a river and on on
a leaf that's true okay yeah and and uh not
clear on how what propelled him okay
all right but it's true that he did cross
water on a leaf that's pretty impressive okay
uh and uh and so so he was actually pretty
desperate looking for someone so anyone please
who wants to learn mahayana i know from me
take it off my hands okay the chinese no no
you're too black i mean your skin too dark
we don't trust you so you know so he really
struggled and finally he found a yellow soul
i mean a chinese soul who took it from him
okay and we're grateful for that my point
here is that in all due respect okay i personally
i'm grateful to chinese culture i feel it's
because because the when when great master
bodhidharma transferred the mahayana to china
he he really
the chinese buddhism that i learned mahayana
buddhism i learned is tremendous so profound
it's so beautiful so wonderful and it's a
gift to the world really you should transcend
the national barriers and and races and genders
and so forth because this buddhism here is
to me it's beauty it's just like you look
at a piece of art it's to me it's like that
you look at a statue Rodin or or what's a
guy who lost his ear cut his ear to give to
a prostitute girlfriend van gogh okay those
things are just beautiful i mean look at this
like wow yeah you know it
it makes you feel good in your heart you know
it's not the visual thing you look at that
yeah i mean it connects from that painting
to your heart directly okay through the stomach
but um yeah but so so i'm grateful i don't
know about you i'm so grateful that the chinese
buddhism because what we got from them what
i got from Master XuanHua is it's it's so
beautiful the first time my life after i learned
mahayana i said wow this is wonderfully beautiful
okay mahayana is helps you appreciate beauty
okay yes was there a question somewhere
master what is the meaning behind venerable
bodhidharma leaving on the leaf because this
has been thousands of years and there's a
lot of painting about it meeting him what
leaving across the cross the river by one
piece of one leaf i have no idea okay when
i'm able to do that i will explain it to you
and don't hold your breath
okay uh you you vietnamese people weird you
know i'm just talking about the depth and
the beauty of mahayana he says let's go back
to floating on a leaf across the river what's
beautiful about that to me is it's a it's
indian show-off okay i'm we're talking about
beautiful chinese people chinese things okay
and taiwanese too yeah it's so difficult nowadays
you know to not offend one and and and please
the other uh anyway so anyway so this sutra
here uh it's about it's about uh the emphasis
of this sutra here is actually uh about cultivation
in order to learn about the sudden teaching
here you need to grind it out first you need
to bear the discomfort and and keep grinding
and grinding and when you ready that's when
the sudden teaching is bestowed upon you and
boom you leap okay any questions okay and
and and uh this is a function the sudden teaching
is a function of the responsibility of the
great teachers and and in a way to be fair
uh master XuanHua did transmit the sudden
teaching to his disciples but low level sudden
teaching all right and you pay attention to
how he explained the six patriarch suture
you find that yes there's some some illusions
to a sudden teaching and when master XuanHua
explained it but he didn't really go into
greater depths so hopefully we add more to
it this is important because remember okay
what we what i call american mahayana is hardly
by the skin color okay look at us
the asians are taking over silicon valley
let's face it [Laughter] all right okay on
the koreans they have no sense of humor and
this is there
ah these poor koreans a long way to go
all right so jewel jewel is his dharma that
is precious and jewel is uh is when you hear
jewel or gem that's a great value it's highly
desirable and it's so chinese to me to me
i would prefer first americans to look at
the beauty of the dharma the dharma is beautiful
the dharma i assure you if you understand
the dharma you see the beauty what kind of
beauty uh estee lauder
lancome
no beauty of people's heart
the heart you cut it up can be very beautiful
when you look at it not with the knife
okay people's heart when you get to recognize
you get to see them people's heart is so beautiful
and i yesterday i was playing with a kid a
kid naughty naughty kid okay and i it's amazing
i tell you this you know i was playing the
kid and i was teaching at the same time i
was teaching the kid about emotions and yesterday
he was playing and he tripped he fell on his
butt the right butt so he was he was gathering
himself up and touching his butt and was deciding
should i cry now or or what i'm entitled cry
am i not and he was as he was thinking i laughed
at him i made fun of him and he immediately
got the message and said i'm so this is so
embarrassing how could i fall like this he
hit behind he ran away and hit immediately
okay so so kids heart can be so beautiful
too you know anyway so the jewel here to me
it's not it's not the gem like a chinese people
would like the asians like to think you know
the indians are into gold chinese are into
jade okay girls are into diamonds i heard
and i'm into vajra
okay vajra is beautiful okay and and and but
but primarily you know the is the heart that
interests me about this mahayana here and
the heart here is is uh uh the heart of mahayana
the heart of master HuiNeng in particular
is precious it's rare and to me it's sublime
all right
platform
apparently on slide number 10 platform is
where the place where the sutra is spoken
is NanHua okay in that famous temple there
and they build a platform like here uh about
10 feet uh Wontek Sunim how tall is this when
you build this you remember how tall is this
not even 31 inches
okay and uh and the platform is a is a place
a revere place pure place where they did important
things in buddhism they transmit the precept
substance from the heart from master to your
heart that's what it happens and then they
speak the dharma to shape the heart okay and
that's called buddhist plastic surgery
all right seriously they they knew about plastic
surgery back then already uh all right 11.
sutra is anything that's spoken by the buddha
to teach us about cultivation and and and
sutra here has a meaning like to attract it's
a it's a it's the logic the uh beauty of the
teaching you know the uh the superior intellect
the superior wisdom is very attractive to
most of us and it's a and and it's designed
to give us directions on how to
what? the chinese like to say to cultivate
i don't think of cultivation i'm thinking
sutra is teaching us how to live our lives
to the fullest whether you're a left home
person or a lay person okay sutras are supposed
to do that supposed to teach us how to live
okay be happier our lives okay and when you're
happy okay you share it with your family you
share it with your students you share your
co-workers okay and uh in particular this
way of practice here is in accord or consistent
with the intent of the buddhas and the wisdom
of the buddhas all right so this sutra here
is very special because because it is um it
is the first time in chinese buddhism and
i don't know it happened in indian buddhism
or not but in chinese buddhism buddhism is
the only time that the sutra was uh recorded
and the teaching was recorded and classified
as a sutra when it was spoken by a chinese
monk not the buddha okay so it's very very
special it's really a a a treasure to the
chinese
okay so we should be grateful here in our
era us here in this country that we're able
to receive this as a gift from the chinese
okay you need to give credit where it's do
so we need to be good to be grateful to the
chinese uh
kindness and generosity via master XuanHua
okay all right at least i am grateful i don't
know about you okay so when he is explaining
sutras we go through the TianTai school for
general analysis to give us an overview what
to expect from the sutra so explain the names
uh and and uh according to that the TianTai
school the sutra is by the title it refers
to a person and a dharma analogy and a place
and so forth uh blah blah blah you know you
can you can look it up i'm i'm not interested
in these things uh it's too TianTai for me
and discriminating is the substance uh it's
talked about real mark as substance and the
real mark here is a very advanced concept
for enlightened people and this is the distinctive
characteristics for chinese buddhism okay
real mark is is by definition real mark is
no mark but uh but nothing is without mark
okay
實相無相無不相 is the chinese thing
i memorized couldn't understand it 25 years
ago okay that's all you have to do memorize
it no mark but nothing without mark that is
real mark all right yes yellow master just
a quick question is it possible that the sixth
patriarch is a reincarnation of shakyamuni
buddha no he's vietnamese
i'm glad you asked
we hear this a lot you know my late vietnamese
master said you know i have proof i written
a book on how the six patriarch is vietnamese
i say oh i know you want to live in your temple
so i'm not going to disagree with you [Laughter]
uh it's so easy reincarnation in the buddha
my in my humble opinion i feel he's a buddha
okay because his depth he's my teacher is
chinese and he's he's his level is very very
high okay but
when you look at his teachings the way he
taught his disciples see i'm he knew and he
taught me three times directly in person and
the other time is like i hear you know i go
crazy like flaming hair
ah yeah there we go again
we wouldn't believe it yesterday i was talk
that taught me about five six different emotions
he became just like that
oh no now he has a companion
all right so uh so easy is he a buddha i feel
that he's a buddha because the teaching is
so profound so so beautiful you will
okay but i don't think he is shakyamuni buddha
at all okay uh because that would be a bad
president and the buddha came he left and
he came back again say what he has nothing
else to do i mean it's like if you leave please
go don't don't come back to me it's just like
doesn't make sense there's no point being
so sticky and the buddha come and go and and
let the next buddha come give them a chance
you know so you know you guys are too sticky
no no i i hope it's not shakyamuni buddha
but i don't know because you asked me about
state of buddha wrong person to ask okay ask
something i know not something i don't know
okay what is the principle here okay uh to
become a buddha all of us can become a buddha
okay message don't sell yourself short no
discrimination okay so that's uh uh it's it's
uh anyone can become a buddha that's why no
that's why that's why now is our chance okay
we don't have to go to china anymore although
you know you want to learn tai chi i still
feel we need still need to go to china wudang
okay i will go to wudang for about a year
too i would love to go there and learn you
know i hear speaking of walking on leaves
i hear they walk on walls i saw a demonstration
he actually walked on walls i was so impressed
i said wow
anyway yeah so you can realize realize buddhahood
you can all of us can okay no one is exempt
even the lady back there who's half asleep
she can too the sudden teaching is that we
can all become a buddha just like that that
she must have to cross her legs
just kidding
it's a requirement you think it's free you
know we have to work for it and the function
is to understand the mind and see your own
nature here understanding the mind is very
interesting you get to see how mind works
your mind how your mind works and once you
understand how your mind works you begin to
be able to see how Yin's minds work you see
all right and the teaching mark is uh oh god
it's so scholarly sutra like sweet do heavenly
elixir immortality yeah so chinese i don't
like these concepts because it makes you greedy
you know it's like makes you so special i'm
i'm listening to six patriarch sutra hello
mama from china
[Laughter] i'm glad you made it the last time
i saw you in wei mountain temple
[Music]
so so this uh this uh not only is beautiful
but it's very tasty you can taste you know
that has to be real when you listen the sutra
and so every now and then you might get to
the state where actually when you swallow
your saliva it's kind of sweet that's a sweet
dew right there it happens all right and and
teaching period is uh is uh uh this uh happened
during the flower uh dharma flower or Lotus-Nirvana
period and then so forth okay all right any
questions i'm not as you have noticed by now
i'm not interested in scholarly thing i'm
just like this raw and uh and uh
limited person i'm more interested in something
that that uh that's a beautiful tasty and
that kind of thing you will have my interest
but scholarly things i leave it to the phd
people all right um five chinese patriarchs
okay now you should uh be you should know
about okay that's how uh chinese buddhism
uh started to take root in china this is important
because we need to know for our generation
how are we going to make these american mahayana
take root okay we are right now i'm my second
generation you're a third generation so therefore
it helps to go back to how it happened in
china okay because we learned from a chinese
anyway
and so it's uh it's set from the uh song of
enlightment another famous chinese uh creation
by the seventh patriarch that he recognized
bodhidharma was a 28th patriarch okay in that
proper or orthodox line of mahayana buddhism
okay and and all the indian prior patriarchs
from 1 to 27 followed bodhidharmas to he brought
all that indian heritage from india to china
and conferred upon the chinese so the chinese
inherited all the indian wisdom okay and that's
what is meant by transmitting the wisdom from
india to china okay it became chinese the
chinese became the guardian of the indian
wisdom and and and later on after six patriarch
the chinese buddhism later on really really
prospered and blossomed they produce many
great talents many great patriarchs that i
feel that for us in our era our times we should
spend the time to learn chinese and study
these great chinese teachers because the depth
of mahayana i keep on telling you this is
in the chinese language not in english yet
okay so if you want mahayana wisdom deeper
wisdom higher level wisdom you have to learn
chinese okay
any questions about that so you know where
to find look for materials and where to look
where to look for in terms of great teachers
it's not you know the uh the chinese teachings
patriarch teachings actually much higher level
than here
that's available in english that's a fact
okay so for you those of you out there who
feel that you understand mahayana i strongly
urge you to learn chinese because you should
go back to the chinese teachers okay and in
the future i hope you transfer translate that
teaching from chinese into english okay in
order to do that you have to learn chan chan
is a requirement okay without chan you cannot
have the proper translation and you find in
the sutra that we use an old version of my
master's disciples translation and it has
quite a few things that missed the mark completely
okay and so there are there are some significant
patriarchs Mahākāśyapa don't have much
teaching of him Ananda and then the second
patriarch fourteen patriarch very famous they
were Nagarjuna
Nagarjuna how how do you say it have flaming
hair
wow
master i don't know but um not what naga una
[Music]
okay and and then an uh Nagarjuna and then
uh Vasubandu is another famous uh uh famous
indian patriarch next 15. uh bodhidharma we're
talking about bodhidharma he is a prince in
of a kingdom in southern india king is very
devout buddhist it shows right there if
your parents are buddhists
then you're bestowing great blessings to your
children
because you give them exposure to the teaching
of wisdom
okay so so the conventional wisdom is that
is that when you're born into a family as
buddhist you are incredibly blessed if you
will all
uh of course there're always exceptions
but not only was uh the king was a buddhist
he is a devout buddhist and and he made uh
offerings to the patriarch so he have access
to the 27th patriarch okay and he gave a priceless
pearl to patriarch okay lesson number two
you have to make offerings to the patriarchs
to the great teachers okay so this king here
not only was he devout devoted to buddhism
meaning he helped propagate buddhism he also
made a lot of offerings supported the great
teachers the patriarchs okay and because of
that his children have tremendous blessings
okay and so this is very special family so
when he offered priceless pearl to the 27th
indian patriarch he showed the pearl the patriarch
showed the pearl to the three princes son
of the king and asked anything more valuable
in this pearl that i just received and the
the two older princes said uh pearl is the
most precious in our kingdom and there's nothing
better in the world i'm very proud of it 16.
the third prince the youngest one was bodhidharma
which later became bodhidharma said this was
worldly pearl
is not the most precious thing it is among
all the gems in the world the truth
is the supreme jewel okay
so indian okay but but back then as a young
prince he had he valued the truth already
okay he felt the truth was a treasure that
that that you that should be cherished not
not gems and jewels okay and the prince
continues he says this this worldly luster
cannot be considered the finest okay the light
the the brightness the light that's most precious
is uh from the light of wisdom
and uh the pearl even though uh has uh lucidity
but the lucidity of the mind is is the most
desirable okay so uh the young prince uh answer
is uh is uh really outstanding and so so the
it showed that this this young man here had
potential to be taught okay and that's what
great teachers recognize they recognize people
say who can be taught who would be worthy
of my efforts
yes go ahead yellow master regarding the pronunciation
of Nagarjuna anthony heard from a disciple
it's pronounced Nagarjuna
that's what i heard from one of your disciples
i think yeah yeah i remember vaguely i just
cannot remember which uh which syllable to
put the inflection on so i thought it was
from flaming hair but it's not it's from someone
else yeah i think it's from someone else yeah
yeah someone else it's clearly not flaming
hair flaming hair is still
uh all right um and uh uh and uh and uh bodhidharma
said a lot of things that you know indians
they they're wordy and they they talk too
much
you know from a child perspective if i were
the 27th patriarch which i'm not i said you
talk too much boy uh uh so anyway it it clearly
this this young prince here is a has a special
mind he's not impressed by worldly things
okay and it comes with it comes with prior
blessings if you will if your children have
blessings they be drawn to thing of wisdom
okay instead of they will not be impressed
by the size of the temple
if i could influence you a little bit
we're not like uh the kings who has palaces
and three princes and so forth you know and
and so forth what we have is big hearts
okay so uh not i'm not interested in what
the young bodhidharma had to say to his teacher
he's not enlightened back then so it's a lot
of nonsense okay but somehow the indians were
impressed the chinese were impressed so they
they they put this down okay uh to me it's
too wordy it's too many words okay it's not
chan like and later he became better okay
so after the king father's death the young
prince became disciple and uh and and became
a monk okay so you see uh that's right there
again the behavior this person is similar
to the buddhas gautama buddhas where he uh
he was not uh impressed by worldly things
by luxury by the uh the uh worldly pleasures
okay he he he
followed his teacher
and he served his teacher for 40 years until
he died okay another another another fact
about great bodhidharma is that he serves
his teacher okay and and and that's one of
the most beautiful things you can do to show
gratitude okay he showed the reason he's a
prince remember he he's used to being treated
like the potential future king future emperor
therefore he's supposed to be uh idolized
and so forth but no he revered his teacher
and became among to serve him
for 40 years that's very very impressive okay
and to me there is no
higher way better way to express gratitude
by taking care of your teacher okay i'm a
a great teacher like him and and and that's
one thing there that you can learn to spot
children or people okay okay the common denominator
of these great people is that they know gratitude
it comes from the heart your heart is big
you your heart is full of gratitude you don't
always have to take okay you can give
okay you give back to the people that
did you great favors
like your teacher like your parents like your
ancestors and so forth okay that's what uh
what uh what's special about the asian culture
okay you teach gratitude by being grateful
not not by talking about it okay and so boddidharma
served his master for 40 years that's very
impressive okay until his master died and
and his master asked him to go to china to
uh bring mahayana from india to china so basically
named him as a 28th patriarch okay and when
he came there didn't speak chinese at all
so the chinese were very discriminatory and
look at him and say your skin is too black
and you two your beard you have a huge beard
and you uh so they look down upon this scornful
towards uh venerable bodhidharma okay uh don't
know why the chinese would draw bodhidharma
bare chested with a lot of hair do indians
have a lot of hair or not chest hair they
do i never know that
watch the movies [Laughter] no we're not watching
the same movies is there a lot of dancing
like
i know you you they're talking all sudden
the man breaks down to dance and singing
anyway hairy chest
why why you would draw him like that anyway
and then 21 he met with emperor the emperor
of the liang dynasty emperor wu this is a
very famous interchange okay hey it's funny
how children so many children here today who
are listening about these words of wisdom
and have no clue what we're talking about
[Laughter] it's fantastic it's called brainwashing
you know that it's called buddhist brain washing
you bring us here we put on you you can do
the same thing at home by the way turn on
the the tapes and and let them you let them
play while they listen to all this thing we
we talk about it's called brainwashing in
the future we come they become you know uh
a monk and uh with uh uh patriarch as well
so emperor wu who is uh who prided himself
on being knowledge about buddhism he spoke
to him he said through an interpreter of course
and who is that interpreter is probably in
my humble opinion in my opinion she's that
interpret probably an ancestor our our uh
precious Zhihong
or you don't know Zhihong it doesn't matter
okay so emperor wu says uh in my entire life
i help a lot of monks and nuns become monks
and nuns because when you become monk or nun
you need to have clothing proper clothing
so he paid for the clothing for the bowls
for the shoes and so forth okay and he built
monasteries for them so they say i've done
all those and have a lot of sutras copied
okay and created a lot of buddha images okay
and how how much merit did i earn okay Bodhidharma
says none
and it says good deeds done with with with
greed worldly intent okay i would translate
it as greed okay he did all those to impress
people
okay when you do good deeds to impress others
it's it's called worldly intent is self-serving
in other words okay and so you're greedy for
recognition in other words you greedy for
rewards okay that's the wrong way to do good
deeds you should do good deeds because
because there's a chance to do it that's all
when we have the chance to do something good
just do it and then forget it okay uh that's
all and and uh so bodhidharma said you did
a good deed but you bring good karma but no
merit okay and the emperor
then pursued he says what is the highest meaning
so he he he didn't like it so he changed the
topic you see emperor's most convenient actually
after he heard the first answer it says no
merit whatsoever he says you just lost an
ear boy i mean indian guy
so he said okay but i'm going to be civil
he's a patriarch supposedly so i can be i'm
an emperor so i need to show my civil side
so he said he changed the subject i said what
is what he said what is the highest meaning
of the noble truth okay see it's very well
read bodhidharma says there's no there's no
no noble truth there's only emptiness okay
Bodhidharma by then was a little bit
cautious because he could tell that the emperor
was not happy with him and there's no point
in offending him and more than he needs to
he needed to so he said there's no noble truth
there's only emptiness actually he could have
said from a chan perspective what is the highest
meaning or noble truth
he could have said nothing but no he said
there's no noble truth there's only emptiness
so you can tell he's scared 23 and then the
emperor again was stumped he said i can't
pursue this so let's give him another one
last chance who's standing before me okay
meaning 朕 朕 is chinese for i'm better
than you you see he says i'm better than you
i'm i'm nobility and you are
black um
dark skinned i mean and the bodhidharma says
i know not your majesty okay
i know not the proper translation should be
changed to i cannot tell
Master XianJie don't just sit there do something
i cannot tell you see the the immediate answer
is so beautiful he says uh i said it says
who's in front of me can you try change it
please who's in front of me okay who's facing
me
either one
okay
and so the brutal answer from from bodhidharma
he meant in english is
i can't tell
all right so after that the emperor gave up
and uh he said uh excuse me i need to go take
this phone call here
from russia
and so later he had an advisor would you believe
it's ZhiGong ZhiGong is one of the of the
wisest chinese monks and what does he do advising
this kind of emperor oh my goodness i when
i got to this point here i lost all respect
for ZhiGong
because if you hang around this person he
was thirsty for power recognition agreed he
was so greedy okay the only way that you can
help is yourself
because that's how he sees you okay if ZhiGong
is a true patriarch a great the person wisdom
is that i'm sorry your master okay i'm not
worthy of your patronage here's uh the master
at the DRBA go go there
okay yeah so uh i i it's a personal thing
for me because i know i was growing up i mean
when i was learning the way uh master XuanHua
spoke so highly of master ZhiGong he had spiritual
powers and so forth when he got to this point
here i said what are you doing advising this
emperor so he's this way because you advise
him
so he's your creation he's a product of your
training right so i would run uh okay that's
why ZhiGong is you know out uh so ZhiGong
says your highness still don't recognize this
person
so you don't recognize this person okay and
the emperor says uh i don't and ZhiGong says
this is GuanYin transmitting a buddha's mind
seal
okay so ZhiGong says bodhidharma actually
is guan yin
so clearly GuanYin has nothing else to do
but we we have so many bodhisattvas and GuanYin
says let me bring mahayana from india to china
you the rest you can go on vacation go to
the bahamas or you take a hike you know something
let me do it for you so the rest of bodhisattvas
so we don't get a chance to create blessings
for ourselves okay so i don't know about this
ZhiGong guy here okay yeah it all due respect
to the chinese and taiwanese people
and um and so the the emperor heard that this
is a sage so he was he he uh he had second
thoughts and tried to uh send his uh uh his
boy to ask the venerable bodhidharma to backtrack
and come back so that he can make offerings
and support him
and and ZhiGong says no don't bother uh uh
even if uh uh uh even if the entire nation
goes all our people go okay he uh still wouldn't
come back
okay so he says [CHinese] and she says even
if
we all go okay
he still would not will not come back not
return would come back all right and so this
is a story of a transmission from india mahayana
from India to china so when venerable Bodhidharama
went to nanjing listen speak dharma and back
then is typical as difficult as it is nowadays
people speak dharma without wisdom they spoke
words they didn't they didn't teach from the
wisdom but from regurgitating the the the
technical jargon but even doing even for just
doing so the heavens the rain fragrant blossoms
and golden petals lotus rose from earth okay
and so he's uh he's a extraordinary dharma
master to the point where the heavens were
making offerings to him and so bodhidharma
stopped by listened to his lecture and waited
for everyone to leave and cornered dharma
master of ShenGuang and asked him what what
are you doing ShenGuang says i am explaining
sutras can't you tell
and i said why are you explaining the sutras
he said the answer is uh to teach people to
end birth and death and bodhidharma says how
does it happen okay the words are black and
white how does black and white you know things
can end birth and death and ShenGuang couldn't
have an answer and this is a lesson i learned
do not offend the chinese patriarchs the the
chinese the chinese dharma masters okay it's
okay for you to offend me because i'm not
chinese but but this is a common protocol
in that you don't you don't ask questions
that that dharma masters cannot answer okay
please
and uh but ShenGuang is a little bit have
a little bit of temp uh temper he got very
upset and he whipped out his beads uh made
of steels okay and whacked them he says these
are the words of the demons and broke the
two front tooth so bodhidharma has a new nickname
leon [?]
yeah
so uh
you know so whack him and say you are the
demon how dare you embarrass me how you say
demon's work you're doing demons yeah and
and so he broke his teeth because bodhidharma
didn't dodge at all i remember and to this
point i remember that video of president bush
the small one when he went to afghanistan
someone threw a shoe at him
he went like this he knocked and he ducked
in a funny way too
but bodhidharma is like a true indian patriarch
stood there and lost two teeth
i hope he gets good dentist
can you imagine we speak dharma and then as
we smile and the front of our mouth is black
oh yeah yeah
what was he thinking
i would have ducked myself like little bush
and uh Bodhidharma apparently according to
chinese the chinese wisdom he says there's
a legend where it sage's tooth fall to the
earth it would not rain for three years that's
probably what happened here in california
and so bodhidharma says that would harm a
lot of people so i better take the pain and
suffering instead of letting bad things happen
to the chinese people although they deserve
it so uh so the tooth fell out and so he swallowed
it okay
and then he went away okay and then and then
uh according to master XuanHua yes did you
have a comment black white red
that video person audio person he sees like
in a trance
yeah right yeah so my question is by swallowing
the teeth that it solves the problem so it
will rain for three years or it solved that
problem or no it wouldn't rain for three years
for that the the dragon's intervention
but uh at least there won't be a a drought
for three years because it would if if he
let the tooth the teeth fell fall to the ground
they would have a drought for three years
there would be no drought for next because
of that okay so uh
so uh
he swallowed them and disappeared okay and
and uh and and uh so according to Master XuanHua
i remember this part master XuanHua then said
uh immediately right after that and you know
please take a grain of salt you know he's
not here so we don't know if i i there's lots
of things folks i wish i were there because
i have so many questions uh i'm not like a
typical american who are you know very afraid
of master XuanHua i would ask him uh great
master really i mean i hit the thing and all
of a sudden the venerable ShenGuang was supposed
to die right away do you buy that or not i
find it's too much a coincidence what's the
rationale for that you believe or not when
i read that story i said seriously
you hit someone and broke two tooth i mean
leon spins never you know killed anyone because
of that no one died because of that
but there is a point to this story why did
he die immediately because he inflicted harm
on a great great sage supposedly GuanYin according
to ZhiGong which i respectfully disagree okay
GuanYin would never fight with the bodhisattvas
would not compete for for blessings from bodhisattvas
i assure you okay we have so many great bodhisattvas
who are waiting for craving to bring mayana
from india to china why would GuanYin bodhisattva
steal those very virtues from them think about
it it just didn't make sense to me okay anyway
so what happened is this monk here
this uh this uh this uh this monk here ShenGuang
okay
injured a great sage for that mere factor
he supposed to fall to the avicii hell the
worst hells there is just for that that's
how serious it is okay and therefore
it's perfectly reasonable to say that he's
supposed to die right away because you know
how how big of a name bodhidharma was then
he deserves to die immediately because it's
very serious offense so
so he's supposed to die so two ghosts came
and said our boss king yama would like to
have a word with you which is the you know
the the underworld uh word for okay it's time
for you to go okay and bodhidharma said uh
no the ShenGuang says why i'm so young in
a prime of my life you know can i have some
more time he said nope your time is up just
like that i say yep
so so ShenGuang says what did i do what did
i do and he said you don't know you broke
the two front teeth of a great sage that's
why and so ShenGuang says
oh i didn't know if i knew i would have not
done it the ghost says not my problem
okay let's go and uh and ShenGuang got on
his knees i think and then begged to the ghost
says look at me i'm the dharma master you're
the ghost i'm beg to you give me some time
so that i uh learned from this monk a little
bit so that my life would not have been in
vain okay and and so the ghosts must be high-ranking
ghosts it says okay i'm not seeing that you
are sincere i allow you a little bit of time
go and look for that monk and and uh and uh
do you think we'll wait a little bit for you
and so ShenGuang ran after after bodhidharma
by that time okay bodhidharma was walking
towards the south yes he went south is it
sound
no that sixth patriarch you confused
so we went somewhere
and he passed by a house where they kept there's
a bird is kept in a cage a bird cage okay
and and the bird
recognized bodhidharma and said
recognize somehow this bird recognized bodhidharma
as a sage so the bird asked him mind from
the west mind from west please teach me a
way to escape from this cage uh flaming hair
can you do it in in a more birdy kind of way
try your best word language now
very good very good yeah
one more time second version
unmuted hey korea unmuted
i can't hear you master can you hear me okay
now now faster go okay mind from the west
mind from the west please teach me how to
escape from this cage
and bodhidharm immediately replied okay let's
find a new voice
china's chinese person there
huh so bodhidharma replied to escape from
the cages escape from the cage put out both
legs close both eyes this is a way to escape
from the cage okay spoke bird language
and and
and
and that's what the bird did and uh the owner
thought the bird oh it was dead so open the
cage and try to to uh take the body out but
uh the bird flew out okay so that's how the
bird escaped okay the great escape if you
will great bird escape so anyway the story
legend has ShenGuang ran after bodhidharma
and went all the way to be a bear's ear mountain
in LuoYang and sat down facing a wall that's
right behind the future shaolin temple okay
and ShenGuang knelt close by behind him apparently
for nine years and when i read this i said
nine years uh how can you do that for nine
years well anyway so he sat for nine years
and i'm first question is uh what about bathroom
breaks uh and uh and uh so they sat behind
uh master bodhidharma for for nine years and
bodhidharma ignored him completely didn't
talk to him for nine years okay and ShenGuang
never gave up it's a test it's a test and
and uh test of sincerity okay and one day
after nine years ShenGuang
never dared bother bodhidharma if you were
there and begging for instruction you don't
want to nag him you know Qun you hear you
don't want to nag okay uh i would not nag
okay for something important i would not nag
and uh and uh
and and one day
bodhidharma asked him a question this is very
important there's a protocol here you would
kneel behind you ask for a favor you ask once
and you wait okay you don't nag and then and
then so he waited for nine years this is beautiful
this is so beautiful of a story to me okay
it is so important to you he said how do i
end birth and death venerable master teach
me how to end birth and death all right you
don't text him to death
okay you ask once how can I end birth and
death and then you kneel down and you wait
you can do anything you like you can
but you don't nag him anymore
the timing is always perfect
and and uh so after nine years interestingly
uh this is so remarkable about venerable ShenGuang
i'm impressed by that that for us in my era
waiting for nine years behind him like that
is total nonsense the sheer nonsense i don't
know about you i cannot do this no way it
doesn't make sense to me okay
that's why i'm glad that ShenGuang did it
for us
thank you china and
and uh and after nine years uh so it's like
it's interestingly like a delay how do i how
how do i end birth and death okay and venerable
bodhidharma didn't say anything for nine years
ignore him completely and the guy would not
go away so after nine years and Bodhidharma
saying you're still here
what's the matter with you i said i'm waiting
for the answer i said i will answer you when
the snow becomes red
and so ShenGuang uh uh got so upset and then
he took out a knife and cut his left arm right
arm this is what i don't remember his arm
right arm okay yeah i am right handed i think
i would take my left arm cut my right arm
it shows more it's more emphatic
so in this movie of mine you take this knife
here this probably has not been sharpened
yet and you hack away your arm
so anyway so it finally cut off and fell to
the ground and the snow become red became
red so he scooped up some red snow with tainted
with blood corrupt with blood and then and
then and so great master great master hey
this the snow there's red snow the snow has
become red and uh now master XuanHua says
uh venerable ShenGuang was so upset he had
a temper so he cut his arm off to show him
uh he's probably right i would never disagree
with my my chinese teacher okay yeah ching
[Laughter] so so Bodhidharma is impressed
and and they say ah and you you are a pretty
tough cookie
and and and uh
and so it is so it is it says wow you're tough
so you're tough okay
right so it is you're so tough so am i okay
you're crazy so am i
and he says he says you are worthy to be my
student okay so i will teach you i teach you
what i know okay and uh so my weight has not
been in vain imagine this guy this great teacher
has been looking for a descendant for a successor
for a long time he saw it in venerable ShenGuang
but still put him through the test okay a
lot of in buddhism is about enduring the test
okay and and that's called what what is that
called
gradual teaching the tests are gradual teaching
you see that that's how mahayana was transmitted
from india to china
gradually teaching for nine years so he sat
there he knelt behind him for nine years so
every day he said oh my legs hurt i hurt so
much what am i doing here what am i doing
here i can't even tell my mother about this
she doesn't want me to become a monk in the
first place now i had to tell her i'm kneeing
behind this dark-skinned monk who cannot speak
a single word of chinese and when he decides
to teach me how we're gonna what are we gonna
use google translate
you see he has so many issues there that's
unresolved okay and yet he knelt and bodhidharma
didn't talk to him he didn't dare ask okay
yeah and and uh so part of the teaching is
you need to go through hardship because that's
part of your gradual training
don't expect shortcuts they say tell me the
best thing give me the give me the sudden
teaching right away okay no you have to pass
the test you have to go through the gradual
training first and then there's a final test
when you actually have to cut off your arm
is that a question you asked do you have to
cut off your arm yes i have a question it's
another question a little bit random uh it's
associated what you just talk about the conversation
between ShenGuang and uh um Bodhidharma yeah
like i'm curious back then what kind of language
they are using when they communicate with
each other do they speak chinese or do they
speak indian language how did they communicate
with each other
[Music] what did i tell you
i will forgive you this one time you never
ask a question i cannot answer okay i'm sorry
okay don't do it again next question how do
i know i wasn't there but if i have to lie
to you okay how do they communicate that's
a good question you see you're so lucky i
am so lenient because i had the same question
too i said you know the guy didn't speak chinese
and the other guy didn't speak indian how
could they talk snow red and all those things
is not vocabulary come on i'm missing something
here yes old monk
[Venerable XianChi speaking in Vietnamese]
ok let master XianRen translate this important
message um master whatever the sage sageely
people did we cannot talk about it but uh
earlier we went through the story that the
patriarch talked to the bird actually the
bird asked the question and then the patriarch
give it the instruction and then the bird
understand and then another story is Yongan
when she meditate and she saw amitabha buddha
appeared wearing a yellow rope and she uh
in her mind arrives a question like why the
buddha where why amitabh buddha wear yellow
rope and suddenly an answer came to her mind
like wait until you die that's when i will
wear a red rope so the buddha can communicate
through the mind and the same thing like in
1976 when i was in the prison and then i in
my dream i saw buddha appear and then i i
have a question i had a question in my mind
and then suddenly the buddha answered me using
the vietnamese he didn't use chinese or english
or whatever he used vietnamese to help me
to understand so in the sutra avatamsaka sutra
say that the buddha has a lot of different
way to communicate to help beings understand
you get that you buy that you believe anything
do you
when you think you think in what language
you think in chinese yes yes
in you think vietnamese or english english
okay but you are vietnamese right
okay vietnamese chinese her mother is vietnamese
chinese okay so you have chinese here english
here
XiaoTai when you think what do you think in
what language do you use
chinese and english chinese and english half
chinese half english very good okay you see
so uh so what happened is that the thinking
do you really think is in chinese or english
how come she thinks in english how come you
think in in chinese
before you verbalize it right when you think
chinese [Some Garbled Chinese]
so these are thoughts how come sees she hears
herself as in chinese and she hears herself
as english why
my master when i was a novice and i was supposed
to train to sit sleep okay and i hate it i
hate it say we suffer all day eat one meal
a day and we can't even sleep with in comfort
what kind of what kind of nonsense is this
so i really struggled with that concept having
to sit sleep and i tried two years unsuccessfully
okay
and then one night in long beach monastry
after two years okay i was sleeping i started
as usual with sitting and then eventually
i slide down slowly slowly slowly slowly and
lean against the wall and then pretty soon
you unbuckle a little bit
a little bit very slow motion and eventually
us like that no no not even
actually listening to our lecture seriously
he's not even playing his kids out there
and and one night i was doing that like every
single night okay and one night i heard
i heard master XuanHua's voice okay he said
he said uh
get up
cross your legs
he's screaming at me seriously
and i immediately jumped up crossed my legs
without thinking i was so scared i never saw
him that angry i always have this you know
the last time i saw me was you know he was
dying okay he was on his deathbed he said
oh i love you you know and you're all so good
you're such a wonderful student and so forth
okay but never been that angry before okay
i was so scared i immediately crossed my legs
and set the rest of the night in full lotus
and right after that i could easily sit in
full lotus every single night
okay and the instruction he gave me was
in
in i call you i'm looking at her i'm calling
your name in
is the first time you attend my sutra lecture
can i make use of you as a prop after 10 years
he's finally attended my sutra lecture the
first time
is that right you never attended my lecture
before i didn't count not until today
exactly i think he spoke english he spoke
in english
okay yeah why
it's more direct
i think that's all i could think of because
i think in english
i don't think in vietnamese i think in english
unless i talk to the vietnamese and then i
think in vietnamese but typically when i talk
to normal people non-vietnamese i think in
english but when i talk to the old monk then
i switch to vietnamese in my thoughts just
like you that's just like the boy what happened
to him now
okay so the point here is that if master XuanHua
can talk to me in english to make sure i understood
because that's my pattern unless you're vietnamese
i only think in english so in order to teach
me he used english to make sure i got the
message immediately no interpretation no translation
yes green is it really he spoke english or
yes it's just your mind translated i heard
his voice that anger i am traumatized for
the rest of my life
and as i just think about revisit that moment
i'm still shaking right now it's how scary
he's violent that's when i first learned about
violence it's okay to be violent towards your
disciples
okay yes so so the point here is that uh here's
what happens
your thought has no language
thoughts have no language for example when
i taught that boy yesterday the troublemaker
about shame on you
okay when he was about to cry you remember
you know he fell on his butt his right butt
and he got up and he was going like this and
he's bound to to cry and i laugh and
say so i said shame on you you know and he
immediately got the message okay that right
there when i taught him right there talking
about shame okay it's not in english at all
it's not in chinese at all he does not understand
chinese i only taught him about this conscious
thought called shame
he got it right away he stood up and he didn't
he didn't cry he stopped his he's about to
cry so i immediately tested him and said you
should be ashamed instead of crying so immediately
yeah i'm not going to cry he ran over there
and he hit himself
so the communications had no language he got
it so yesterday i was playing with him i taught
him five different emotions and he got them
all so the thought in communication has no
language but you add another layer on top
of yourself because you need to talk to your
thinking mind so that's why you translated
internally your wiring it translated from
that thought language which is pure thoughts
into english uh chinese excuse me
taiwanese or chinese chinese mandarin okay
whereas that one there is english
okay so that's why that's how they could communicate
it turns out by the way for important lessons
important teachings you cannot afford to be
be be distracted by languages so i'm sure
that bodhidharma and venerable bodhidharma
he when he wanted to teach ShenGuang he could
talk to him directly through his mind and
ShenGuang could understand okay and the this
is the storytelling where master XuanHua would
explain it to us in chinese and we translate
it into english so it's for our understanding
but for them it's direct very direct mind
to mind if you will okay just like you um
venerable Bodhidharma send him a thought okay
ex talked him in in thoughts and ShenGuang
would translate that thought into chinese
if you will that's what happened
does it help okay just remember no more questions
today
but he's uh the old monk is correct okay he's
right but he does you understand that's the
exactly the first layer is thought thought
has no language thought is just taught when
you you do mind you're able to read mind like
venerable bodhidharma okay you can read people's
mind that has no language okay he can read
your mind her mind your mind is in chinese
her mind's vietnamese and his mind and god
knows what language we don't know okay so
it doesn't matter at all so the first layer
is thought thought is just thought and then
next layer is language
all right that's how it works next
so this gradual teaching that bodhidharma
did for ShenGuang span nine years it's very
important okay do not expect immediate results
like we in our era are accustomed to instant
gratification it takes time okay it takes
time to prepare it takes time to
let the wine mature properly you cannot rush
it even soy sauce needs to mature naturally
is that clear or fish sauce for that matter
go ahead wei mountain
master when the that baby yesterday you play
that he fall down did you read his mind [Laughter]
yes
now you mentioned it now you brought it up
oh what a stupid question of course i did
i mean
occasionally because yesterday i i finally
found my soul mate a mischievous mind that
boy was causing trouble all afternoon for
four hours while you were here the small gathering
is still like five six of us get gathered
together and talking and telling your stories
and so forth the mind the boy was you know
creating mischief after mischief and so forth
oh this boy sounds like my kind of soul mate
so i intrigued me i said so i was starting
to say i was i started paying attention what
he was going through his mind how does he
create mischiefs so i was more intrigued by
that okay so so i i so i was able to connect
with him at that mischievous level that's
it and you call it thought reading mind reading
so be it guilty
okay so anyway so bodhidharma uh so the real
question is now how does he transmit the teaching
mind to mind teaching this is very very precise
language how is he gonna teach something he
does not understand the language or speak
the language okay you wouldn't i would not
dare use the chinese to teach you mind to
mind for example never because my chinese
is horrible okay so but bodhidharma decided
to transmit the sudden teaching the chan dharma
door here okay translation for you chan dharma
door here is sudden teaching because he taught
the chan dharma door for nine years already
the gradual dharma door okay venerable ShenGuang
saw how bodhidharma was teaching him not by
language not by thoughts but by what
by what
yes chinese person tests tests no tests that's
too chinese anyone else
yes from the philippines
you you want to make it sound so like we are
so international
yes by his behavior no wrong philippines doesn't
have it yellow yes emituofo by uh he sat for
nine years as well
anyone else old monk i'm sure the old monk
wants to say something
[Laughter] don't even translate green by uh
let him suffer
pretty good not quite but yeah it's pretty
good it's pretty good it's pretty good excellent
and you are devious i would be careful you
know if i were your husband
anyone else
by
doing
so for example this is just my imagination
okay please take a grain of salt there's no
proof don't ask me
how do you know i was talking a korean person
you know two nights ago and she says why are
you so sure
you don't ask someone that you know are you
sure you how can you be so sure i mean it's
not not proper anyway
what bodhidharma did for ShenGuang is that
if you can imagine ShenGuang is his hot stuff
he's revered by lay people he's he's uh he's
well respected impressed by the heavenly beings
okay he's a hot shot okay but ShenGuang is
not used to kneeling behind someone like that
so initially i assure you ShenGuang had thoughts
of quitting he said this is nonsense okay
it's going nowhere what am i doing let's go
back and face death it's less embarrassing
than this how can i explain to my supporters
i knew behind this dark skinned monk bushy
beard who ignores me completely
okay and when these thoughts of quitting arose
in in in in ShenGuang's mind bodhidharma would
do something
and the thought would die
okay so ShenGuang actually received help from
bodhidharma invisibly otherwise there's no
way ShenGuang could have lasted nine years
so what Bodhidharma did for ShenGuang is that
he invisibly helped ShenGuang not quit otherwise
you have quit nine years ago a long long time
ago does it make sense to you no ordinary
person unless they be they are sage would
do this silly thing for nine years that's
impossible that's totally nonsense unless
he was helped is that clear okay so don't
be so full yourself your progress actually
is your practice has a lot of help from a
lot of good guys we're on the good side of
the fence of the railroad tracks okay when
you do this good thing here you receive so
much help trust me so ShenGuang got help from
bodhidharma because budidharma would make
sure that he was not he would not quit okay
and then for example in the summertime it's
very very hot okay and and ShenGuang was perspiring
for example and he said i can't take this
much i'm going to pass out this heat and all
sun this is a light breeze
so the dharma protectors would blow air cool
air not hot air
seriously when you are hot someone does this
for you it's it changes it gives you the kind
of relief that's so much appreciated so ShenGuang
had a lot of help a lot of support because
not only bodhidharma was helping him the dharma
protectors around venerable Bodhidharma will
also assisting him you know in so many invisible
ways we on the good side guys if you think
that the demons are causing a lot of problems
out there i assure you the good guys are also
helping us as well okay that's what happened
that's the only way that this could have transpired
in my opinion
lesson
don't be so full of yourself we're receiving
a lot of help a lot more help than we are
aware of
all right say anyway
okay yeah why do we go into uh
大慧宗杲
大慧宗杲 whatever okay uh so anyway the
main thing here i don't know why we're going
to do this this uh this uh that way here okay
but my interesting the interesting point here
is that venerable Bodhidharma transmitted
the sudden teaching to okay and that is the
seal behind the transmission from generation
generation somehow they have to transmit the
sudden teaching to next generation because
that is the essence of chan that is essence
of mahayana i'm sorry korean sunims chan is
not it's not seon is not is not uh Huatou
okay seon is the sudden teaching
that's how you can tell whether you have real
chan or not for example in japan they don't
have sudden teaching at all there's no mention
of it yeah from the documents i read in english
no mention of sudden teaching it's all about
you know hinayana aspects of child of meditation
all right
uh anyway i don't know why we had 43 here
at the [unintellible] here uh real chan on
the uh so so so after venerable bodhidharma
taught ShenGuang okay that special sudden
teaching right there ShenGuang immediately
became enlightened that's how you transmit
the sudden teaching
then bodhidharma recognized ShenGuang yeah
was was uh was uh was right there at the threshold
okay and then uh ShenGuang who then later
became HuiKe said uh uh now that the arm hurts
yeah and he says uh my my i am troubled by
my the pain my arm okay please help me uh
calm my mind down and bodhidharma says bring
me your mind i will calm it down for you and
HuiKe says i can't find my mind how can i
bring it to you okay i said then i pacified
your mind and at that point HuiKe uh huike
then [Music] cross the threshold and went
into the world the realm of enlightenment
time is up oh my god time is up so sorry korea
okay so we end here today thank you all for
coming and i'm sorry i i exceeded a time limit
next time we continue 45 okay thank you
you