Um.
Boy: "Excuse me, Sir.
It's not recording."
Master Yong Hua: "It will be."
Boy: "Is it gonna record?"
Master Yong Hua: "Yes." Boy: "[?unintelligble?] record it."
Master Yong Hua: "It's going to be recorded." Boy: "How?"
Master Yong Hua: "Machine over there." Boy: [?Unintelligble?]
Master Yong Hua: "Yeah, right there. yeah."
Boy: "I don't see it."
Master Yong Hua: "Yeah, right there, behind, behind those
gentlemen."
Boy: "Oh?
Wow."
We
respectfully request
the Sangha of great virtues,
For the sake of this Assembly
and all living beings,
Please turn the Wonderful Dharma Wheel
to teach and guide us,
How to end birth and death,
leave suffering and attain bliss
and quickly realized Non-birth.
Gong qing Da De Seng ting
Wei ci Fa Hui ji yi qie zhong sheng
Qing zhuan miao Fa Lun Jiao dao wo men
Ru he liao sheng tuo si, Li ku de le
Su zhang Wu Sheng.
Homage to the Blessed, Noble and
perfectly Enlightened One.
Na Mo Sa Dan Tuo, Su Qie Duo Ye, E La He Di, San Miao San Pu Tuo Xie. [Vietnamese]
The unsurpassed, profound, subtle and
wonderful Dharma,
In a hundred thousand million aeons is
difficult to encounter,
Now that I'm able to see and hear, I will
receive and maintain it. I vow to fathom
the Thus Come On'es true and actual
principles.
Wu shang shen wei miao fa
Bai qian wan jie nan zao yu. Wo jin jian wen de shou chi
Yuan jie Ru Lai zhen shi yi.All Buddhas and Bodhisattvas, Venerable Hui Neng, Venerable Xuan Hua,
Venerable left-home people, and all good-knowing advisors, Emituofo. [Chinese] [Vietnamese] Hello everyone. Today is the 23rd of October,
2021. Uh.
We are gathered here to start discussing the
Sixth Patriarch Sutra, uh,
one of the, uh, uh,
most important, uh,
document, of
Buddhist scripture on
the Sudden Teaching.
Okay? Which is a distinctive
characteristics of the Chan school of
Mahayana. Uh.
Alright. So the full name is "The Six
Patriarch's Dharma Jewel
Platform Sutra," okay? Uh.
And on slide, let's see-
We are redoing this because we did this
like four years ago, four plus years ago,
and when we first started for uh, for uh,
over four years ago,
my intention was to honor my
late Chinese teacher, Master Xuan Hua, and
so, uh
who was hiding under his shadow, and
trying to explain, simply try to
elaborate what he meant. Was my intention.
And now the conditions have changed, a
little bit.
So now, we try to
explain the Sutra from the
American Mahayana perspective, instead of
Chinese Mahayana perspectives. So,  uh,
that's why we, we, we are, uh, we, I, we
feel that it's
worthwhile to do it again and explain it
in a way for, uh,
people in the 21st century, especially
Western-educated people. I'm not Chinese,
but,
but, um, but, um
I try. I'm sort of a hybrid person. I try
to
bridge the gap between the East,
Eastern culture and the Western culture.
And uh,
luckily for us, we have a lot of very
competent, uh,
Chinese-speaking, uh, uh,
people as well, so, and Taiwanese as well. Uh.
No
disrespect intended to the Taiwanese
people. Uh. [laughs] Ah, ah.
So,
so,
it is a collaborative effort. I hope
you all pitch in, and we, we will-
each other-
we learn from each other, and make
this a richer and more rewarding
experience. In particular, this is a very
auspicious because,
uh, we also have, hm,
the Korean audience as well. Ah, Korean is a
culture, a Buddhist culture, that
emphasizes Chan meditation, in
particular the Hua Tou. They put a lot of
emphasis on that. Uh.
And uh-
and so, this is a in a small way, a
little bit of contribution to their Chan
culture, and they call it Seon, Seon culture as
well. Okay. So, welcome all of you, thank
you very much, okay.
God, when you get on your knees like that I go "Urgh!" [laughs]
Is it me? [laughs]
Thank you.
Alright. Like so-
uh- six- uh- that's uh- Let's jump right into it. Uh.
The Sixth Patriarch is the sixth patriarch
from a Chinese lineage. Uh.
The first patriarch was Indian. That's
Venerable Great Master Mahakashyapa. Uh.
So he's he first patriarch of the
orthodox line,
lineage of, uh,
of Orthodox Buddhism. So,
the very important thing here we need to
take away from this is that, this is uh,
where, if you want to learn Buddhism,
if you want to learn Mahayana, this is
where
you should go and look for
good teachers, these patriarchs.
Alright? So, it started in India and
then
eventually it was transferred from India
to China and,
and to-
via Venerable
Great Master Bodhidharma, the 28th
Patriarch.
Okay?
Is there a question from JMMT or is it just my
imagination? Because the sign keeps on
flashing that, you know.
Or is it just uh, Malcolm who cannot
decide uh,
between Seoul and, and, and, and uh
JMT? Huh?
Anyway, is it you Malcolm?
Yeah! I recognize his flaming hair.Yeah
Yeah now, today- yesterday is that, uh, it's
in Seoul and today he's in- at uh, Jewel
Mountain Temple.
Yeah, hello!
Yeah.
The world traveler.
[laughs] Uh.
Alright, so, the Venerable Great Master
Bodhidharma brought the Mahayana,
transferred Mahayana from India to China,
because,
that's at the time, that's where the
next
competent
students would be found.
This is a problem with the patriarch, they
need to go
where
the students are, so that they can teach
them and train them, okay? So
at that time, uh, uh,
Venerable Bodhidharma had to go to India- uh-
from India to China. He abandoned India,
his Indian disciples,
went cold turkey to China on his own, by
himself. No entourage, okay? Uh.
And he went there, and, and, and to transfer
the Indian Mahayana knowledge
to
the Chinese uh. The First Patriarch. So
he became the first Chinese Patriarch.
So he's like holding two hats: Indian
Patriarch, 28th Patriarch from India, and
first Chinese Patriarch. Alright?
So...
And he transferred it to
the, uh, uh, the
second
Chinese Patriarch by the name of Hui Ke.
Okay? So
what did he transfer? Uh.
They didn't quite say it. But what he
transferred
is,
had to be
the Sudden Teaching.
Mahayana is about the Sudden Teaching.
If you don't have the Sudden Teaching,
you cannot teach Mahayana.
If you don't understand the Sudden
Teaching, you cannot, uh,
really, uh,
train the next generation at all.
And that's a constraint, and that's why, uh,
when we got to the Sixth Patriarch,
the Sixth Chinese Patriarch,
Venerable, Venerable Hui Neng, okay?
He was there around the 8th century AD.
Alright?
So now on slide number four. Uh,
in contrast,
if you look at the Hinayana hierarchy of
Buddhism, uh,
then you have to, you want to learn
Hinayana, then
I
have tremendous respect for the Thai
people, the Thai
Buddhist system. Hmm, ah,
why is that? Because
they have a long history
of training people. Uh,
I
met, uh,
some of the recent, uh,
the recent head monks,
Thai monks and uh,
they are very good. They are, they are
really, uh, pretty good levels of Arhats.
Fourth-stage Arhats. And therefore, that
system consistently passed on that
knowledge to the next generation. This is
key to Buddhism.
Buddhism is about once you have the
knowledge, once you have the wisdom, it is,
behooves upon you to pass it on to the next
generation. You cannot
let it discontinue at all.
So that knowledge
about the Sudden Teaching
in Mahayana must be passed on to next
generation, okay? And uh,
similarly, uh,
in Hinayana, they have a way of training
people so that uh,
they have uh,
tremendous success. They produce a lot of
Fourth-stage Ahats and probably Pretyekabuddhas
as well, even though, I haven't
met any yet, okay.
So that's the distinctive characteristics
over there. And, um,
and uh,
uh,
so they have a lot of, uh, Thai, uh,
jargon here. They're, they're big shots.
And uh, just between us, uh, don't say this
don't quote me, okay? Among them
are Bodhisattvas. Shhhhh...
they're gonna be offended. [laughs]
I saw some of them are Bodhisattvas.
Okay? You know why it's important?
Because the Bodhisattvas
help defend them against the demonic
perversion
in the system.
Because they spot those things and say,
"No, no, no, no, cut this off." This is why you
call the doctor and cut off the limb.
"This is a bad limb, cut it off, cut it off!"
Okay?
Otherwise,
the system will be, uh, uh, uh,
what's the word, huh, Master Xian Jie?
Tainted? What else?
Master Xian Jie: "Um, I'm not sure what we're looking for
right now, sorry."
Master Yonghua: [sigh] Okay, I'll, you know...
What is the more polite term for
polluted?
Deeriorated, is too uh, too scholarly.
Master Xian Jie: "Is it like corrupted?"
Master Yonghua: Corrupted! Thank you.
It's very serious.
If you let corruption
sneak in,
that's the beginning of the end.
Just like uh,
speaking of uh, governments and policy,
and so forth, you know, we go to another
country, and try to change government and
change uh, the political system, and all. And, and
you don't guard against corruption in
government, that's it. It will never work.
Never ever. Never happened, never worked in
Vietnam, for example,
okay? Never workd in any country as a
matter of fact. If you have corruption in
the system, the system will fall. So what
happened, never mind about politics and
you know,
so what happened is that,
in the Thai system, they have
Bodhisattvas
disguising themselves as Arhats, and
they are not in power. They only serve in
advisory roles and,
and, and that's why the system is so
healthy, so strong, because of that reason.
They have protection. Because if you them
leave alone, it alone to the Arhats, the
Arhats can still be fooled.
Okay? So, so, that's why, that's why in
terms of Hinayana, I highly recommend you if
want to uh,
learn the Maha-, uh, Hinayana thing,
go to Thailand. I highly recommend it,
okay?
And they have a council and I know, briefly
about it, I met the Tha- head
guy from the Thai council, and I said,
yeah, he's, he's a fourth-stage Arhat for sure.
And, and, uh,
he has spiritual penetrations as
well, and so forth, okay? So these peopleaare
for real folks.
They're worth, they're worthy of
our offerings, okay? I would not hesitate
to make offerings though. Okay?
Uh, uh,
And uh, Supreme Patriarch,
is uh,
this uh, Great Rattanakosin, okay,
uh,
since
2017, and so forth. Look how young he is,
yeah, young looking he is. Hm?
Okay?
And,
uh, alright, so,
so that's the Buddhism right there. If
you want, you are a believer in Hinayana,
okay, and you say Mahayana is
not for me, go to Thailand. I don't care
whoever you are, okay.
It's a, it's a great place to learn.
Yes Sir, yellow.
Speaker Yellow: "Be the more proper adjective,
corrupt?" Master Yonghua: Yeah, corrupt.
Yeah thank you. Thank you very much.
Alright. Uh,
I stand uh,
corrected. I should be more corrupt, okay?
Corrupted is, uh,
is uh,
not quite correct.
Okay? Uh.
Alright.
So, uh,
so going back to our small world of
Mahayana. Because
in the West right now, Master Xuan Hua
transmitted his knowledge
of the
Sudden Teaching
to
this country, already.
Okay? Meaning that,
the fact
from a profess- from a professional
perspective,
the people here are better recipients of
that teaching, then
the people back in his country.
It's a fact, okay.
No disrespect intended for the Taiwanese
either.
Alright? So,
so he had to go to this country, to the
U.S. to transfer the Sudden Teaching Dharma
Door.
Okay so, as Americans here, American has
no color, skin color by the way. As you
can look around you,
there's only,
hardly any white-colour skins here at
all.
You see? And that's the nature of American
Buddhism. American Buddhism, people think
American is like, you know, it
must be Caucasian. No! American is a mixed,
you know,
thing and, and, and, and uh, that's what
makes America
superior, in my s-, in my, my, my, in my mind, is
that the ability to absorb and embrace
everything. That is the spirit of Mahayana
right there.
Okay, so he had to go to this country,
Master Xuan Hua, okay? Uh,
brought this Chinese
Mahayana to the U.S., in particular he
brought the Dharma door of the Sudden
Teaching,
okay. Sudden teaching meaning that
those of you who are not familiar with
this, uh,
Sudden Teaching meaning that with this
teaching, teaching, meaning,
you have to hear it, you have to, uh, you have
to, uh, someone has to speak it, okay?
Okay? And when you hear this,
when you read this,
you can attain
Enlightenment.
Suddenly.
Okay?
Only in Mahayana can you have that.
Okay? And so this uh, the Sixth Patriarch
taught
this method of Sudden Enlightenment,
if you will,
okay?
And uh, and
so, uh, this Dharma door here
actually has many access,
access routes.
It leads to that door called Sudden
Enlightenment, but to get there it has many
pathways, if you will.
Alright?
Questions? This is very important. This is
a momentous moment
in China
when uh, um, Great Master Bodhidharma
went to China and decided, "Ah,
I'm gonna teach Hui Ke, Great Master Hui Ke,
this Sudden Teaching thing," and then
Master Hui Ke then transferred it to the
Third Patriarch, who transferred it to the Fourth
Paatriarch, who transferred it to the Fifth
Pariarch,
Master Hong Ren, who then transferred it,
that Sudden teaching to Master Huineng.
And we'll find out a little bit later.
Alright?
So this is very, very important. And
by the way, okay, as Americans, okay, uh, uh,
the mindset should be that we should be
grateful to the Chinese for this gift.
Because you know, it's a gift
that will have tremendous consequences
for us,
our generation, as well our children's
generation, and further, further down the
road as well,
okay? This is very, very critical, uh,
heritage, that we,
we are, we are leaving behind, okay? So
that's why we,
uh since, uh,
since Master Xuan Hua didn't really
elaborate that much about the Sudden
Teaching when he taught this, in
how long ago? I don't remember.
It, the...
Anyone knows? He taught this, he
explains the Sutra, he explained the Sixth Patriarch
Sutra, as one of the popular
explanations out there, for,
in Mahayana.
A lot of people, Buddhists and
non-Buddhists like
would read up on his books. They find it
very, very, uh,
interesting, very insightful. Hm. And.
But
he never really
elaborated that much on the Sudden
Teaching, which is
what uh,Venerable Hui Neng specialized in doing.
Okay. So we'll dwelve on that side.
Number eight. Uh.
And at the time,
at the time, Buddhism uh,
was
there in China already, okay? But
just like nowadays, just like typically
what happens, uh,
that,
people studied books, studied scriptures
and did ceremonies, and so what it's
called very superficial cultivation. Okay?
Substance is what Mahayana is about, okay?
It's, it's, it's a, it's, uh, it's about, uh, uh,
the core, your core,
your heart. It's not, it's not about
appearances, not about temples, it's not
about fame, reputation.
Alright? Go ahead
Korea.
JMT.
Speaker from JMT: "Good morning from Korea." Master Yonghua: Good morning.
Good afternoon to you too.
Good morning there and good afternoon
here.
[Laughs]
Speaker from JMT: "Ma- Master, did Bodhidharma walk from-
walk all the way on foot, from India to
China?"
Master Yong Hua: Not true.
It's uh, it's a myth,
What actually happened, it sounded good,
but what did happen is that- the Chinese
would like you to believe that he walked.
But it's not true.
Actually what happened, he boarded
a boat.
He didn't swim either.
And then he walked to Vietnam, that's
true. [laughs]
Yeah.
Monks couldn't, couldn't, couldn't uh, couldn't ride
horses,
they can't, they can't ride horses.
Only for pets, but not for riding uh
that's how they keep horses. Speaker: "I have one more question."
Yes go ahead, uh, uh,
flaming
hair.
Speaker "flaming hair": "Uh, Master this is more of
a comment.
There's a,
there's a rapper I listened to and he, he
wrote a book and Bodhidharma was
mentioned,
and he's- he was- that's where I got that
from. He walked from India to China
and um
he actually mentioned Chan in the book
and that Zen came from Chan,
like the Japanese Zen. So I thought that
was pretty cool. That he um-"
Master Yonghua:  This is where?
A rap song?  Speaker "flaiming hair": " It kinda- Sorry, it's a, it's a rapper that got me
into um, the Asian culture, a long
time ago." Master Yonghua: Did I hear right? You, you
listen to rap?
Speaker "flaming hair": "Not as much anymore."
Master Yonghua: Good for you.
[Laughs]
I'm open-minded but there're certain
things I just can't stand. [Audience laughs]
Just kidding, just kidding. [Master Yong Hua laughs]
Alright very good. Yes Wei Mountain. Oh
god.
I always get in trouble when I joke too
much.
Speaker from Wei Mountain Temple: "Master when did Bodhidharma went to
Vietnam?"
Master Yonghua: In Vietnam?
Oh my, my, my province. Huế [?Vietnamese spelling?]
Definitely. [laughs]
Central Vietnam.
No hesitation, no doubt.
Yes, uh, over here black.
Speaker Black: "So it is the
tradition
story that Bodhidharma came to China, um,
well actually, while he was travelling to
China he traveled-
wait no sorry- I think when he came to
China he um, came by a piece of leaf and
then" Master Yong Hua: No. Speaker Black: "-went across the water, right?" Master Yonghua: No.
No, no, no, no, no, no. You Chinese, nice try.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You're distorting the fact, you're
China's, China person.
No no. You can't, you you, can't sneak that
in. No, no, no, no, no. Speaker Black: "I think uh uh-" Master Yong Hua: He
boarded a boat. Speaker Black: "I think-" Master Yonghua: A Viking boat. [laughs]
Speaker Black: "Yeah um it was it was quoted as an
example of um,
you actually can show um, spiritual power
as a Chan Master, uh,
to teach people."
Master Yonghua: When he was in China, he did cross a
river on a leaf, that's true.
See, your Chinese history is so mixed. Speaker Black: "I thought I
thought it was Indian ocean, I guess I got it wrong, Master."
Master Yonghua: Indian ocean is an ocean, it's not a
river, my dear, okay? Speaker Black: "Yeah yeah okay." Master Yonghua: Get your Chinese
facts straight please.
Alright yeah, he did cross, actually, it,
that's very famous, he, he, had a, there's
plenty of drawings of him
on a leaf when he walked across the water. Speaker Black: "Yeah. Oh I think uh that's when
Master Yonghua: That's when, how he showed off. Like, you know,
Chinese. They show off.
Speaker Black: "He uh, he came from the north when after
he talked with Lian Wu Di
and then he pissed off Lian Wu Di and
then he left, um,
the Northern China to go to Southern
China. I think that's where the the story
of the one leaf crossed the river." Master Yonghua: Yeah
he crossed a river and on, on a leaf,
that's true, okay. Yeah and, and uh,
not clear on how what propelled him, okay? [laughs]
Alright? But it's true that he did
cross, uh, uh, uh,
water on a leaf. That's pretty impressive,
okay?
And, uh.
And so,
so, he was actually pretty desperate
looking for someone, so
"Anyone please, who wants to learn
Mahayana from me, take it off my
hands." Okay? And the Chinese was like "No, no, you're too
black. I mean
your skin too dark.
We don't trust you." Uh.
So you know,
so he really struggled, uh,
and finally he found a yellow soul, I
mean a Chinese soul, [audience laughter]
who took it from him,
okay? And we're grateful for that.
My point here is that with all due respect
okay, I personally, I'm grateful to
Chinese culture. I feel it's because uh,
because the
when,
when Great Master Bodhidharma
transferred the Mahayana to China,
he, he really, uh, uh,
the Chinese Buddhism that I learned,
the Mahayana Buddhism I learned is
tremendous, it;s so profound. It's so
beautiful, so wonderful. And it's a gift
to the world, really.
You should
transcend the national barriers and, and,
races and genders and so forth, because
this Buddhism here is, to me, it's beauty.
It's just like you look at a piece of
art.
To me, it's like that you look at a
statue [unintellgible?]
or, or, uh,
what's the guy who lost his ear, cut his
ear, to give to a prostitute girlfriend?
Van Gogh! Okay? Those things are just
beautiful. I mean look at that, like wow,
yeah.
You know, it, it, it, it
it makes
you feel good in your heart,
you know?
It's not the visual thing, it's just, you look at
that [and you go] "Yeah!" I mean it connects from that
painting to your heart directly,
okay?
Through the stomach.
But, mm, uh, so, so, I'm grateful. I don't know
about you, I'm so grateful that the
Chinese, uh,
Buddhism, because of what we got from them.
What I got from Master Xuan Hua,
is, is, it's so beautiful.
The first time in my life, after I learned
Mahayana, I said, "Wow.
This is
wonderfully
beautiful."
Okay?
Mahayana is,
helps you appreciate beauty,
okay?
Yes, was there a question somewhere? Oh, oh! Wei Mountain!
Speaker from Wei Mountain Temple: "Master what is the meaning behind
Venerable Bodhidharma
leaving on the leaf, because this has been
thousands of years, and there's a lot of
painting about it."
Master Yonghua: Meeting him, what?
Speaker from Wei Mountain Temple: "Leaving, uh,
across, across the river by one piece
of- one leaf."
Master Yonghua: I have no idea,
okay?
When I'm able to do that, I will explain
it to you.
And don't hold your breath. [laughs]
Okay? Uh.
You, you Vietnamese people are weird, you know.
I'm just talking about the depth and the
beauty of Mahayana and he says, "Let's go back
to floating on a leaf across the river."
What's beautiful about that? To me, it's, it's,
it's Indian show-off,
okay?
We're talking about beautiful
Chinese people,
Chinese things. Okay?
And Taiwanese too. Yeah.
It's so
difficult nowadays, you know, to
not offend one
and, and,
and please the other. Anyway!
So, anyway, so this Sutra here, it's
about, it's about, uh the emphasis of this
Sutra here, uh, uh, is actually
about cultivation.
In order to learn about the Sudden
teaching here,
you need to grind it out first, you need
to bear the discomfort, and
and keep grinding and grinding, and when
you ready, that's when the Sudden
Teaching is bestowed upon you, and boom!
You leap.
Okay? Uh,
any questions?
Okay, and, and, and uh,
this is the function, the Sudden
Teaching is the function of, uh,
the responsibility of the great teachers,
and um, and um,
in a way to be fair, Master Xuan Hua did
transmit the Sudden Teaching to his
disciples. But low-level
Sudden Teaching.
Alright. And, and
you pay attention to how he explained
the Six Patriarch Sutra, you find that
yes, there's some,
some allusions to uh, the Sudden Teaching
when Master Xuan Hua explained it, but
he didn't really
go into greater depths. So hopefully, we
add more to it. This is important, because
remember, okay?
what I, we, I call American Mahayana is
hardly
by the skin color.
Okay? Look at us.
The Asians are taking over Silicon
Valley, let's face it.
[laughs]
Alright? Okay.
Oh the Koreans, they have no sense of
humor. They're, they're... [Sighs]
Ah those poor Koreans. A long way to go. Uh, um.
Alright.
So jewel,
jewel is his Dharma that is precious.
Jewel is, uh, is, uh, when you hear jewel or
gem, uh,
that's of great value, it's highly
desirable, uh,
and it's so Chinese to me.
To me,
I would prefer for us Americans,
to look at the
beauty of
the Dharma. The Dharma is beautiful. The
Dharma, I assure you, if you
understand the Dharma,
you see the beauty.
What kind of beauty?
Uh...
Estée Lauder?
Lancôme?
No!
Beauty of
people's heart.
The heart, if you cut it up,
can be very beautiful,
when you look at it.
Not with the knife.
Okay? People's heart, when you get to
recognize, you get to see them,
people's heart is so beautiful. And I,
yesterday I was playing with a kid, a kid,
a naughty, naughty kid,
okay? And I,
it's amazing, I tell you this, you
know, I was playing the kid and I was
teaching at the same time, I was teaching
the kid about emotions.
And yesterday,
he was playing and he tripped and he fell on
his butt,
the right butt,
so he was,
he was gathering himself up and touching
his butt and was deciding, "Should I
cry now, or
or what? [laughs] I'm entitled cry am I not?" And
he was thinking I laughed at him,
I made fun of him, uh,
and he immediately got the message and
said, "I'm so this is so embarrassing, how
could I fall like this?" So he hid behind the, the,
he ran away and hid immediately.
Okay?
So, hm, so,
kids' heart can be so beautiful too, you
know.
Anyway, ah,
so, ah,
the jewel here, uh,
to me, it's not, it's not the gem like a
Chinese people would like, the Asians
like to think, you know, the Indians are
into gold. Chinese are into jade, okay?
Ugh, girls are
into diamonds,
I heard.
And I'm into Vajra,
okay? Vajra is beautiful, okay? And uh, and and uh,
but primarily, you know, it's
the heart that interests me about this
Mahayana here. And
the heart here is uh, uh,
the heart
of Mahayana, the heart of Master Huineng, in
particular, is precious, it's rare
and to me, it's
sublime.
Alright? Uh.
Platform, uh,
apparently on slide number 10, platform is
where the place, where the sutra is
spoken is Nan Hua, okay? In that famous
temple there,
and they build a platform like here, uh,
about 10 feet. Uh,
Wontec Sunim, how tall was this when you built
this?
You remember how tall is this?
Not even 31 inches. Hm.
Okay?
And the platform is a, is, is a place,
a revered place, a pure place where they did
important things in Buddhism. They
transmit the precept substance
from the heart, of Master to your heart.
That's where that happens, and then they
speak the Dharma to
shape the heart, okay? And that's called
Buddhist plastic surgery.
Alright? Uh,
seriously, they, they knew about plastic
surgery back then already. Ah, ah.
Alright 11. Mmm,
sutra is anything that's spoken by the
Buddha, uh, to teach us about cultivation
and um, and, uh, uh, and, and uh,
Sutra here has uh, a
meaning, like to attract.
So it's a, it's a
it's the
logic,
the, uh,
beauty of the teaching, you know, the, the uh,
superior intellect, the superior wisdom
is very attractive to most of us.
And it's, and, and it's
designed to give us
directions on how
to
work. The Chinese like to say to
cultivate, I don't think of cultivation.
I'm thinking the Sutra is teaching us how to
live
our lives to the fullest.
Whether you're a left-home person or a
lay perso, okay, Sutras are supposed to
do that, supposed to teach us how to live,
okay? Um,
be happier with
our lives. Okay?
And when you're happy,
you share it with your family, you
share it with your students, you share
your co-workers.
Okay? Uh.
And, uh,
in particular, this weight of
practice here, uh,
is in accord, or consistent
with the intent of the Buddhas and the
wisdom of the Buddhas.
Alright? So this Sutra here, is very
special because, uh, because,
it is uh, um, it is the first time
in Chinese Buddhism, and I don't know if it
happened in Indian Buddhism or not, but
in Chinese Buddhism, it's the only
time that a Sutra
was, uh,
recorded, and the teaching was
recorded, and, and,
classified as a Sutra when it was spoken
by a
Chinese monk.
Not the Buddha. Okay?
So it's very, very special, it's
really a, a,
a, uh,
treasure to the Chinese,
okay? So, we should be grateful
here in our era,
us here in this country, that we're able
to
receive this as a gift
from the Chinese,
okay? Uh,
you need to give credit where it's due, so
we need to be grateful to the
Chinese, uh, uh,
kindness
and generosity
via Master Xuan Hua.
Okay? Uh.
Alright, at least I am grateful, I don't
know about you. Uh.
Okay, so when he
is explaining sutras, we go through the
Tian Tai school
for general analysis to give us an
overview what to expect from the Sutra,
so explain the names, uh
and uh, and uh,
according to that, you know,
the Tian Tai school, there's a the sutra, by the
title, it refers to a person, uh,
and the Dharma analogy and a place and so
forth. Uh blah blah blah. See, you know, you can,
you can look it up. I'm not
interested in these things, uh it's too
Tian Tai for me. And discriminating the
substance, uh, it's talked about real mark
as substance.
And the real mark here is a very
advanced concept for enlightened people,
and this is the
distinctive characteristics
for Chinese Buddhism. Okay? Real mark is, is,
by definition, real mark is no mark,
but uh,
nothing is without mark, okay? Shi xiang wu xiang. Wu wu xiang
is the Chinese thing that I memorized.
Couldn't understand it 25 years ago.
Okay?
That's all you have to do, memorize it. So no
mark, but nothing without mark that is
real mark.
Alright? Yes yellow.
Speaker "Yellow": "Master, just a quick question, um,
is it possible that the Sixth Patriarch
is a reincarnation of Shakyamuni Buddha?"
Master Yong Hua: No! He's Vietnamese! [Audience laughs]
I'm glad you asked. [laughs]
We hear this a lot, you know, my late
Vietnamese master said you know,
I have proof, I written a book on how the
Sixth Patriarch is Vietnamese.
I say, "Oh,
I know you want to leave me your temple,
so I'm not going to disagree with you."
[laughs]
Uh, so,
so is he a reincarnation of the Buddha?
In my, in my, humble opinion, I feel he's a
Buddha,
okay? Because his depth, because my teacher
is Chinese and his level is
very, very high, okay?
But,
when you look at his teachings, the way
he taught his disciples,
and see, and he taught me
three times directly, in-person and the
other time is like, I hear, you know, I go
crazy like flaming hair. [laughs]
Ah yeah, there we go again. [Audience laughter]
We wouldn't believe it yesterday I was
taught him about five, six
different emotions, he picked them just like
that. [Kid fussing around in bacground]
Oh no, now he has a companion.[Laughs]
Alright. Ah,
so, so, is he a Buddha? I feel that
he's a Buddha.
Because
the teaching is so profound, uh,
so,
so
beautiful, if you will. Hm.
Okay?
But I don't think he's Shakyayumi
Buddha at all. Okay?
Because that would be a bad
precedent.
The Buddha
came, he left and he came back again? Say
what?
He has nothing else to do?
I mean it's like,
if you leave, please go, don't, don't come
back. To me, it's, it's just like, doesn't make
sense.
There's no point being so sticky. The
Buddha come and go and, and, and,
let the next Buddha come.
Give them a chance, you know. Uh, so
you know, so you guys are too sticky. No, no I
hope it's not Shakyamuni Buddha, but
I don't know, because you asked me about
state of a Buddha. Wrong person to ask.
Okay? Uh.
Ask something I know, not something I
don't know. Uh.
Okay, what is the principle here?
M'kay?
To become a Buddha.
All of us can become a Buddha.
Okay?
Message:
don't
sell yourself short.
It [?] knows discrimination, okay? Uh.
So,, uh, uh, it's, it's a,
anyone can become a Buddha. That's why, uh,
that's why, uh,
that's why, now is our chance, okay, we
don't have to uh,
go to China anymore. Although,
you know,
you want to learn Tai Chi, I still feel
we need still need to go to China. Wu
Dang, okay. [?]
I will go to Wu Dang [?] for about a year or two,
I would love to go there and learn.
You know, I hear,
speaking of walking on leaves, I hear they
walk on walls.
I saw a demonstration. Shhh.
He actually walked on walls.
I was so impressed, I said, "Wow."
Anyway, uh,
so you can realize, realize
Buddhahood. You can. All of us can.
Okay?
No one is exempt. Even the lady back there
who's half-asleep,. She can too. The
Sudden Teaching is that, we can all
become a Buddha, just like that.
But she must have to cross her legs. [laughs]
Just kidding. [laughs]
There's a requirement, you think it's free?
No, we all have to work for it. And the
function is to understand the mind and
see your own nature. Here,
understanding the mind
is very interesting.
You get to see how mind works. Your mind.
How your mind works. And once you
understand how your mind works, you begin
to be able to see how
In's [?] mind
work.
You see? Uh.
Alright? Hm.
And the teaching mark is, uh, uh,
oh god, this is so scholarly.
Sutra is like sweet dew,
heavenly elixir of immortality.
Uh yeah, so Chinese, uh,
I don't like these concepts because it
makes you greedy.
You know, uh,
it like, makes you so special. "I'm
listening to Sixth Patriarch Sutra." Uh.
Hello Mama [laughs]
from China.
[Laughs] Uh,
I'm glad you made it! The last time I saw
you in Wei Mountain temple.
Oh, okay. Xie xie, bu ke qi. [laughs]
Ah.
So, ah, so, um, this um, this um,
not only is it beautiful,
but
it's very tasty.
You, you can taste, you know,
that has to be real. When you
listen to the Sutra,
and so every now and then you might get
to the state, where actually when you
swallow your saliva, it's kind of sweet.
That's a sweet dew right there.
It happens.
Alright? Hm.
And, and uh,
teaching period is, is uh, is uh, this uh,
happened during the Dharma uh, Flower
and Lotus-Nirvana period
and so forth,
okay?
Alright, any questions?
I'm not, as you have noticed by now, I'm
not interested in scholarly things. I'm
just like,
this raw
and uh, and uh, uh, uh,
limited person. I'm more interested in
something that, that's, uh,
beautiful,
tasty and that kind of thing, you will
have my interest. Uh.
But scholarly things, I leave it to the
PHD people.
Alright. Um.
Five Chinese Pariarchs. Okay? Now you should be, you
should know about, okay. Uh.
That's how uh, Chinese Buddhism, uh,
started to take root in China. This is
important because we need to know
for our generation, how are we going to
make these
American Mahayana take root.
Okay? We are, right now I'm in my second
generation, you're the third generation, so
therefore, it
helps to go back to how it happened in
China, okay?
Because we learned from the Chinese anyway. Okay, hm, hm.
And,
so it's uh, it's set from the uh, uh,
Song of Enlightenment, another famous Chinese uh
creation by the Seventh Patrairch. Uh, uh, that uh,
he recognized Bodhidharma who was the 28th
Patriarch, okay. In that
proper or orthodox line of Mahayana
Buddhism, okay?
And, uh, and, uh,
all the Indian
prior Patriarchs from 1 to 27, followed
Bodhidharma's, to,
he brought all that
Indian
heritage
from India to China.
And conferred upon the Chinese. So the
Chinese inherited all that Indian wisdom,
okay? And that's what is meant by
transmitting, uh,
the wisdom from India to China, okay? It
became Chinese.
The Chinese became the guardian
of the Indian wisdom.
And, and,
and later on after Sixth Pariarch, the Chinese
Buddhism later on, really really
prospered and blossomed. They produced, uh,
many great talents,
many great patriarchs, uh,
that I feel that for us, in our era, our
times, uh,
we should spend the time to learn
Chinese
and study
these great Chinese teachers.
Because the depth of Mahayana, I keep on
telling you this, is in the Chinese
language, not in English yet.
Okay? So if you want Mahayana wisdom, uh,
deeper wisdom, higher level wisdom, you have
to learn Chinese.
Okay?
Any questions about that? So you know
where to find, look for materials, and
where to look, where to look for in terms
of great teachers.
It's not,
you know, the, uh, Chinese
teachings, Patriarch teachings actually
much higher level than
here,
that's available in English.
That's a fact.
Okay? So for you, those of you out there
who feel that you understand Mahayana, I
strongly urge you to learn Chinese.
Because you should go back to the
Chinese teachers, okay? And
in the future, I hope you transfer,
translate that teaching from Chinese
into English.
Okay? In order to do that,
you have
to learn Chan.
Chan is a requirement.
Okay?
Without Chan, you cannot have the proper
translation, and you find in the Sutra,
that we use an old version of um,
my Master's disciples' translation, and it
has
quite a few things
that missed the mark completely.
Okay, uh,
and so there are some
significant Patriarchs,
Mahakashyapa, uh,
don't have much teaching of him, Ananda
and then the Second Patriarch, the Fourteenth
Patriarch, very famous. They were Nagarjuna.
Nagarjuna?
How do you say it, huh, flaming hair?
How?
Speaker Flaming hair: "Master I don't know, but
um, Na-, Naga-,
Nagarjuna?"
Master Yonghua: Oh no. Speaker Flaiming Hair: "I don't know." Master Yong Hua: Nevermind. Stay there. Don't uh-
Okay, and
then, Naga-, Nagar-
Nagarjuna, and then Vasubandu is another famous, uh, uh,
famous Indian Patriarch.
Next, 15. Uh, uh,
Bodhidharma,
we're talking about Bodidharma, he is a
prince in of a kingdom in Southern India.
King was a very devout Buddhist. It shows
right there.
If
your
parents are Buddhists,
then you're bestowing
great blessings to your children,
because you give them exposure
to
the teaching of wisdom.
Okay?
Uh, so,
so the conventional wisdom is that, is that,
when you're born into a family as
Buddhist, uh,
you are
incredibly, uh,
blessed,
if you will.
Alright?
Uh, hm, of course they are always exceptions.
Uh, but not only was the king was a
Buddhist, he is a devout Buddhist,
and uh, and uh,
he made, uh,
offerings to
the Patriarch. So he have access to the
27th Patriarch, okay? And he
gave a priceless pearl to the Patriarch,
okay? Uh.
Lesson number two
You have
to make offerings
to the Patriarchs,
to the great teachers,
okay? So this king here, not only was he
devout, devoted to, uh,
Buddhism, meaning that he helped propagate
Buddhism, he also made
a lot of offerings, supported the
great teachers, the Patriarchs.
Okay?
And,
because of that
his children
have tremendous blessings,
okay? And so this is very special family.
So when he offered a priceless pearl to the
27th Indian Patriarch, he showed the pearl, the Patriarch showed the pearl
to the
three princes, sons of the King and asked
"Anything more valuable than this pearl, uh,
that I just received?"
And
the, the two older princes said
"Pearl is the most precious
in our kingdom, and there's nothing
better in the world." Very proud of it.
16.
The third prince,
the youngest one, was Bodhidharma, who
later became Bodhidharma said, "This
worldly pearl, uh, uh,
is not the most precious thing. Uh.
It is uh,
among all the, uh,
gems in the world, uh,
the truth
is the supreme jewel."
Okay? Uh.
So Indian.
Okay?
But, uh,
but back then as a young prince, he had,
he valued the truth already. Okay?
He felt the truth was a treasure,
that
uh, that
that you, that uh,
should be cherished,
not, not, uh,
not gems and jewels.
And the prince, uh, uh,
continues. He says,
"This worldly luster, uh,
cannot be
considered the finest. Okay?
The
light, the,
the brightness, the light, that's most
precious is uh, from the light of wisdom.
Hm.
And uh, the pearl, even though, uh, has
lucidity, uh, uh,
but the lucidity of the mind is uh,
is the most desirable." Okay?
So, uh, the young prince's, uh, uh
answer is really outstanding.
And so, so the,
it showed that this, this young man here
had potential to be taught, okay?
And that's what great teachers
recognize. They recognize people, they say,
"Who can be taught?
Who would be worthy of my efforts?"
Yes go ahead, yellow.
Speaker Yellow: "Ah, Master, regarding the pronunciation of
Nagarjuna, Anthony heard from a disciple, uh,
it's pronounced Nagarjuna." Master Yonghua: Nagarjuna?
Speaker Yellow: "Yes, yes, that's what I heard from one of your
disciples, I think." Master Yonghua: "Yeah yeah, I remember
vaguely, I just cannot remember which uh, which uh, uh, uh, which
syllable to put the inflection on.
So i thought it was from flaming hair,
but it's not, it's from someone else. Speaker: "Yeah.
I think it's from someone else." Master Yong Hua: Yeah,
someone else. It's clearly not flaming
hair, flaming hair is still
uh- Alright, um,
and uh, uh, and uh, and uh,
Bodhidharma said a lot of things,
that you know,
Indians. They're, they're  wordy, and
they, they talk too much. Uh, uh.
You know, from a Chan perspective,
if I were the 27th Patriarch, which I'm
not,
I'd say, "You talk too much boy."
Uh, uh,
So but anyway,
clearly, this young prince
here, has a special mind. He's, he's not
impressed by worldly things.
Okay?
And it comes with, it comes with
prior blessings. If you
will.
If your children have blessings, they'd be
drawn
to
things of wisdom,
okay?
Instead of, they will not be impressed by
the size of the temple. [Audience laughs]
If I could influence you a little bit, [laughs]
we're not like uh, the kings who has
palaces and three princes and so forth.
You know, and,
and so forth.
What we have is big hearts.
Okay. So, uh,
I'm not interested in what the young
Bodhidharma had to say to his teacher.
He's not enlightened back then, so it's a
lot of nonsense. Okay? But somehow the
Indians were impressed, the Chinese were
impressed, so they, they put this
down. Okay, to me it's too wordy. It's
too many words, okay? It's not Chan-like.
And later, he became better, okay?
Uh, so after the
King father's death, uh,
the young prince became disciple,
and, uh, and uh,
and became a monk, okay? So, you see, uh,
right there again, the behavior
this person
is similar to the Buddha's, Shak-
Gautama Buddha's, where he, uh,
was not
impressed by worldly things,
by luxury,
by
the, uh, the
worldly pleasures, okay? He,
he, uh, he uh, he
followed his teacher,
and
he served his teacher for 40 years until
he died.
Okay?
Another, another, another,
fact about Great Bodhidharma is that he
serves his teacher,
okay? Ah, and, and uh,
and that's one of the most beautiful
things you can do
to show
gratitude.
He showed- the reason, he's a prince
remember, he's used to being, uh,
treated like uh,
the, uh, the
potential future King, future Emperor,
therefore he's supposed to be uh,
idolized and so forth, but no. He revered
his teacher and became a monk to serve
him, um, uh, uh,
for 40 years. That's very, very impressive,
okay?
And to me, there is no, uh,
higher
way, better way to express gratitude by
taking care of your teacher, okay?
Of a, of a great teacher like him.
And, and uh,
and that's one thing there that you can
learn
to spot children or people, okay?
The common denominator of these great
people is that they know gratitude.
It comes from the heart. If your heart is
big, your heart is full of gratitude.
You don't always have to take,
okay?
You can give,
okay? You give back to the people
that
did you great favors. Hm?
Like your teacher, like your parents, like
your ancestors and so forth,
okay? Uh.
That's what's uh, what special
about the Asian culture,
okay? Uh.
You teach gratitude,
by being grateful, not, not by talking
about it,
okay? And so Bodhidharma served his
master for 40 years, that's very
impressive, okay? Until his master died
and, and
his master, uh,
asked him
to
go to China
uh,
bring Mahayana from India to China. So
basically, uh,
named him as the 28th Patriarch,
okay? Hm.
And when he came there, uh,
didn't speak
Chinese at all.
So
the Chinese
were very, uh,
discriminatory and look at him and say,
"Your skin is too black
and you're too- your beard, you have a huge
beard," and you know,
so they looked down upon this. They're scornful, uh,
towards Venerable Bodhidharma,
okay?
Uh.
Don't know why
the
Chinese would draw Bodhidharma bare-
chested, with a lot of hair.
Do Indians have a lot of hair or not?
Chest hair?
They do?
I
never know that.
Watch the movies?
[Laughter]
Not! We're not watching the same movies!
Is there a lot of dancing like [Master Yonghua mimics Bollywood music and dancing] [audience laughter]
I know- you, you, they're talking all of a
sudden, the man breaks out into dance and
sings? [Master Yonghua mimics Bollywood music and dance] [Audience laughs] [Master Yong Hua laughs]
Anyway, hairy chest. Uh.
Why?
Why you would draw
him like that?
Anyway.
And then, 21.
He uh, he met with emperor, the emperor of the
Liang dynasty, Emperor Wu. This is a very
famous interchange, okay? Hey, it's funny
how children, there's so many children here today
who are listening about these words of
wisdom and they have no clue what we're
talking about.
[Master Yong Hua laughs]
It's fantastic. Ah.
It's called brainwashing, you know that?
It's called Buddhist brainwashing. You
bring them here, and you put on- you can do
the same thing at home, by the way. Turn
on the,
the, the tapes and, and you let them
play, while they listen to all this thing
we talk about. It's called
brainwashing.
In the future, they become, they become, you
know a monk, and with
the Patriarch as well.
So Emperor Wu,
who is, uh, uh, who prided himself on, on being
knowledge about Buddhism.
He spoke to him through an
interpreter, of course.
And, um,
who is that interpreter is probably, in
my humble opinion, in my
opinion, he's that interpreter, probably an
ancestor, of our, of our
precious Zhi Hong.
Oh, you don't know Zhi Hong, it doesn't
matter, okay. So Emperor Wu says,
"Ah, in my entire life I helped a lot of
monks and nuns uh, become monks and nuns,"
because when you become monks and nuns you need
to have clothing, proper clothing. So he
paid for the clothing, for the bowls, for
the shoes and so forth, okay?
And he built monasteries for them. So
he said, "I've done all those and
have a lot of Sutras copied, okay?
And uh, created a lot of Buddha images, okay.
And how, how much merit did I earn?" Okay
Bodhidharma says, "None."
And, and uh,
says, "Good deeds done with
greed,
worldly intent," okay,
I would translate it as greed,
okay?
He did all those to impress people.
Okay? When you do good deeds to impress
others, it's,
it's called worldly intent, is
self-serving, in other words, okay?
And so you're greedy for recognition
in other words.
You're greedy for rewards, okay? Uh.
That's the wrong way
to do
good deeds.
You should do good deeds because
because,
there's a chance to do it.
That's all. When we have the chance to do
something good, just do it and then
forget it.
Okay? Uh. That's all.
And, and uh,
so Bodhidharma said, "You did a
good deed,
you bring good karma, uh,
but no merit."
Okay? And the Emperor uh, uh,
then pursued. He says,
"What is the highest meaning?" So he, he
didn't like it, so he changed the topic,
you see?
Emperor's most convenient, but actually
after he heard the first answer, he says
"No merit whatsoever," he says,
"You just lost an ear, boy," I mean Indian
guy! [Master Yonghua laughs]
So he said, "Okay, but I'm going to be
civil,
he's a Patriarch, supposedly.
So, I can be, I'm an emperor, so I need to
show my civil side." So he said, he changed
the subject, and said. What he- He said,
"What is the highest meaning of the noble
truth?"
Okay? See? He's very well-read. Bodhidharma
says, "There's no, no, no
noble truth. There's only
emptiness."
Okay?
Bodhidharma actually by then, was a little bit, uh, uh,
cautious because he could tell that uh,
the emperor was not happy with him, and
there's no point in offending him evem
more than he needs to, needed to. So he
said, "There's no more truth, there's only
emptiness." Actually
he could have said from a Chan
perspective, uh,
what is the highest meaning of noble
truth? Uh. Uh.
He could have said, uh,
nothing.
But no, he said, "There's no noble truth,
there's only emptiness." So you can tell
he's scared.
23.
And then the emperor
again was stumped. He said, "I can't pursue
this, so
let's give him another, uh, one last chance
Who's standing before me?"
Okay?
Meaning zhèn, zhèn is Chinese for "I'm
better than you."
You see? He says, "I'm better than you.
I'm, I'm
nobility, and you are uh,
black. Um,
dark-skinned I mean." Uh.
And Bodhidharma says, "I know not Your
Majesty," okay? You know,
"I know not"- hmm,
The proper translation should be, change it
to, "I
cannot tell."
Master Xian Jie, don't just sit there, do something.
"I cannot tell." You see? The, the
immediate answer is so beautiful.
He says,
uh, I say, he says, "Duì zhèn zhě shuí." Um.
Who's in front of me?
Can you try, change it please?
"Who's in front of me?"
Okay?
"Who's facing me?"
Either one.
Okay?
And so the, the brutal answer from, from,
Bodhidharma, he meant in english is,
"I can't tell."
Alright? Uh.
So, and
after that, the emperor gave up
and uh, he said uh, uh,
"Excuse me, I need to go take this
phone call here. Uh.
From Russia."
And uh,
so later, he had an advisor.
Would you believe it's Zhi Gong?
Zhi Gong is one of the, of the
wisest Chinese monks, and what does he do
advising this kind of emperor? Oh my
goodness!
I, I, I,
when I got to this point here, I lost all
respect for Zhi Gong.
Because if you hang around this person,
who was thirsty for power, recognition,
greedy, he was so greedy,
okay? The only way that you can
help,
is yourself.
Because that's how he sees you.
Okay? If Zhi Gong is a true Patriarch,
a great, a person of great wisdom, he'd say, "I'm
sorry, young master, okay, I'm not worthy of
your patronage."
Here's,
uh, the master at the DRBA, go over there.
Okay? Yeah so, uh, I, I,
it's a personal thing for me because
I know I was growing up, I mean when I
was learning the Way, uh,
Master Xuan Hua
spoke so highly of Master Zhi Gong. He
had spiritual powers and so forth. When
I got to this point here, I said
"What are you doing, advising this emperor?"
So he's this way because you advised him?
So he's your creation. He's a product of
your training, right?
So, I would run, uh, okay? That's why Zhi Gong
is, you know, out. Uh, uh.
So Zhi Gong says,
"Your Highness, uh,
still don't recognize this person?" Bì xià hái shí cǐ rén fǒu?
Hm. So you don't recognize this person, okay?
And the emperor says, "Uh, uh,
I don't."
And Zhi Gong says, "This is Guan Yin
transmitting the Buddha's Mind Seal."
Okay?
So Zhi Gong says Bodhidharma actually is, is
Guan Yin.
So clearly, Guan Yin has nothing else to do.
But we, we have so many Bodhisattvas,
and Guan Yin says, "Let me bring
Mahayana from India to China. You, the rest of
you can go on vacation, go to the Bahamas,
or you, uh,
take a hike, and you know, or something.
Let me do it for you."
So the rest of the Bodhisattvas say, [Master Yonghua makes bewildered expression]
"So we don't get a chance to create
blessings for ourselves?"
Okay? So,
I don't know about this Zhi Gong guy
here. Okay? Yeah, with all due respect to the
Chinese and Taiwanese people.
And um, and so the emperor heard that
this is a Sage, so he was uh, he, he, uh, he
had second thoughts and tried to, uh,
send
his, uh, uh,
boy to ask the
Venerable Bodhidharma to backtrack
and come back so that he can make
offerings and support him.
Uh, uh, and
Zhi Gong says, uh,
"No, don't bother. Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
Even if,
uh, uh, uh, uh, uh
even if the entire nation
goes,
all our people go, okay,
he
still
wouldn't come back." Hm.
Okay? Uh.
So he says, uh, uh,
gai guó rén qù
And he says, "Even if
we all go,
okay?
He still would not, will not come back.
Not return. Would not come back." Alright?
And so,
this is a story of a transmission
from India, uh,
Mahayana,
from India to China. So Venerable Bodhidharma went to
Nan Jing,
listen Dharma Shen Kuang, um,
speak Dharma. And back then it'ss typical, as
typical as it is nowadays, people speak
Dharma without
wisdom.
They spoke words.
They didn't,
they didn't
teach, uh,
from the wisdom,
but from
regurgitating
the, uh, the, uh,
the technical jargon. Uh.
But even doing, even for uh,
just doing so, the heavens rain
fragrant blossoms
and golden-petaled lotus rose from earth.
Okay.
And so he's uh, he's uh, an
extraordinary
Dharma Master,
to the point where the heaven lands were
making offerings to him.
And so Bodhidharma stopped by, listened
to his lecture,
and waited for everyone to leave,
and
cornered
down Master Shen Kuan, and asked
him,
"What, uh, what
are you doing?" And Shen Kuang says, "I am
explaining Sutras. Can't you tell?" Uh.
And he said, uh,
"Why are you explaining the Sutras?" He
said, uh,
"The answer is, uh, to teach people to end
birth and death."
And Bodhidharma says,
"How does it happen?
Okay? The words are black and white,
how does
black and white, you know, uh, uh,
things can end birth and death?"
And Shen Kuang
couldn't have an answer. Uh.
And this is the lesson I learned: do not
offend the Chinese Patriarchs, the
Chinese Dharma Masters.
Okay? It's okay for you to offend me
because I'm not Chinese, uh, uh,
but, but this is a common protocol, uh,
in that, uh,
you don't, you don't ask questions that, that
Dharma Masters cannot answer,
okay?
Please.
And, uh,
but Shen Kuang is able to-
has a little bit of a temper, a temper. He got
very upset and he whipped out his beads, uh,
made of steels,
okay, and whacked them.
He says, "These are the words of the
demons,"
and broke the two front tooth. So
Bodhidharma has a new nickname! Leon
Spinks! [Audience laughs] Hm.
Yeah,
so, uh,
you know, so whack him and say, "You the
demon! How dare you embarrass me! It's
the demon's word! You're doing demons',
you know..."
And, and so he broke his teeth because
Bodhidharma didn't dodge at all.
I remember, and
to this point I remember that video of
President Bush, the small one,
when he went to Afghanistan, someone
threw a shoe at him, [Master Yonghua laughs]
he went like this [Master Yonghua dodges]
He ducked and he ducked in this funny way
too. [Master Yonghua dodges again]
But Bodhidharma is like a true Indian
Patriarch,
stood there and
lost two teeth.
I hope he gets a good dentist. [Audience laughs]
Can you imagine we speak Dharma and then
as we smile, and the front of our mouth
is black? [Maser Yonghua laughs]
Oh yuh, yuh.
What was he thinking?
I would have ducked myself, like Little
Bush.
And, uh,
Bodhidharma, uh, uh,
apparently, according to Chinese, the
Chinese wisdom, it says, there's a legend
where if
a Sage's tooth
fall to the Earth, it would not rain for
three years. That's probably what
happened here in California.
Uh, and so Bodhidharma says, "That would harm a
lot of people,
so I better take the pain, uh,
and suffering, uh,
instead of, uh,
letting bad things happen to the Chinese
people, uh,
although they deserve it."
So, so, the tooth fell out, and so he
swallowed it,
okay?
And then he went away,
And then,
and then,
according to Master Xuan Hua, yes. Did
you have a comment? Black? White? Red?
That, that video person, audio person he sits
like he's in a trance.
Yeah, Red.
Speaker Red: "Right, yeah, so
my question is,
by swallowing the teeth,
does,
it solves the problem? So it will rain
for three years, or it solved that
problem or-?"
Master Yong Hua: No, it wouldn't rain for three years for
that. Speaker Red: "It wouldn't rain for three years?"
Master Yong Hua: You need the dragon's intervention,
but at least there won't be a, uh,
a drought for three years.
Because it would, if, if he let the tooth,
the teeth fell, fall to the ground,
they would have a drought for three
years.
So, there would be no drought for the next,
because of that, okay?
So, uh,
uh, so, uh,
he swallowed them and disappeared, okay?
And, and, and uh, and so
according to Master Xuan Hua,
I remember this part. Master Xuan Hua
said, uh,
immediately right after that, and you
know, please take a grain of salt, you
know,
he's not here so
we don't know.
There's lots of things, folks, I
wish I were there, because I have so many
questions.
I'm not like a typical American who
are, you know, very afraid of Master Xuan Hua, I
would have asked him,
"Great Master,
really? I mean I hit the thing and all of
a sudden, the
fame of Shen Kuang
was supposed to die right away?
Do you buy that or not?"
I find it's, it's too much a coincidence.
What's the rationale for that?
You believe it or not?
When I read that story, I said,
"Seriously?
You hit someone and broke two tooth, I
mean Leon Spinks never, you know,
killed anyone because of that. No one
died because of that."
But,
there is a point to this story.
Why did he die immediately?
Because
he
inflicted harm on a
great, great Sage. Supposedly Guan Yin
according to Zhi Gong, which I
respectfully disagree, okay?
Guan Yin would never fight with the
Bodhisattvas.
Would not compete for,
for blessings from Bodhisattvas, I assure
you,
okay?
We have so many great Bodhisattvas who
are waiting,
are craving to bring Mahayana from India
to China. Why would Guan Yin Bodhisattva
steal those
merit and virtues
from them? Hm?
Think about it, it just didn't make sense
to me, okay?
Anyway!
Uh, so,
what happened is, this uh, this uh,
this monk here,
Shen Kuang, okay,
injured a Great Sage.
For that
mere fact there,
he's
supposed to fall to
the
Avici Hell, the worst hells there is.
Just for that.
That's how serious it is.
Okay? And therefore
it's perfectly reasonable to say that
he's supposed to die right away, because
you know how, how, how big of a name
Bodhidharma was,
then he deserves to die immediately,
because it's very serious offence.
So, so,
he's supposed to die, so two ghosts
came and said,
"Our boss, King Yama would like to have a
word with you," which is the, you know, the
the Underworld, uh,
the word for, uh,
okay,
it's time for you to go.
Okay, and Bodhidharma said, uh no,
Shen Kuang says,
"Why? I'm so young, in the prime of my life,
you know?
Can I have some more time?" He said, "Nope!
Your time is up." "Just like that?!" He said, "Yep!"
So, so, uh,
Shen Kuang, says, "What did I do? What did I
do?"
And he said, "You don't know? Hah!
You broke the two front teeth
of a Great Sage.
That's why."
And so Shen Kuang says,
"Uh. Oh.
I didn't know, if I knew I would have not
done it." Okay?
The ghost says,
"Not my problem."
okay.
"Let's go!"
And uh, and uh,
Shen Kuang got on his knees, I think and
then begged to the ghost says, "Look at me,
I'm the Dharma Master, you're the ghost I
beg to you, give me some time, uh, so that I
learned from this monk a little bit so
that my life would not have been in vain."
Okay?
And so, uh,
the ghost must have been a high-ranking ghost,
he says, "Okay I'm seeing that
you
are sincere, I allow you a little bit of
time, go and look for that monk and, and uh, and uh,
do you think, we'll wait a
little bit for you."
And so
Shen Kuang, uh, uh,
ran after,
after Bodhidharma. By that time,
okay, Bodhidharma was walking towards
the south, yes he went south.
Is it south?
No that's Sixth Patrarich, you confused.
So he went somewhere [Master Yong Hua laughs]
And he passed by a house
where
they kept, there's a bird,
is kept in a cage, a bird cage,
okay?
And, and uh, and uh
the bird, uh, uh, uh
recognized Bodhidharma and said, uh,
recognize, somehow this bird recognized
Bodhidharma as a Sage,
so the bird asked him,
"Mind from the West, Mind from the West, Teach me
a way, To escape from this cage."
Uh,
Flaming Hair, can you do it in, in a more
birdy kind of way?
Try your best.
Bird language now.
Very good, very good, yeah.
One more time. [Audience laughs]
Second version.
Unmute it, hey Korea, unmute it.
I can't hear you.
Speaker Flaming Hair: "Can you hear me?" Master Yong Hua: Okay now, now. Go.
Speaker Flaming Hair: "Mind from the West! Mind from the West!
Please teach me how to escape
from this cage!" [Master Yong Hua laughs] [Audience claps]
Uh, and Bodhidharma immediately replied, "Okay,
let's find a new voice."
Uh, uh, China's
Chinese person there.
Huh? Uh.
So Bodhidharma replied, "To escape from
the cage; to escape from the cage,
put out both
legs, close both eyes,
this is a way to escape from the cage!"
Okay, spoke bird language.
Uh, and, and uh, and uh, and uh,and uh, and uh,
And
that's what the bird did, and uh, the
owner thought the bird was dead, so
opened the cage and tried to
take the body out, but the bird
flew up, okay. So that's how the bird
escaped,
okay. The great escape, if you will, uh,
but the bird escaped.
So anyway, the story, legend has it that Shen
Kuang ran after Bodhidharma
and went all the way to
be a Bear's Ear Mountain in, in Lo Yang,
and uh, sat down facing a wall that's right
behind the
future Shaolin Temple, okay? Hm.
And
Shen Kuang knelt
close by, um,
behind him apparently, for nine years.
And when I read this, I said nine years?
Uh,
how can you do that for nine years?
Well anyway, so he sat for nine years, and
I'm, first question is, uh,
what about bathroom breaks?
And uh, um,
and um, uh,
so they sat behind
MAster Bodhidharma for,
for nine years, and Bodhidharma ignored
him completely, didn't talk to him for
nine years,
okay?
And Shen Kuang
never gave up.
It's a test. Hm?
It's a test. And uh,
test of sincerity, okay. And one
day,
after nine years,
Shen Kuang
never dared bother
Bodhidharma. If you were there and
begging for instruction, you don't want
to nag him,
you know. Xun,
you hear? You don't want to nag.
I would not nag, okay.
For something important, I would not nag. Uh, uh.
And, uh, and uh, um, mmm, and uh, and
one day, uh, uh, uh,
Bodhidharma
asked him a question. This is very
important. There's a protocol here.
You
would kneel behind, you ask for a favor
you ask once and you wait, okay, you don't
nag.
And then, and then, so he waited for nine years.
This is beautiful, this is so beautiful
of a story to me,
okay?
It is so important to you, he said, "How do
I end birth and death?
Venerable Master, teach me how to end birth
and death."
Alright?
You don't text him
to death. [Audience laughs]
Okay, you ask once.
How can I end birth and death, and then you
kneel down and you wait.
You can do anything you like, [Master Yonghua drops head from one side to another]
but you don't nag him anymore.
[Master Yong Hua looks behind] The timing is always perfect! [Audience laughs]
And, and uh, so after nine years,
interestingly, uh, this is so remarkable of Venerable
Shen Kuang,
I'm impressed by that. That for
us in my era, waiting for nine years
behind him like that is total nonsense,
the sheer nonsense. I don't know about
you, I cannot do this, no way, it doesn't
make sense to me, okay? Uh.
That's why i'm glad that Shen Kuang did
it for us.
Thank you China. [Master Yong Hua looks up]
And, and um, and
after nine years, so it's like,
it's interestingly like a delay, how do I,
how do I end birth and death?
Okay?
And
Venerable Bodhidharma didn't say anything
for nine years,
ignored him completely. And the guy would
not go away, so after nine years BOdhidharma says,
"You're still
here?
What's the matter with you?" And he said, "I'm
waiting for the answer," and he said, "I will
answer you when the snow becomes red." Okay?
And so Shen Kuang, uh, uh, uh,
got so upset
that he took out a knife and cut his
left arm or right arm? This is what I don't
remember. Is it right arm? Right arm,
okay.
I am right-handed, so I think I would take
my left arm, cut my right arm.
It shows more- it's more emphatic. [Master Yong Hua laughs]
So in this movie of mine,
you take this knife here, this probably
has not been sharpened yet,
and you hack away your armor, [Master Yong Hua laughs]
So anyway, so it finally
cut off and fell to the ground, and the
snow become red, became red. So he scooped
up
some red snow with, tainted with blood,
corrupted with blood,
and then, and then,
and "So great Master, great Master, hey!
This- the snow- there's red snow! The snow
has become red!"
And,
now Master Xuan Hua says,
Venerable Shen Kuang
was so upset, he had a temper so he cut
his arm off to show him. Uh,
he's probably right, I would never
disagree with my, my Chinese teacher,
okay?
Yeah ching! [Master Yong Hua points above his head]
[Master Yong Hua laughs]
So, so,
Bodhidharma is impressed,
and um,
and he said, "Ah! You,
you
are a pretty tough cookie."
And, and um, and um, uh, and uh,
"So it is, so it is," he says, "Wow you're
tough, so you're tough."
Okay? Uh. Ru shi. Ru shi. So it is ru shi, ru shi.
"You're so tough, so am I."[Master Yong Hua laughs]
Okay? "You're crazy, so am I."
Uh, and he says, he says uh,
"You are worthy
to be my student."
Okay? "So I will teach you, I teach you
what I know," okay? And "So my wait has
not been in vain."
Imagine this guy, this great teacher has
been looking for a descendant,
for a successor, for a long time.
He saw it in Venerable Shen Kuang, but
still put him through the test,
okay?
A lot of, in Buddhism, it's about
enduring uh, the test, okay?
And uh,
that's called
what?
What is that called?
Gradual
teaching.
The tests are
gradual
teaching.
You see that? That's how
Mahayana was transmitted from India to
China.
Gradual teaching for nine years.
So he sat there, he knelt behind him for
nine years. So every day, he said, "Oh my
legs hurt, and
it hurt so much, what am I doing here? What
am I doing here? I can't even tell my
mother about this.
She doesn't want me to become a monk in
the first place, now I have to tell her
I'm kneeling behind this
dark-skinned monk who cannot speak a
single word of Chinese?
And when he decides to teach me how
we're gonna, what are we gonna use? Google
Translate?"
You see? It has so many issues there
that's unresolved, okay? And yet he knelt,
and Bodhidharma didn't talk to him, he
didn't dare ask, okay?
And, and uh, so,
part of the teaching is
you
need to go through hardship,
because that's part of your gradual
training.
Don't expect shortcuts. They say,
"Tell me the best thing,
Give me the Sudden Teaching
right away, okay?" No,
you have to pass the test,
you have to go through the gradual
training first.
And then there's a final test where you
actually have to cut off your arm.
Is that a question you asked? Do you have
to cut off your arm, yes.
Speaker: "I have a question-" Master Yonghua: Another question?
Speaker: "It's a little bit random uh it's associated
with what you just talk about the
conversation between Shen Kuang and uh
Bodhidharma..."
Master Yong Hua: Yeah.
Speaker: "Like, I'm curious back then, what kind of
language they are using when they
communicate with each other? Do they
speak Chinese or do they speak Indian
language? How did they communicate with
each other?" [Audience laughs]
Master Yonghua:
What did I tell you? [Audience laughs]
I will forgive you this one time.
You never ask a question I cannot answer.
Speaker: "Okay, I'm sorry." [Speaker laughs] Master Yong Hua: Okay, don't do it again.
Next question! [Audience laughs]
How do I know? I wasn't there.
But if I have to lie to you,
okay,
how do they communicate? That's a good
question.
You see, you're so lucky that I, I am so lenient,
because I had the same question too. I
said, you know
the guy didn't speak Chinese and the
other guy didn't speak Indian,
how could they talk?
Snow, red and all those things that's a lot of
vocabulary, come on! [Master Yong Hua laughs]
I'm missing something here! Yes, old monk.
Venerable Xian Chi: "Emituofo." [Vietnamese]
Master Yong Hua: Okay, let's let Master Xian Ren
translate this important message.
Venerable Xian Ren: "Um Master,
whatever the um,
Sage,
sagely people
did, we cannot uh,
talk about it, but,
uh,
earlier we went through the story that
the Patriarch talked to the um,
bird. Actually the bird asked the
question and then the Patriarch gave
it the instruction.
And then the bird understand.
And then another story is Yong-A [?]
when she meditate
and she saw Amitabha Buddha appeared
wearing a yellow robe,
and she,
uh, in her mind, arrives a question like,
why Amitabha Buddha
wear yellow robe? And suddenly an answer
came to her mind, like
wait until you die that's when I will
wear a red robe.
So the Buddha
can communicate
through the mind, and the same thing like uh,
in 1976 when I was in the prison and
then I,
in my dream I saw
Buddha appear and then, uh, I
I have a question, I had a question in my
mind, and then suddenly the Buddha
answered me using the Vietnamese. He
didn't use uh,
Chinese or English or whatever, he used
Vietnamese to help me to understand. So
in the Sutra, Avamtasaka Sutra,
say that the Buddha
has a lot of different way to
communicate to help beings understand."
Master Yong Hua: You get that? You buy that?
You believe anything, do ya? [sigh]
When you think,
you think in what language?
You think in Chinese, yes?
Yin, you think in Yietnamese or English?
English, okay. But you Vietnamese, right?
Okay, Vietnamese-Chinese. Her mother is
Vietnamese-Chinese.
Okay, so you have Chinese here, English
here.
Xiao Tai when you think, what do you
think? In what language do you use?
Speaker Xiao Tai: "Chinese and English." Master Yong Hua: Chinese and English!
Half-Chinese, half-English. Very good.
Okay, you see? Uh,
so, uh, so uh,
what happened
is that
the thinking-
do you really think is in Chinese or
English?
How come she thinks in English, how come
you think in in Chinese?
Before you verbalize it, right?
when you think
Chinese- [Master Yong Hua mimicks Chinese sounds]
[Master Yong Hua laughs] And Yin would say [Master Yong Hua mimics Chinese sounds] [Master Yong Hua laughs]
So,
these are thoughts. How come
she sees, she hears herself as in Chinese, and
she hears herself as English? Why?
My Master,
when I was a novice and I was supposed
to be trained to sit sleep,
okay? And I hated it. I hated it.
Say,
we suffer all day,
ate one meal a day, and we can't even
sleep within comfort? What kind of what
kind of, kind of, nonsense is this? So I really
struggled with that concept of having to
sit-sleep. And I tried two years
unsuccessfully,
okay?
And then one night in Long Beach
Monastery, hm,
after two years,
okay, I was sleeping. I started as usual with,
with sitting, and then eventually I slide
down slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly and
lean against the wall, and then pretty
soon
you unbuckle a little bit, [Audience laughs],
a little bit, very slow motion
and eventually. [Master Yong Hua leans back further and makes noise of conent]
Like that!
No, no, not even- [Master Yong Hua laughs]
Actually he's listening to our lecture,
seriously?
He's not even playing with his kids out there?
Uh, and, and
one night, I was doing that like every
single night, okay, and one night I heard, I heard
Master Xuan Hua's voice,
okay?
He said, he said ,uh,
"Get up!
Cross your legs!"
He's screaming at me. Seriously.
And I immediately jumped up, crossed my
legs, [Master Yong Hua laughs]
without thinking.
I was so scared.
I never saw
him that angry.
I always have this, you know, the last
time I saw him was, you know, he was dying.
Okay? He was on his deathbed. He said, "Oh I
love you, you know, and you're all so good,
you're such a wonderful student," and so
forth, okay?
But never been that angry before,
okay? I was so scared, I immediately
crossed my legs, and sat the rest of the
night in full lotus.
And right after that, I could easily sit
in full lotus.
Every single night.
Okay?
And the instruction he gave me was?
Yin?
Yin! I call you! I'm looking at her, but I'm
calling your name! [Audience laughs] Yin,
it's the first time you attend my Sutra
lecture and can't I make use of you as a
prop?
After 10 years, you've finally attended my
Sutra lecture, the first time.
Is that right? You never attended my
lecture.
That didn't count, not until today. [Audience laughs]
Exactly! Speaker: "I think he spoke in English!" Master Yong Hua: Exactly. He
spoke in English.
Okay, yeah.
Why?
Speaker: "It's more direct?
I think that's all I could think of."
Master Yong Hua: Because
I think in English.
I don't think in Vietnamese. I think in
English.
Unless I talk to the Vietnamese, and then
I think in Vietnamese.
But typically, when I talk to normal
people,
non-Vietnamese, I think in English.
But when I talk to the old monk,
then I switch to Vietnamese in my thoughts.
Just like you. That's just like uh,
the boy,
what happened to him now?
Okay? So the point here is that
if Master Xuan Hua can talk to me in English,
to make sure I understood, because that's
my
pattern.
Unless you're Vietnamese,
I only think in
English.
So in order to teach me,
he used English to make sure I got the
message,
immediately. No interpretation, no
translation. Yes green!
Speaker Green: "Is it really he spoke English or-" Master Yong Hua: Yes.
Speaker Green: "Or is it just your mind translated?" Master Yong Hua: I heard
his voice, that anger.
I am traumatized.
For the rest of my life.
And as I just
think about, revisit that moment i'm
still
shaking right now.
It's how scary,
he's violent. That's when I first learned
about violence.
It's okay to be violent towards your own
disciples.
Okay?
Yes?
So, so the point here is that, uh,
here's what happens.
Your thought has no language.
Thoughts have no language. For example,
when I taught that boy yesterday,
the troublemaker,
about shame on you,
okay?
When he was about to cry, you remember?
You know, he fell on his butt, his right
butt, and he got up and he was
going like this [Master Yong Hua looks up and rubs his behind] and he's about to cry,
I laughed at him.
So I said,
"Shame on you!"
You know?
And he immediately got the message,
okay?
That right there, when I taught him right
there, talking about shame, okay?
It's not in English at all.
It's not in Chinese at all. He does not
understand Chinese.
I only taught him about this conce-
thought called
shame.
And he got it right away. He stood up and he
didn't cry, he stopped. He's
about to cry so I immediately tested him,
and said you should be ashamed instead
of crying! So immediately, he said, "Yeah, I'm not
going to cry!" So he ran over there and he
hid himself. Okay?
So the communications
had no language. He got it.
So yesterday, I was playing with him, I
taught him five different emotions, and
he got them all.
So the thought
in communication
has no language.
But you
add another layer on top of yourself
because you need to talk to
your thinking mind. So that's why you
translated internally. You're wiring it, it
translated from that thought language,
which is pure thoughts into
Engli-, uh, Chinese, excuse me.
Taiwanese or Chinese?
Chinese.
Mandarin.
Okay?
Whereas, that one there is in English.
Okay? So,
that's why,
that's how they could communicate.
It turns out, by the way, uh,
for
important lessons,
important teachings, you cannot afford
to
be
uh, be,
distracted by languages.
So i'm sure that Bodhidharma, Venerable
Bodhidharma, he, when he wanted to teach
Shen Kuang,
he could talk to him directly through
his mind, and Shen Kuang could understand,
okay? And the,
this is the storytelling where Master Xuan Hua
would explain it to us in Chinese and we
translate it into English, so
it's, it's for our
understanding. But for them, it's direct,
very direct, mind to mind, if you will.
Okay?
Just like you, um,
Venerable Bodhidharma
sent him a thought, okay? Talked him in,
in thoughts and Shen Kuang would translate
that thought into Chinese,
if you will. That's what happened.
Does it help?
Okay. Just remember,
no more questions today. [Audience laughs]
But he's, the old monk is correct, okay?
He's right, but you understand
that's exactly-
the first layer is thought language.
Thought has no language.
Thought is just thought. When you,
you do mind, you're able to read minds
like
Venerable Bodhidharma, okay? You can read
people's mind, that has no language, okay?
He can read your mind her mind, your mind
is in Chinese, her mind's Vietnamese, and
his mind, God knows what language, we
don't know, okay? So it doesn't matter at
all. So the first layer is thought,
thought is just thought.
And then next layer is language.
Alright? That's how it works.
Next! Hm.
So
this
gradual teaching that Bodhidharma did
for Shen Kuang,
spanned nine years.
It's very important.
Okay? Do not expect
immediate results. Like we, in our era,
are accustomed to
instant gratification. It takes time,
okay?
It takes time
to prepare,
it takes time
to
let the wine mature
properly. You cannot rush it. Even soy
sauce
needs to be matured naturally.
Is that clear?
Or
fish sauce for that matter.
Go ahead Wei Mountain.
Speaker from Wei Mountain Temple: "Master, when the, that baby yesterday you
played,
that he fall down, did you read his mind?"
[Audience laughs]
Master Yong Hua: Yes.
Now you mentioned it...
now you brought it up, yes.
Oh what a stupid question. Of course I
did [Master Yong Hua luaghs] I mean uh-
occasionally. Because yesterday
I
finally found my soul mate, uh,
a
mischievous mind.
That boy was causing trouble all
afternoon for four hours, while you were
here, the small gathering, like
five, six of us gathered together and
talking, and telling your stories and so
forth. And the boy was, you know,
creating mischief after mischief and
so forth. And I was like, oh this boy sounds like my kind
of soul mate.
So it intrigued me so I was
starting to, I started paying
attention to what he was going through his
mind. How does he create mischiefs? So I
was more intrigued by that, okay?
So
I was able to connect with him
at that mischievous level, that's it. And
you call it thought-reading, mind-reading,
so be it.
Guilty.
Okay? [Master Yong Hua laughs] Uh.
So anyway, so Bodhidharma, uh, uh,
so the real question is, now, how does he
transmit the teaching, mind to mind
teaching. This is
very, very precise language. How is he
gonna teach something he does not
understand the language, or speak the
language?
Okay, you, I would not dare use
the Chinese to teach you mind to mind,
for example.
Never because my Chinese is horrible.
Okay,
so
but Bodhidharma decided to transmit
the Sudden Teaching. The Chan Dharma Door
here,
okay?
Translation for you: Chan Dharma Door here
is Sudden Teaching.
Because he taught the Chan Dharma Door for
nine years already,
the Gradual Dharma Door,
okay?
Venerable SHen Kuang
saw
how
Bodhidharma was teaching him, not by
language, not by thoughts but by,
what?
By what? [Master Yong Hua shakes his head] Mmm.
By what?
Yes Chinese person?
Speaker Chinese person: "Tests? Tests?"
Master Yong Hua: No tests. That's too Chinese.
Anyone else?
Yes,
from the Philippines. [Audience laughs]
You want to make it sound so, like we
so international! [Audience laughs]
Yes. Speaker from the Philippines: "By his behavior."
Master Yong Hua: Nope, wrong, Philippines doesn't have it. [Audience laughs]
Yellow, yes.
Speaker Yellow: "Emituofo uh he sat for nine
years as well."
Master Yong Hua: [Master Yong Hua yawns] [Audience laughs] Anyone else? Old monk, I'm sure the old
monk wants to say something.
[Audience laughs] Venerable Xian Chi: [Vietnamese]
Master Yong Hua: Eeeh! Don't even translate! [Audience laughs]
Green. Speaker Green: "By, uh, let him suffer."
Master Yong Hua: Pretty good.
Not quite, but yeah, it's pretty good, it's
pretty good.
It's pretty good, excellent. And you are
devious.
I would be careful, you know, if I were
your husband.
Anyone else?
By?
Doing.
So, for example, this is just my
imagination,
okay? Please take a grain of salt,. There's
no proof.
Don't ask me [Master Yong Hua points at an audience member]
how do you know?
I was talking a Korean person, you know,
two nights ago and she says,
"Why are you so sure?"
You don't ask someone that, you know, are
you sure? How can you be so sure? I just,
it's
not proper.
Anyway,
what Bodhidharma did for Shen Kuang is
that,
if you can imagine Shen Kuang is
hot stuff,
he's revered by lay people, he's uh,
he's well respected, impressed by the
heavenly beings, okay? He's a hot shot,
okay? But Shen Kuang is not used to
kneeling behind someone like that.
So initially, I assure you Shen Kuang had
thoughts of quitting.
He said, "This is nonsense,
okay? It's going nowhere. What am I doing?
Let's go back and face death.
It's less embarrassing than this. How can
I explain to my supporters I kneeled behind
this dark
skinned monk,
bushy beard,
who
ignores me completely?"
Okay? Hm.
And
when these thoughts of quitting
arose in, in, in the, in
Shen Kuang's mind, Bodhidharma
would
do something- [Master Yong Hua heavily coughing]-
and the thought would die.
Okay? So Shen Kuang actually
received help from Bodhidharma, uh,
invisibly, otherwise there's no way
Shen Kuang could have lasted nine years.
So what
Bodhidharma did for Shen Kuang is that
he
invisibly
helped Shen Kuang
not quit.
Otherwise he would have quit nine years ago, a
long, long, time ago. Does it make sense to
you?
No ordinary person, unless they be, they
are a sage, would do this silly thing for
nine years. That's impossible. That's
totally nonsense. Unless he was helped.
Is that clear?
Okay?
So don't be so full yourself.
Your progress actually
is, rece-,
your practice has a lot of help from a
lot of good guys. We're on the good side
of the fence, of the railroad tracks, okay?
When you do this good thing here, you
receive so much help, trust me.
So Shen Kuang got help from Bodhidharma,
because Bodhidharma would make sure that
he was not,
he would not quit,
okay? And then for example,
in the summertime it's very, very hot,
okay, uh,
and Shen Kuang was perspiring for
example, and he said, "I can't take this
much, I'm going to pass out this heat," and
all of a sudden, there's this light breeze. [Master Yong Hua blows gently]
So the Dharma protectors would
blow air,
cool air, not hot air.
Seriously, when you're hot, someone does
this for you,
it changes you, it gives you the kind of
relief that's so much appreciated.
So Shen Kuang
had a lot of help, a lot of support,
because not only
Bodhidharma was helping him, the Dharma
protectors around Venera-
Venerable Bodhidharma was
also assisting him,
you know ,in so many invisible ways.
We on the good side guys, if you think
that the demons are causing a lot of
problems out there, I assure you the good
guys are also helping us as well.
Okay?
That's what happened.
That's the only way that this could have
transpired,
in my opinion.
Lesson?
Don't be so full of yourself.
We're receiving a lot of help,
a lot more help than we are aware of.
Alright? Hm.
So anyway, uh, hm, okay. And
why do we go into
Da Hui Song? Or Zhong?
Zhong,
whatever, okay. So anyway, the main
thing here, I don't know why we got into this, this, uh, this uh
Da Hui here,
okay, but the interesting
point here, is that
Venerable Bodhidharma
transmitted
the Sudden Teaching
to Shen Kuang.
Okay, and that
is the seal
behind the transmission from generation to
generation.
Somehow,
they have
to
transmit the Sudden Teaching to the next
generation,
because that is the essence of
Chan.
That is essence of Mahayana.
I'm sorry Korean Sunims,
Chan is not,
it's not, uh,
Seon
is not, is not, uh, Hua Tou,
okay? Seon is
the Sudden Teaching.
That's how you can tell whether you have
real Chan or not. For example
in Japan,
they don't have Sudden Teaching at all.
There's no mention of it,
yeah,
from the documents I read in English.
No mention of Sudden teaching. It's all
about you know more Hinayana
aspects of Chan, of meditation.
Alright?
Uh,
anyway,
I don't know why we had 43 here, this Da Hui
here,
uh,
real Chan, real Chan is [uninteliigible]
So, so, so,
after
Venerable Bodhidharma
taught
Shen Kuang, okay,
that
special
Sudden Teaching right there, Shen Kuang
immediately became enlightened. That's
how you transmit the Sudden Teaching.
Then Bodhidharma recognized Shen Kuang, uh,
was, was uh, was uh, was
right there at the
threshold,
okay,
and then,
Shen Kuang who later became Hui Ke, uh,
said, "Uh, uh, now that the arm hurts," uh,
and he says,
"My, my, I am troubled by the pain in my
arm. Okay? Please help me
calm my mind down." And Bodhidharma says,
"Bring me your mind, I will calm it down
for you,"
and Hui Ke says,
"Uhh... I can't find my mind, how can I bring it
to you?" okay he said, "Then I pacify your
mind."
And is, and at that point Hui Ke, Hui Ke
then
crossed the threshold, and went into the
world, the realm of Enlightenment.
Time is up? Oh my God, time is up.
So sorry Korea. Uh.
Okay? S‮o
we end here today, thank you all for
coming. And I'm sorry I exceeded the time
limit. Next time we continue 45
okay?
Thank you.
[Audience claps]