you
um
we respectfully request the song of grave
virtues for the sake of disassembly and all
living beings please turn the wonderful dharma
will to teach and guide us how to end birth
and death leave suffering and attain bliss
and quickly realized known birth could [Music]
did
[Music]
oh [Music] the blessed noble and perfectly
enlightened
yet
the unsurpassed profound subtle and wonderful
dharma in a hundred thousand million eons
is difficult to encounter now that i'm able
to see in here I will receive and maintain
it I vow to fathom then thus come one's true
and actual principles [Music]
[Music]
[Music] to [Music]
hello everyone thank you all for coming it's
nice to see you today is the 30th of october
2021 and we are
continuing to discuss the sixth patriarch sutra we're
starting over we're on slide number 45. thank
you very much okay so in in the midst of the
story between bodhidharma and how he transmitted
chan to the second patriarch the um the um
uh this uh second patriarch venerable HuiKe
okay before he was ShenGuang, ShenGuang is
his dharma name but then after he became second
patriarch venerable bodhidharma was very kind and gave him
a dharma name and that's what he used um uh
so uh so after after the uh after venerable HuiKe
became enlightened and he went through a lot
of hardship uh imagine yourself having to
kneel for nine hours I mean nine years sorry
not hours nine hours pretty easy uh nine years
all day okay and back then I don't think they
invented the full lotus posture yet
no i'm kidding
i thought I think full lotus came from india
but in china I think it's probably the case
where uh the chinese didn't believe in full
lotus and that's why he made them kneel
for nine years he said see how tough you chinese
people are
and after that HuiKe up knew better I said
oh we better learn teach Chinese how to do
full lotus
because I don't think anyone would be stupid
enough like me to kneel for nine years like
this okay it's extraordinary of a feat you
see this this uh this monk here was uh extraordinary
of a monk okay and extraordinary people moved
through extraordinary extraordinarily difficult
tasks so don't complain you know I said I'm
too sleepy and sit in full lotus then get
up and kneel for nine years
you're such a wimp
okay uh so uh this is so so anyway so HuiKe
when venerable HuiKe, second patriarch HuiKe uh had to
prove himself for nine years before master
Bodhidharma decided to teach him
so after he taught HuiKe taught him the sudden
teaching dharma he named him HuiKe meaning
wise and able uh Hui(慧) here is refers to prajna
wisdom okay meaning that he's certified HuiKe
as the first chinese monk to have prajna
wisdom that's why hui comes first not last
okay Ke(可) here refers that uh he's able to
carry on the burden of propagating Mahayana
he's able to carry on the transmission of
this wonderful sudden teaching Dharma door
all right so oh that's a word of encouragement
i deem you worthy so carry on
and um and uh so HuiKe asked great master Bodhidharma in india do you transmit the dharma
to your disciples did you also give robe and
bowl as certification okay and 46 uh Bohdidharma
replied I transmitted the dharma in India
of course what do you
think it's just like
just like you just gave it to us right I mean
you know not the Indians right your own kind
we better right uh
there's a little bit of racism in here if
I I think and so Bodhidharma has to say yes
of course I transmitted the Dharma I taught
the sudden teaching in India as well but
I did not use a robe and bowl Indian people
are straightforward to attain fruition they
know they must be certified that comes from
the tradition from the great first patriarch
Indian patriarch Mahākāśyapa okay if no one certifies
them they do not say I have attained the way
I have given proof to arhatship I am a
bodhisattva okay so he's saying that the you
Chinese people are not as straightforward
as the Indian back then that is not the case
anymore
unfortunately uh and unfortunately the Chinese
tend to lie
it's probably translation error you know you
know you don't want to bring the Dharma to Chinese
say you are a bunch of liars
many claim sagehood although they fully know
they aren't that's what Indians do by the
way it's not just the Chinese Indians do that
too nowadays therefore I transmit the robe
and bowl to prove that you have received transmission
in other words there's only one robe and bowl
ever gave to the Indian I'm not going to give
it to you so uh I said oh that's uh the answer
and that's the completes the cycle of certification
so we certified uh that HuiKe was enlightened
and then he also uh uh gave him the robe
and bowl as well okay and that's uh happy ending
uh story uh and venerable Bodhidharma according to
master XuanHua was poisoned six times
some of them were really famous Chinese monks
Indian monks his contemporaries and that's
comes with the job okay you you do something
important uh the uh your peers are your worst
enemies
okay uh and and that's the nature of the Chinese
competition they can't beat you they poison
you
I take it back uh not the Chinese and the
monks in general if they can't compete with
you they do things to uh destroy you to harm
you uh and that's the way it is okay yeah
you don't like it don't be patriarch stop
complaining uh so and and uh venerable Bodhidharma
also gave a prediction he says why am I doing
this I'm doing this not only to give this
to you this precious Dharma here
okay I do this because you are just
a vehicle just a bridge for
the propagation for the Dharma to be propagated
to future generations where there will be
the case one flower opens uh the five petals
um okay uh this refers to the fact in the
future that there is a a monk by the name
of MaZu well very famous very competent Chinese
patriarch who then had five eminent disciples
okay and from his uh that uh that learned
from him and later uh did great things for
the Chan school and for Mahayana in general
so venerable Bodhidharama says you know you make sure
that you pass on this knowledge because uh
there's a in the future you need this bloodline
this transmission to go to future generations
so that it will blossom eventually okay that's
the way it has to be in China back then Q&A
go ahead uh quick question master why did
Bodhidharma make venerable HuiKe kneel for
nine years before telling him to wait until
the snow turns red why not just tell him wait
at the very beginning wait until the snow
turns red yeah I could have said oh yeah yeah
oh yeah uh he could have said you
know in the future in nine years later there
is uh the Dharma will be transmitted somehow
so you hang in there right no it turns out
that uh I don't know because I cannot speak
for master Bodhidharma okay Bodhidharma
is is a great great sage from India okay so
uh and and and you can tell it's a great sage
because uh he went through a lot of hardship
and he he his hardship proved that great men
walked the difficult paths that's what makes
them great
it's never easy for these people okay so he
uh he he um he taught this Chinese guy who
did not sit in full lotus
okay so uh so this part of this nine years
here is to help him understand that in order
to become enlightened you must endure suffering
if you are not willing to endure suffering
you will not become enlightened
so if you know and and you can imagine do
you you think that HuiKe when he was great
master HuiKe when he was kneeling behind Bodhidharma
did he say oh ouch ouch out there's mosquito
here master master
okay it's raining can we stop can we can we
take a break I'm having a I have a cold today
I think it covid 17.
so you see they went through a lot you we
only see it as nine years actually they went
through so much okay so many things occur
that was not even worthy to be recorded and
the simple thing is just you kneel there for nine
years see if you can do that see how many
people can do that okay uh and and that's
what enabled HuiKe
to be ready for the transmission okay so according
to venerable Bodhidharma conditions were that that's
what he felt that HuiKe was has to go through
for for nine years basically the test is that
aren't you gonna give up every day aren't
you going to give up China's Chinese person
are you going to give up
and what did HuiKe have to work with
nothing
he has no fourty two hands and eyes
remember he's a dharma master he lectures
on sutras he doesn't know how to cultivate
didn't have any great compassion mantra
didn't have any Buddha's name to recite
have no Medicine Master Buddha blessings see
how weak you are you have all those things
HuiKe had nothing whatsoever
so what did he have how did he survive
you think
with Covid and you know SARS and you know
going around the country you know and hunger
and pain in the legs in the back aches
sleepiness
Q&A what do you have to work with Q&A
okay
master I think like the fact that
master HuiKe can kneel for nine years because
before that there was the ghost the impermanent
ghost came and then say that okay it's time
for you to die and then he was asking like
is there any way that I can get help or can
you wait for me and then they give him a tips
like the monk that you uh knock down two teeth
he's the one that already escaped birth and
death so HuiKe he has no other way to turn
so that that's why he has to kneel for nine
years to wait for Bodhidharma to teach him
and rescue him from the death and then the
patriarch YinGuang he also say that if you
want to be uh vigorous you just have to think
that the death is coming so that is one way
to help you to be vigorous and work hard and
then for me the price he has to pay to kneel
for nine years like uh because of the offenses
he beat up on the arhat and then just
nine years that is a very cheap uh light punishment
otherwise he will be fall into the um the
hell and stay there forever very good good
answer that's it yeah exactly in summary what's
this alternative if he quits what's going
to happen he dies so he has no choice but
to hang in there okay and so he uh he had
to somehow find a way to survive okay and
he cannot afford he cannot afford to quit
that's why so that's which brings to mind
uh a recently a disciple of mine she says
you know I got so much out of the chan Dharma door here it does wonders for me but I don't
know how I can uh share with my colleagues
I know they need it desperately but I don't
know how I can share it with them
okay and then I didn't say anything but the
answer is
what oh monk see if you can do it again
he was he relaxes oh I hit I hit the bull's
eye so I can relax no I came right back at
him no time to relax HuiKe who has to do
for nine years in a row you can't relax
caught red-handed
[Venerable XianChi speaking Vietnamese]
anyone else I knew it
anyone else hmm
yes Diego let's hear some south american wisdom
here
well thank you master uh I don't think
I'm just bragging It's just It's as if you
know you came from oh yeah from south america
somewhere bogota or yeah and you know calling
in and you know yes sorry yeah I'm from bogota
you got it right
thank you master, I don't think she has to do anything
because that would be like interfere with
them I feel she just have to teach by example
so when when they see that they are following
the precepts and and like their life has changed
so much they will naturally approach to her
ummmm anyone else
almost so it is almost so it is
anyone else how do you say in Chinese
差不多如是，差不多如是 anyone else yes sir four along the
lines Diego was saying just if if they improve
themselves eventually the people will ask
so when they ask that's when you can say something
um
anyone else what
conch
master he also had help from GuanYin and
the protectors around him and the Dharma protectors
did you dye your hair sorry what were you
saying
master he he also had um no about the hair
no sir
what kind of question is that right okay never
mind what what's your answer again sorry the
hair distracted me one day's flaming the others
black I mean it's confusing
he he had the emergency help from Guanyin
and the the dharma the Dharma protectors don't
you wish okay anyone else
Q&A
master uh I think she needs to wait till they
have the need
to learn Chan umm so proud of you it's not something
southern California people can answer
the wisdom seems to have migrated up north
excellent very good hmm excellent
see I trick you I said uh I said uh she saw
the need their needs to do it but the key
is do they see the need or not she she forgot
about herself she saw the need that's why
she did the Chan thing but unless people
see the needs they have real needs like HuiKe
here they won't do it there's no point in
forcing the issue you have to wait until they
see the need that's all okay and guess what
they eventually will see the needs all you
have to do is make yourself available you
know until then you make yourself available
my door is open you know my cubicle is open
you know
let's have a cup of tea next month you know
whatever you know but just make yourself available
that's all so that when they have the need
they'll come and ask you point number one
point number two like the south American wisdom
okay uh you don't do anything Chan is that we don't
scheme conch listen carefully we don't scheme
we don't have to scheme we don't have to sell
anything it's there and when they need it
they'll ask
okay so yes because they see people will see
and when you all you have to do is continue
to improve become better happier uh healthier
what -ier can we do
okay and then they see themselves and say
oh I need to be like that you see that so
that's a very subtle way the south American
way to make it very subtle to to to create
a need a little bit quicker by
look at me all right very good so one day
Bodhidharma called together the disciples
and said it's time has come for me
to return each of you say something to demonstrate
your understanding so this is uh seems to
start this silly thing that Chinese do you
know after you go to ChanQi they have an
exit interview and said give me your 心得
what is that you have in what insight did
you have
and that's what happened so I think Bodhidharma
is the one who started it all to mess up all
the chinese so now all the chinese do that
now you go to a Chinese Qi and you is not
a real Qi unless when you finish you go through
exit interview and say what is that you what
is your understanding and they have to say
something okay and say 如是如是 everyone
says 如是如是 so it is so it is and then
they remain who they are okay so anyway say
something to demonstrate your understanding
this by the way is a trick question it's not
meant for them to imitate venerable Bodhidharma
said this to it's like a jab do you box it's
a left jab
see say something
you got that a disciple named DaoFu said
as I see it function of the way is the function
of the way is not bound by word speech nor
is it separate from words and speech very
profound
shall we continue is it more you have attained
my skin
we continue first before I comment okay can
we do that is that okay I know you say say
something master say something master I said
no no that wait a little bit okay
the nun ZongChi said according to my understanding it is like
Ananda's glimpse of the realm of Akshobhya
Buddha seen once it is never seen again Bodhidharma
said you have attained my flesh
a disciple named DaoYu four elements are all
empty the five skandas are without actual
existence I see that there is not a single
dharma to be grasped and we should have the
Chinese for this it annoys me when I don't
see Chinese in these translations because
I don't trust their translations at all okay
these people the Chinese translators don't
really understand Chan that's why I don't
trust any of them
okay in the future if you uh if you are you
people are preparing you notice for example
people have been working very hard preparing
like Korean here Vietnamese here Chinese here
okay so you know when you prepare can you
make sure that I have the Chinese version
here and they say oh my god master you're
asking about the impossible where am I going
to fit it I don't care
not my problem I just want Chinese somewhere
is it too much to ask stop complaining it
hurts too much nine years and not reasonable
okay so anyway and master Bodhidharma said
you obtained my bones okay finally without
saying HuiKe bowed and stood in his place
Bodhidharma said you have attained my marrow
precisely ah I forgot about this thing here
okay 48 going back to these four characters
yeah yeah you see he's going like this the
boy is having a good time [Music] uh I'm glad
to see some people are enjoying the lecture
so DaoFu said as I see it the functional way
is not bound by words and speech nor is it
separate from words and speech old monk what
do you have to say
Very good! next! [Venerable XianChi begins to speak Vietnamese] I help you already, shut up
if he's not bound by words and speech nor
it's not separate from words and speech why
does he have to open his mouth
however this is correct therefore his understanding
is superficial my skin skin deep this wisdom
here is a wisdom of enlightened person but
it is only skin deep
next ZongChi, Chi, ZongChi
hey by the way someone asked me can a woman
be enlightened
it's proof right here since Bodhidharma yes
before we don't know
maybe only Chinese women can be enlightened
we don't know
how about American women can they come and
become enlightened well we'll find out
so ZongChi said according to my understanding
see I love to see the Chinese here would the
Chinese start with according my understanding
why do you even have to say that
whatever she says doesn't it come from her
understanding or is it is he stealing from
from the old monk
superfluous
so clearly these first two here have a lot
of free time to kill
uh according to my understanding
you know this is when you know us people who
work in real have real-life jobs say you're wasting
my time uh you're not getting that raise okay
it is like Ananda's glimpse of the realm
of Akshobhya Buddha seen once is never seen
again uh so apparently there has a little
bit deeper wisdom I don't know why okay anyone
understands why it's deeper than skin hmm
why
good lord you don't get it
anyone please don't embarrass me
please say something meaningful the Chinese
are watching
it's all these guys been boasting saying we're
better than us the Americans are better than
us let's see how good they are say something
smart anyone please Korea
China I don't care
the Korean look at them
statues
they all look down too
it's a new style for statues you know you
know they're all from Korea when they go like
this Buddha statues are like this but no Korean
is a so when they become enlighten these people
in the future
anyone else
why is it deeper
why is a high level wisdom
please I beg you
yeah I'm desperate yeah go ahead and say anything
I don't care we might hit like you might get
lucky I think I remember what master said
the first time around no I never said anything
about it about this I thought you said that
something about it's just total nonsense so
she knows that it's that there's nothing to
be said because she just says nonsense boy
was I wrong did you believe that ah god I'm
glad we're redoing this because I'd be so
embarrassed if I hear anyone talk like that
oh good lord anyone else Catholic man
he's saying say I'm here to learn Buddhism
you know I don't want to watch these Buddhists
make a fool of themselves speak nonsense what
is this
here's a difference this guy still remembers
being bound by something yes this woman here
Chinese woman
does she remember anything
nothing sticks in her mind
this my guy here is still stuck on words and
speech and no words in speech this woman here
says I I saw the state of enlightenment I don't
remember a darn thing
nothing sticks
that's true emptiness nothing whatsoever
you like that same thing all the Koreans are
you like it better XianJie you like it better
very good he likes it better
okay she's high level she says
what am I supposed to understand I don't remember
there's nothing here nothing worth remembering
can you see that
well anyway and someday you understand next
has his flesh okay so skin flesh next
DaoYu, education of the way okay which is a reminder
we need to educate people okay your children
in particular have to educate them about the way
he said see he's better already according to
my understanding he dropped it see that right
there is
improvement okay he says the four elements
are all empty okay the five skandhas are without
actual existence and I I can can someone give
me the Chinese please I don't dare touch this
unless I see the Chinese this is tricky
reload
q&a while they're reloading let's talk to
that shoot the breeze
okay remember before you say anything you
have to uh maintain the standard the wisdom
that I just elevated all of you to
see they all yeah of course
so American and the China and the Koreans
would but look at the Americans of course
yes go ahead this is just quoting the DaoYu's
words 四大本空，五陰非有，而我見處，無一法可得
okay very good let me see
水火風本來是空的，眼耳鼻舌根也非實的，整個世界無一法可得 um um umm umm
okay
four elements are all empty
he didn't mention five skandhas okay this
is incorrect translation you see there's no
word skandhas here
the the version that Qun found, it says 四大本空，五陰非有，而我見處，無一法可得, I think the chinese here is more the 白話文. more the. ok very good. 五陰皆什麼？五陰非有 that's more Chan!
who did this Chinese thing here has to be
can we know this person here does this person
have a name
huh I'm not sure who did it maybe Jane okay
I'm not sure okay uh uh
it's not Jane someone was just adding it right now
so we can't kill this person
okay
okay very good mm-hmm yeah please don't do
the 白話 anymore okay give me the the
actual the actual original text I'm not interested
interested in the 白話 at all can you reload it again
they changed it
I'm sure the non-Chinese people are so bored
and just give it to me anyway no you can't
give it to you yeah you have to make sure
that we learn from the Chinese wisdom first
okay let's see what Chinese wisdom what's
the level of Chinese wisdom they have here
okay so uh oh this is 簡體 oh good lord
this is mainland China person 四大本空，五陰非有，而我見處，無一法可得
okay of course I knew that this is a 見 character
I'm not that dumb
I just it's justified myself
you know so
okay
okay very good okay uh so here's what it means
the four elements are all empty meaning there's
uh there's nothing to make up this world okay
this world here as we see is made up of the
four elements okay you name anything it's
solid it's made of you know the four elements
our body is made of four elements this uh
this uh beautiful uh uh uh halloween thing
is made up of four elements okay four elements
are wood uh water what else fire and wind
okay okay so the four elements are empty so
the wood is empty the water is empty the wind's
empty everything is empty okay because they're
empty therefore everything is that they they
that that's made up of these four elements
are empty so every are all empty so all is
empty five skandhas without actual existance
meaning there's no one there's no ego so outside
there's no world inside there's no me so
far so good
而我見處 but as I see it 無一法可得
can be
obtain not 得 grasp here is obtained okay
that's why this this this uh translation is
off uh
as I see you know as I see it there
isn't a single dharma to be attained
so far so good
the four elements are fundamentally empty
not all
this is easy really this is simplified character
again right oh these Chinese people have a
way of of of uh throwing me off
okay 五陰非有 the five skandhas
don't exist
that's the Chan terminology you want to simplify
to make it punchy like when you want to punch
someone you want to go as fast as quickly
as possible you don't say
okay you guys don't box at all clearly neither
do I uh anyway so the five skandhas don't exist
as I see it
there is isn't a single dharma to be attained
this is more interesting than the prior two
prior two are amateurs okay this one is pretty
good why
what he's seeing he says that
I know that the outside world is empty inside
is also empty okay but but I know as I see
it meaning I know okay 見 is that I know that
there isn't a single dharma to be obtained
okay so he has this profound emptiness understanding
correction it was 五陰非有 not 五蘊, 五陰, 陰陽的陰
no no 陰 that 陰 is also skandhas the
skandhas has two words 五蘊 or 五陰
okay they both are referred to skandhas depending
on which translation version but they all
refer to 陰 here is skandhas not the 姻緣的姻
okay
this is a comment from Taiwan people don't
trust them
I can't trust the mainland China people I
can't trust Taiwanese people what's happening
in our world
okay so far so good so what does it mean he
says outside is empty inside is empty actually
if you ask me of the entire universe there
isn't a thing
so he his vision is what and then the great
master says you attain my bones so it's deeper
so this is a deeper level wisdom why is it
deeper deeper because
the Koreans are going like this again okay
I won't ask you don't worry relax relax Koreans
anyone else oh Korean here number six I think
what he mentioned is something similar from
the Vajra sutra it's maybe it's a Vajra wiz
wisdom
they all have prajna wisdom oh okay prajna
wisdom of wisdom you know it's all prajna
wisdom but it's the prajna wisdom has different
levels of depth okay so why is it deeper here
six uh because uh this person here has a deeper
understanding of emptiness
XianJie are you checking my old notes
check my old notes please say can you please check
my own notes see what did I say I don't want
to contradict myself
go ahead q&a it's too embarrassing why would
I contradict myself oh wow how stupid a comment
that is
it's self-defeating
[Venerable XianChi speaking Vietnamese]
no keep going keep going
translation and then he'll continue
so master before we go into comparison or
whatever first of all we need to understand
the term of the words what does that mean
so Buddha is mean like awareness anybody uh
sentient being all have this type of awareness
so if you pay attention you will see that
in your mind like there will be one thought
arise and then it will disappear and then
the second thought arises and then it will
disappear but like between the two thoughts
there will be an empty space and
that
empty space is called um uh 如來
如來 thus come one so everybody all
all have it and then but because we didn't
aware of it and then we keep chasing after
something else that's why it caused the affliction
and then in the great compassion repentance
in page 49 the verse is also that we and the
Buddha all also have that but because it was
covering up so that's why we didn't aware
of it and uh so for the first two they still
see like there's an emptiness there is a person
that attends a person there's nothing to attend
or whatever so it's similar to the blue sky
then it still have a flashing light in the
sky but then ultimately there's nothing
for you to to see and then if you can maintain
that emptiness it will be the same day and
night that is the thus thus unmoving the
thus come one and then uh if you pay
attention to it all of us have it continue
[Venerable XianChi speak Vietnamese]
okay we're going to stop now so the the third
person she also see it but then she still
used the um the false thinking and then she
still used the words to express it so basically
she's still not uh truly entered
that
[Venerable XianChi and Master speak in Vietnamese]
know your limitations
you are in no position to comment about master
XuanHua nor master XuYun
translate that vietnamese part where I I yelled
at him I scolded him
so master like for example in the um the morning
ceremony then and the three refugees and then
there is a part that we say we vow that uh
all living beings will understand
the great way profoundly and bring forth the
bodhi mind so uh this is similar to to that
emptiness and then like um you know like when
master XuanHua see that Master XuYun and the master XuYun
say like uh you are like that and I'm like
that
go ahead q&a
it's okay
okay
you have to know your limitations meaning
that the reason I bring mentions one of the
reasons why I mention certain people's levels
and so forth is to tell you that if when they're
higher than you do not touch them because
you don't know their state don't make that
mistake okay he said it's a state of wisdom
that I don't understand it's a proper comment
you don't say is that's what he means what
how what do you know what he means you're
no position to comment okay say so all right
why is it higher
I give you a very simple explanation okay
this is a high level wisdom because see go
back to go back to the first two first one
says
words and speech are meaningless so he says
there is no words no no speech as the Chan school advocates
okay
言語道斷 the pathways of words and speech
are terminated is terminated so he understands
that good uh but he still use words and speech
okay number two nun says I don't remember
very good whatever I saw I don't remember
whatever you taught me I don't remember excellent
the third guy here is go beyond goes beyond
that he says
I see
this emptiness here is huge there's nothing
there
okay it's like it's higher I use the word
high high-level wisdom it's like you go into
a high-rise building when you're low level
you can see only your neighbor's house when
you go to the tower you can see further you
can see tennis courts you can see you can
see the freeway you can see all those things
you understand so the division is broader
that's why it says the four elements meaning
how this world is is composed is made of it's
all empty that's how I see the entire my vision
is of the entire world so my realm is bigger
than the other two that's why it's higher
he can see further than the other two they
the other two can see emptiness but they cannot
see as far as this guy that's why venerable Bodhidharma
says you got my bones that's pretty good
does it help the Chinese avoid explaining
this okay because now you're touching you
know these people who are you are you know
who knows what level they are and you know
and and uh venerable Bodhidharma you know what he
did he teach them what dharma did he teach them
we don't know so so whatever I told you take
a grain of salt which is for fun only to make
fun of the Chinese that's all and the Indians
all right and finally HuiKe he bowed and stood
in his place you obtained my marrow Bodhidharma
says
okay HuiKe's level is highest okay that's
why now is one of the reasons why you understand
that venerable Bodhidharma made him kneel for
nine years because those nine years prepared
him to have a deeper understanding than sitting
in full lotus
now you see there's a proof right there level
the level of HuiKe is very very high
okay meaning that venerable Bodhidharama's level
is extremely extremely high much higher than
HuiKe
there's what because the level of understand
HuiKe is is incredible
okay and that's why venerable Bodhidharma
said this is as deep as my dharma can go
this is as deep as my dharma can penetrate
you
that's a very high compliment
okay this is how Chan people compliment their
students you don't say oh you're such a wonderful
student you're so so why you're so smart you're
so handsome no you're my bone marrow
yeah southerner no do you have a question
in conch you see XianAn is sleeping he's uh
I don't know what they're talking about it's
too much for me go ahead conch I bet you he
dyed his hair I don't believe him
different lighting in JMT no no no no
master when you said you have my bones you have my marrow what does that mean like I am you what what do we say well liar liar
or whatever what what is that that yeah liar liar
pants on fire
translate that into Korean
Chinese see if you can translate that into
Chinese
liar liar pants on fire
I see they don't get it only Americans get
it okay go ahead sorry uh fire hair
yes is it working yeah master when he said
when he said um you have my bones and you
have my marrow what does that mean like I
am you I'm the same as you no no no it's not
the same he says it refers to skin deep wisdom
muscle deep wisdom bone deep wisdom and inside
the bone that's it that's the deepest
okay and that's amazing because because uh
because by the time Bodhidharma left HuiKe
attained a very very high level and what's
amazing is that he didn't have a lot of disciples
after that that's what's surprising to me
at his level he should have a lot of eminent
disciples
okay
but he didn't that's what is baffling to me
now I look at this and says how come he didn't
have a lot more eminent disciples like the
sixth patriarch why not I mean you know he
at that level he's an incredible teacher let
me assure you I feel he's most incredible teacher
and yet his disciples weren't there meaning
that maybe the Chinese you know weren't available
or something we don't know but to me it's
amazing that venerable Bodhidharma transmitted
his knowledge to HuiKe and and we're very
very lucky that venerable HuiKe's level is extremely
high and that's why uh that's why the knowledge
uh to me that's that that's a kind of proof
that the great dharma was transmitted to China
back then it's for real
okay and what I don't understand again is
that how come at that level he didn't have
that many more disciples so that Buddhism
in China would prosper a lot quicker I don't
understand that that's amazing number nine
this is from Jane liar liar pants on fire
in chinese is translated into 騙子騙子褲子著火 [Laughter] I like that translation
the pants on fire yeah okay very good Korean
translation how did we do in Korean translation
hey Korean translator uh speak it out so that
we can correct you
say it loud we're double checking the Korean
translator
very good yeah
this woman here is so hard to get any word
out of her
see still
master do you hear me no I can't hear you
I don't know how to translate it
okay never mind okay so it's very good so
this is this is so fantastic that that uh
that um that when venerable HuiKe uh attained really
attained the sudden teaching dharma from
venerable Bodhidharma on 53 Bodhidharma recited
the this poem originally I came to this land
to rescue the deluded by transmitted dharma
one flower will open in five petals with five
petals and the fruit will ripen by itself
吾本來茲土，傳法救迷情，一花開五葉，結果自然成. so venerable Bodhidharma recited this poem
not sure whether it's Chinese or or or in
Sanskrit or whatever but he says I he got
I think he got he got a little bit emotional
he says original I came to this land looking
back I came to this land, what for to rescue
the deluded by transmitting the dharma to
rescue all these deluded Chinese people okay
and I transmit the dharma to my successor
and in the future one flower will open with
five petals okay so five beautiful uh manifestations
uh five beautiful components of the great
Chan dharma the five schools maybe and the fruit
will ripen by itself okay and meaning what
what does it mean the fruit by ripening itself
Chinese people Indian people we don't have
any Indian people do we
no Indian people
hmm we should be more open-minded and welcome
more Indians uh what does it mean the fruit
will be we or will be ripen by itself
yes Diego
seven uh maybe I think it's that the patriarch
will get like in a higher level just by itself
without the necessity of a master at that
time
yeah close enough yes six
eventually the transmission of dharma will
be successfully um given to the Chinese yeah
okay basically he says my job is done
you guys just uh I don't know where you're
from but it's so clear to me I'm done here
I'm out of here isn't that we Americans do
I say I'm done hallelujah free at last free
at last thank god I'm free at last huh
because he's like remember he sat there for
nine years is he gonna leave or what
HuiKe refused to leave for nine years so
finally I'm done the fruit will ripen by itself
there's no need for for me to do anything
anymore because it takes it will take care
of itself
okay I'm done I'm out of here but the Indians
don't speak like we do
all right
fifty-four three years after Bodhidharma's
death ambassador SongYun of northern Wei
is said to have seen him walking while holding
a shoe at premier heights somewhere in India
I guess okay so he saw Bodhidharma it could
be real could be a vision we don't know SongYun
asked Bodhidharma where he was going
to which Bodhidharma replied I'm going home
so apparently some kind of ambassador saw
him between the borders the border region
this area here between India and China so
yes where are you going you went to China
or India so he says I'm going home okay and
55 and why you're holding your shoes
Bodhidharma says you will know when you reach Shaolin
monastery don't mention you saw me or you will
meet with disaster and after arriving at palace
soon told him emperor he met Bodhidharma on
the way [Laughter] don't trust Chinese people
emperors said Bodhidharma is already dead
and buried and SongYun arrested for lying [Laughter]
serves him right [Laughter] sorry
I told you I have no compassion whatsoever
even for historical personalities yes sir
number seven so I I imagine that in the future
when the master is done he will be seen walking
in the Bahamas [Laughter] what a prediction
praise the lord
and at Shaolin monastery monks informed them
that Bodhidharma was dead had been buried
buried in a hill behind the temple okay
and the monks then said master has gone back
home and prostrated three times for nine years
he had remained and nobody knew him carrying
a shoe in hand he went home quietly without
ceremony
okay probably some kind of verse here okay
uh anyway it's Chinese monk so who cares what
they say okay uh and this is Bodhidharma being
depressed and said when is he gonna leave
me alone
and you see how he did not even sit in full
lotus he says I'm not teaching him nothing
I hope he leaves soon but he refuses to leave
and the the skull is interesting to me anyway
uh 59 second patriarch okay HuiKe was born
to family of Taoist scholars in what is now
Henan province china about 60 miles east
of Luoyang and that's a capital and a bit north
of the sacred mountain of SongShan
a sacred mountain SongShan that's uh I don't
know probably Shaolin temple when he was born
his parents saw WeiTuo Bodhisattva golden armored spiritual
protector come to offer protection not offer
protection came and stand in guard I don't
know who made this translation here it's not
offer protection WeiTuo came and stood in guard
okay there upon in 60 they named their son ShenGuang
which means spiritual light and that's from
WeiTuo Bodhisattva's light not only was a patriarch
intelligent but he has an excellent memory
as well and his skills and power of discrimination
was so remarkable that he could read 10 lines
in the time it took an ordinary person to
read one okay you have these strange traits
manifestations okay of of remarkable individuals
61 in a gathering 100 people all talking at
once he could clearly distinguish each conversation
that's impressive that's a very high processing
power is that would you say it's like a tensor
chip or m1 or m2x or whatever in today's power
no oh you don't keep up with iphones and uh
pixel
ummm boring
however had great anger he disagreed with
everyone was always ready to fight asura
okay
as a young man HuiKe also studied Confucianism
along with Taoism so this is a erudite he
is well read very good because when you want
to teach you need to have comparative things
we teach worldly people you need to know where
they're coming from and back then the worldly
wisdom is being consists of Confucianism
and Taoism there was the highest level of
wisdom in china back then so he had to prepare
himself now you're listening boys and girls
you want to teach later you have to learn
about worldly wisdom okay eventually not yet
give yourself time I'm not dead yet
the deaths of his parents cause HuiKe to turn
to Buddhism why could not find the answer
okay Buddhism has very profound insights into
death that the other doctrines do not
all right so at in 519 when he was 32 years
old he became a Buddhist monk in a temple
near Luoyang ancient capital about eight years
later he left in search of Bodhidharma so he
became a monk okay and he was well read well
educated person and of course he read a lot
of Buddhist scriptures okay and wasn't long
before he was able to lecture on Buddhist
scriptures see back then
important point they did not have Chan at
all that is why it was considered back then
that Mahayana was not quite in China yet
okay in other words Mahayana needs the backbone
of
Chan that's why Bodhidharma had to come to
China in order to transmit specifically this
dharma door called Chan okay so that's why
even though you could lecture it's basically
scholarly stuff
all due respect to the scholars they put a
lot of work blood and sweat into their acquisition
of Buddhist knowledge but the knowledge is
hair pore deep not even skin yet hasn't penetrated
the world of wisdom yet so far so good
and so uh 32 years he became a monk and eight
years later so this guy is very very sharp
he decided to
follow
great master Bodhidharma okay and he was about
40 years old okay so he started the age of
40. wow there's hope for you after all huh
most of you are like in your 40s aren't you
and the girl said yeah yeah that's me
no you're not 40. don't laugh you must be
around close to 60 I would say
60 uh he obeyed his teacher and went to hiding
for 40 years oh wow so 40 to 49 okay and then
he studied under Bodhidharma for some more
years so let's say five six years okay so
it's 54 55 and then went to hiding for 40
years so he's about 100 years oh wow that's
too much no so clearly my master Bodhidharma
didn't teach him much okay because when he
was 80 he began to propagate the Buddha dharma
okay meaning that he hid for 40 years he he
uh he um he was around 40 when he became enlightened
okay
you know when he started so 40 49 years when
are you how can the math doesn't add up i
don't I don't get it this doesn't add up it's
a chinese arithmetic for us it doesn't add
up okay but anyway let's not worry about this
you know this detail it's not that important
okay whether it's 100 years or 200 years who
cares okay and he started at 80 years old
he began to propagate the Buddha dharma teaching
and transforming living beings while 80 years
old that's impressive 80 years let's see probably
had to use a cane q&a
Emituofo master in the history saying that
the Bodhidharma
went to China in the in the um fifth and between
the fifth and the sixth century 502 to about
550 something but then the XuanZang dharma
master who went to India to get Buddhism or
to get Buddhist texts to translate in the
early 600s meaning only 50 years after Bodhidharma
so so meaning after Bodhidharma passed away
the the Chan sect is not really uh
popular yet no
until like six patriarch in order
yes it's not until the fourth and fifth patriarch that's when it used to have thousands of people
cultivating oh I see okay yeah thank you back
then there weren't a lot of people okay I
weren't a lot of people who were willing to
kneel for nine years
okay
all right uh later disciples of Bodhiruci
another famous eminent monk back then and
Vinaya master Kuang Tung tried to kill him
he who and so he feigns insanity to uh to
uh uh to fool them but he never ceases
to save living beings who were ready to receive
his teaching okay patriarchs uh when you hear
these stories who would want to be a patriarch
it's a lot of work a lot of grief and no reward
okay
62 that's his parents oh why did I go back
sorry
uh
64. thank you about 534 northern Wei dynasty
they had rural northern China collapsed under
the weight of riots and revolts and northern
China was split into two kingdoms new dynasties
dynasties seized power and soon met with violent
ends from to 557-581 much northern China not
California was ruled by the northern Zhou
dynasty
all right 65 the northern Zhou emperor Wu who were persuaded
that Buddhism has become too powerful and
in 574 and 577 he attempted to abolish Buddhism
in his kingdom and the patriarch HuiKe had
to flee south he found a hiding place in mountains
of southern AnHui province near the Yangtze
river
well it's yeah it's a lot of hardship now
you know why there weren't a lot of followers
because he's running for his life and hiding
most of the time uh 66 according to the scholars
today on a mountain name uh how why how come
the two "s" Sukungshan there's a stone platform
on which uh it is said that HuiKe lectured and
the boulder it is said that marked a place where
Huike pass bodhidharma's robe and bowl the successor SengCan
SengCān cán or càn, càn càn càn càn càn
in time a very elderly HuiKe returned to north
China he told his students he had to repay
a karmic debt a day 199 593 a famous monk
named him called him of heresy accused him
of heresy not name him okay accuse him of
a heresy the emperor ordered the district
magistrate to arrest him and the patriarch
was locked up and questioned are you human
are you a freak asked the magistrate I'm a freak
replied HuiKe magistrate knew the patriarch
said this to avoid causing jealousy so he ordered him to tell the truth speak
clearly what are you uh I am a freak replied HuiKe
the Buddha dharma will not flourish until the
time of forth patriarch he announced then he was
executed he cut his head off instead of blood
a white milky uh milky white liquid flowed
into the chopping block must eat a lot of
this white cheese thing the emperor knew they
had executed a sage because you remember the
24th indian patriarch Aryasimha had also
been beheaded and had not bled but white milky
liquid had poured forth because he had been
without outflows when no one has ignorance
one may attain may attend to a state without
outflows they enter the white Yang realm so
the blood becomes white wow that's too much
so can you imagine go to Kaiser hospital
and try to give blood
uh you go ahead seven master is your blood
red or white my blood is red hot
because of the anger issues
71 realizing he was a bodhisattva in the flesh
emperor felt great shame a bodhisattva had came to
our country he said and instead of offering
him protection we killed him excuse me
and the emperor had all the great officials
take refuge with this strange Bhikshu political
thing you know a real politician you know
this is great sage let's all take refuge
with him even though he's dead
and the name they gave themselves their own
dharma names
letter to student by Dr. Suzuki translation you
have truly comprehended the dharma as it is
the deepest truth lies oh my god I want I
need chinese I need chinese oh yeah yeah these
people are not qualified to translate uh Chan
texts but that's see what else see
if you can find it please anyway I can't understand
when it's more than one sentence
I struggle it is due to one's ignorance that
the mani-jewel is taken from piece of brick for
a piece of brick but when one is suddenly
awakened to self-enlightenment is realize
that one is in possession or real jewel oh
yeah yeah yeah what a boring stuff I'd rather
have some cold noodles than reading this the
ignorant and the enlighted are of one essence they are
not really to be separated who asks you to
be separate oh god lord I mean it says they
contradict themselves they want essence they
are not really to be separated who asks you
we should know that all things are such as
they are who cares
tell me how to get rich
those no no no actually it doesn't sound right
tell me how to get a bigger temple those who
entertain a dualistic view of the world are
to be pitied that I write this letter for them
who's this HuiKe okay he came from saying
nothing to being very verbose
what happened old age he lost his marbles
I write this letter for them when I know that
between this body and the Buddha there is
nothing to separate one from the other what
is the use of seeking after nirvana something
is turning ourselves it's too verbose like
the old monk here our old monk
okay any questions about venerable Huike he's
an extraordinary individual I'm I'm so I'm
I'm so happy that we discovered that is his
uh it's uh he's uh he he got a lot from venerable Bodhidharma's
teaching and so that's why Chinese Buddhism
was in good hands when Bodhidharma left now
you understand why Bodhidharma left
because he knew that he's no longer needed
you understand they don't waste time they
stick around only because they are needed they're
not needed they go home
all right questions comments
we are
learning about this to appreciate the depth
of Chinese Buddhism it started with the second
Chinese patriarch HuiKe okay very very impressive
Chinese monk okay uh what happened
oh in simplified again oh my god you guys
are just want the end of me
the student is not very bright is he that's
why it's so verbose okay not interest not interested
in this letter at all sorry yeah next a few
more minutes any questions uh all right let's
see what kind of patriarch venerable SengCàn cān or cán cān.
SengCàn SengCàn
okay
look at him
love the nose
what do you call the kind of nose you physionomist
Chinese physiologist is that a good nose or
a bad nose nevermind 77 little known about
him transmission of the lamp the records there produced
in a song dynasty by uh 釋道原
author of famous Chan poem
信心銘 okay inscription on the mind of faith okay
so
not much okay but he produces Chan poem called
信心銘 okay and uh and uh inscription
on the mind of faith uh that's he composed
that when he first came to visit the second
second patriarch his body is recovered with repulsive
sore like those are a leper oh yuk where
are you from asked the second patriarch what are
you doing here
I have come to take refuge to the high master
and study and cultivate the Buddha Dharma
answers SengCan you have loathsome disease
and your body is filthy how can you study
the Buddha Dharma 79 SengCan said I'm a sick
man you are a high master he said but in our
true minds where is the difference there upon
the second patriarch transmitted a dharma to
him saying this rope and bowl have been passed
on from Bodhidharma they certify that you
have received the dharma seal
that's all the training no nine years [Laughter]
what's going on this simplified too much I'm
worried now about the third generation
is it for real really that's it
so easy that way I want to become
a patriarch too in order to protect it you
must go into hiding because Bodhiruchi's followers
will try to harm you be very careful and let
no one know that you have received transmission
SengCan asked HuiKe saying I'm diseased I implore
you to cleanse me of my offenses
what did he do 81 HuiKe says said bring me
your offense I will cleanse it for you
i cleanse you of it oh yeah yeah
cleanse you of it
it's gotta be Chinglish
SengCan thought for a while and said I
cannot get at
it
覓罪不可得 close enough, that's okay
HuiKe replied then I have cleansed uh you of it should
live by the Buddha dharma and sangha okay
well that's a nice way of cleansing the all
the illnesses let's try that sometimes
83 I can see you as a monk a member of the
Buddhist community what are the Buddha and
the teaching all of a sudden now there is Chinese I'm confused
84. this mind is Buddha this mind is a teaching
the teaching and Buddha are not separate this
is also true of the sangha not the community
oh good lord change it to sangha okay 是心是佛， 是心是法
法佛無二，僧寶亦然
huh the Dharma is not teaching the mind is
the Dharma the Dharma Dharma and Buddha are
not two don't say separate two
and the sangha jewel so is a sangha jewel
okay anyway it doesn't matter it's not a Chan thing
so who cares
okay it doesn't do much for the people who
read it okay it's not meant as instruction
for you to become enlightened so who cares
okay why waste time on this
okay did you fix it okay there you go very
fast very good 85. today for the first time
I have realized that the essence of offense
is not inside not outside not in between so
it is also a mind
the Buddha and teaching are not separate either
who is he teaching against sorry I forgot
how can HuiKe reply
oh yeah HuiKe to SengCan so SengCan said so I cleanse it for you
okay fine and then I see you monk okay uh
what are the Buddha and the sangha okay and
uh this mind Buddha is mind is Dharma and
the Dharma Buddha are not two so is a sangha
jewel very good for the first time you realize
essence of offense are and the Dharma are uh
um 佛法無也
there's no Buddha there's no Dharma
what is it Buddha and the teaching as separate
either oh good lord the Chinese says Buddha
Dharma no osi I mean two
oc french excuse me
I heard that Abba broke up again I know it
broke my heart I was looking forward to their
new album they have you know I'm an Abba fan
dancing queen [Music]
clark can I enjoy music thank you yeah I said
yeah yeah because Clark is giggling at
me oh god he looks so ridiculous
okay so and HuiKe saw profound understanding
shaved his head SengCan cultivated under the
second patriarch his illness gradually improved
that's what happens when you're sick you became
a monk and you know good things happen okay
and that's natural by the way if it doesn't
happen you don't improve uh change temples
HuiKe gave robe and bowl two years later wow
only two years what's with these people I
think it's fake
it's too easy
no seriously
they make us look bad
the Chinese beat us again [Laughter] he gave
SengCan instruction not to teach publicly
because of impending danger uh predicted by
27th patriarch uh Prajnatara uh third patriarch feigned
insanity while he taught living beings
okay they all have to pretend to be crazy
okay uh not to draw attention to themselves
87 during persecution Buddhism by emperor
Wu northern Zhou dynasty the patriarch fled into
mountains while hid there tigers wolves
leopards fierce animals all disappeared he
ate them all
wondered mountains for 10 years with no fixed abode
Hinayana practice
okay 88 he met 道信 that's the fourth
patriarch a novice monk of just 14 in 592 592.
道信 attended 僧璨 (SengCan) uh attended to SengCan
for nine years received dharma transmission when
he was still in his early 20s oh my god the
Chinese beat us again
after transmitting dharma to the fourth patriarch 道信
master SengCan invited 1 000 Bhikshu to great vegetarian
feast who is no longer crazy or something
after they have eaten he said you think that
to sit in full lotus is the best way to die
watch I demonstrate my mastery over birth
and death showing off before he die he left
a dining hall followed by the thousand Bhikshu
can you imagine these Chinese are something else
he halted by the trunk of a tree
and after pausing for a moment for you know
like before you enter the stage you take a
pause
hello there
uh he lept up and grabbed a big branch and
while swinging from tree from the tree by
one hand he entered nirvana I mean he croaked
okay and enter nirvana is the Chinese or something
else he just died oh he's not he didn't enter
nirvana how do they know seriously how would
you know he entered nirvana or not oh and
the Chinese are encourageable
ninety uh first Chan poem in China was composed
by him the 信心銘 okay first Chan poem
ever in China interesting song of enlightenment
and so on later was uh composed by the seventh
patriarch 永嘉 which we will you know explain in our
Chan class because otherwise I'm running
out of time to discuss these scriptures is
it okay Korean during a Chan class dharma
talk we can spend a little bit of time
talking about the song of enlightenment because
the Chinese said oh this is a Chinese you
know Chinese masterpiece that we will take it to
pieces okay we shred it dissect it okay open
it up okay uh and with something called
um 參同契
there's no English translation that's why
it's no English title was composed by 石頭
another uh peer of master 馬祖 and then another
one poem composed called 寶鏡三昧歌
the jewel mirror
samadhi
song okay and then there's more okay
this is the extent of my Chinese okay next
91 oh time is up
thank you everyone