oh
me
happy
from outside
uh
hey oh my god
bye
um
oh yeah
we respectfully request and the song of great
virtues for the sake of this assembly and
all living beings please turn the wonderful
diamond will to teach and guide us how to
end birth and death leave suffering and attain
bliss and quickly realize non-birth [Music]
video
[Music]
you
how much the blessed noble and perfectly enlightened
one
amo
foreign
the unsurpassed profound subtle and wonderful
dharma in a hundred thousand million eons
is difficult to encounter now that I am able
to see and hear I will receive and maintain
it I vow to fathom the thus come once through
an actual principles ooh
[Music]
[Music] oh
[Music] we
[Music]
all good monks and nuns and all good knowing advisers
amituofo
諸佛菩薩，六祖師傅上人，
各位出家人，各位善知識阿彌陀佛
hello everyone today is the 6th of August
2022. thank you all for joining us in this
explanation of the sixth patriarch sutra we are
currently in chapter 2 uh slide 180. chapter
2 is teaching us about this wisdom
from enlightenment that is um and this is
the kind of wisdom that you have already and
you don't know how to use it okay you lost
track of it because of your incessant revolution
in the wheel of reincarnation every time we have
a new body we get a little bit further away
from this this great wisdom of ours so that's
why it's like it has so many layers that we
can no longer recognize it we can no longer
know how to access it so the Buddhism is about
the way for you to recognize what you have
recognize the treasure in your mind and know
how to use it okay and so sixth sixth patriarch
is one of the best teachers in Chinese Buddhism
and he's really the foremost teacher on sudden
enlightenment on sudden teaching sudden
teachings is a kind of teaching that will
enable you to straight away reach enlightenment
easier said than done but at least the kind
of technology is available for everyone to
anyone and so he's been teaching us about
this prajna thing I think this prajna is
sanskrit word for transcendental wisdom the
kind of wisdom that will free you from any
kind of hindrances any kind of obstructions
against your wishes okay and so so what's
special about his instructions is that he
gave us secret recipes on how to reach or
rediscover or reconnect with our prajna
wisdom so maybe initially you won't be able
to do it but you should know about it you
should hear about it eventually down the road
in time it's going to happen to you this is
one of the ancient Buddhist wisdoms ancient
Buddhist secrets that is we all eventually
will be able to rekindle to reconnect with
our incredible wisdom okay that's a fact the
Buddha all Buddhas guaranteed it it's nothing
new at all so so don't look down upon yourself
don't sell yourself short you are perfectly
capable to be the best you can be and be
equal of all Buddhas and it's because of
the blessings you planted in the past and
you continue to plant the more blessings you
plant the quicker you get there that's all
so now it's 180 and look at sutra text thank
you all the Buddhas in three periods of time
and the 12 divisions of sutra texts as well
exists within the nature of people originally
complete with them within them
[reading Chinese sutra text]
okay 181 he says that all Buddhas of the three
periods of time three periods of time in Buddhism
means of the past and the present of the future
meaning all Buddhists from the past all Buddhas
are present right now in the universe and
all Buddhas on future Buddhists in the universe
okay so this refers to the fact all Buddhas
at all times and the 12 division of sutra texts
as well the 12 divisions of sutra text refers
to all the Buddhist texts that the Buddha when
the Buddha came to our world and gave us sermons
or preached his teachings and they can be
classified into 12 different types of
language I mean phrasing and that's what
they call 12 divisions okay and and it says
it exists within the nature of people he says
that you nature of people refers to you to me
to all of us all of us are endowed with this
thing called nature or the short nature short
for Buddha nature meaning that we have it
believe it or not this nature here is as vast
as the universe it's no different from the
universe it contains everything in that little
thing of a frame of yours it has it infinite
uh thing uh that's uh contained within it
you believe it or not you see uh see it's
not something that you can understand and
this is why it's called wisdom you don't have
enough wisdom yet to understand and that's
why you need more time to um begin to rediscover
your true self okay so it says that all the
Buddhas all the Buddhas in this universe are
they exist within our nature how is it possible
how is it possible
how can all Buddhas especially for you intellectual
people rational people how come how can Buddhas
who have not come have not come Buddhas yet
they all exist in our nature how can something
hasn't come to fruition fruition yet who
has not come to existence yet they also exist
in our nature your nature and my nature
nature of short people nature of children
nature of tall people nature of yellow people
nature of white face people pale face people
all people all living beings they have this
nature that contains all Buddhas of the three
periods of time and all the teachings
so that's why for example master XuanHua when
he was lecturing sutras he never used any
texts like us okay he doesn't have to read
his slides or look at the sutras and read
from sutras he would sort of like open his
spiritual eye and start like we do here instead
of me reading from the slide here moving the
cursor and the mouse and say all Buddha three
periods of time I have to read it he would
you know sort of close his eyes and they started
reading off somewhere in space
proof right there that he's able to see it
and and uh so that's uh that's uh so he can
see it within his nature okay his Buddha nature
so Buddha nature is replete with everything
okay and it is uh accessible through you through
your small frame the little girl's frame is that
okay to mention your name right now honey
she said you have to ask my permission next
time
you understand permission is that okay okay
there you go thank you okay so so all the
the nature the natures refers to the Buddha
nature that each and every single living being
possesses okay and it says in that nature
right there are you have everything you have the
entire universe you have Buddhas all teachings
as well so far so good
and that's why so the self nature these are
the little bit of a jargon you should remember
and that's important because this is yours
it's like this your treasure make sure you
recognize it don't throw it away right so
something that we mentioned nature is your
Buddha nature your self-nature those are the
jargons it tells that tells you about the
true treasure that you all possess we all
possess okay uh it's worth a lot more than
a house in San Jose
okay and and the all these Buddha in the three
periods of time and and the all the sutra
texts uh they exist and originally complete
with them within them it means nothing lacking
at all we are we have everything there is
in other words all the treasures are within
you when we worldly people when you get education
we get training get experience what we are
learned to do we learn to look outside look
at how the external world functions and we're
fascinated by that fascinating how to build
bridge how to build things how to acquire
things and so forth and so what happened is
is right there is the confirmation to you
the proof to you that we so we are so brainwashed
into looking outside that's why we forget
about our own treasure
okay and and that's the difference about Buddhism
Buddhism says that the ultimate Buddhist wisdom
is that you are just like me and I exist within
you I'm not different from you at all all
right 182 if you're unable to enlighten
yourself you should seek out the instruction
of a good knowing advisor who'll instruct and lead
you to see your nature
[Read sutra text in Chinese] well Chinese pronunciation is a little
bit sharper than Taiwanese I'm noticing it
beautiful okay so he says I know you're skeptical
it sounds too good to be true right Daniel
me is it me my nature has everything how come am
I so poor huh how come I struggle so much
okay how come I'm not married yet okay he
says if you're unable to enlighten yourself
meaning uh he says he addresses all
these people his disciples have been teaching
all these years I've been telling you over
and over again and you still are not there
you still cannot see your nature so that's
it's referring to such people that includes
us if we are unable to enlighten ourselves we
should seek out the instruction of a good
knowing advisor it says if you can't see it
you cannot see the nature you cannot see the
sutras in space you cannot see the sutras
inside of your nature okay if you cannot access
your own enlightened your own wisdom then
what you ought to do you should seek out the
instructions of a good knowing advisor good knowing
advisor again is a technical term another
jargon is someone who is enlightened and who
can teach us how to become enlightened he
can show us the way okay so that's what he
says good knowing advisers in Buddhism are the
ones who have enough wisdom to instruct us
give give us instructions on how to be just
like them no less okay remember when you become
enlightened when you see your nature we're all
the same you then realize that woman is not
different for men girl is not different from
boys okay little girls is the same as adults
okay it's no more discrimination it's no more
differentiation no more differences between
you and me between ethnicities between uh
height some people are short some people are
tall okay it's my fascination I don't know
why the Chinese people who are wiser than
than I am they're all shorter than I am for
some reason I don't get it
the the people I admire most have incredible
wisdom that's all so short and skinny
okay they must never eat pizza or anything like
that
I understand that little girl doesn't eat
tacos I can see you yes you do last night
finally
before you forgot ah okay how about churros
churros? churros is good
okay so you should seek out the instructional
good knowing advisor good knowing advisors by the
way are the ones who would be gladly share
be we have the opportunity to share with you
uh how to enlighten yourself
and this this is the thing why because once
you're enlightened you have the wisdom you
know that you're the same as others that's
therefore why should you hold back why you
should not help others you help others it's
the same as helping you
okay so that's why you should have no fear
you say you want to become enlightened you
want to open your wisdom seek out someone
who has done it already and you know what
you find out they will gladly share with you
uh
and they share the instruction what the instruction
will do for you they will show you instruct
you and lead you to see your nature so a teacher
a wise teacher is not the one who makes promises
he's not the one who tells you stories you're
not the one who would waste your time it's
the one that says um so you want to become
enlightened you want to be the same
as all Buddhas to help you want to be
at your best then I will instruct you I will
tell you how to do it not only will I instruct
you the good knowing advisor is supposed to give
you instruction instruction meaning do this
and do that it's not theory folks
this is a mistake that you make when you meet
and seeing good knowing advisor you think good
knowing advisors are going to sit there and argue
with you and demonstrate to you that they
know more than you and they that you are stupid
you don't understand Buddhism at all so they
would keep on talking endlessly about this
suture and all the sutures and the principles
and how wonderful their their knowledge is
how deep the knowledge is no good knowing advisers
don't do that that's for professors that's
for people who are not enlightened who have
a lot of time remember enlightened people
are busy helping others become enlightened
so they don't have time to waste with you
for me with me as a matter of fact as well
okay and so they would not spend time telling
you about how much they know about this sutra
or the other sutra how much they know about
wine how much you know about you know geography
history and so forth what they will tell you
is what you need to do what you need to know
in order to become enligtened that's it nothing
more it's very specific instructions that
are but that are peculiar to you specific
to you only it's not like you know do this
and get rich and so forth anyone can do that
he says for you to get rich what you need
to do is buy this cryptocurrency called uh
okay and then you hold it for so long and
then you switch to the other cryptocurrency
because this one will crash and so forth so
there's so detailed you know I remember I
don't know you believe it or not
when I first started teaching Chan meditation
I met this guy here who's uh really not a
Buddhist believer but uh in a Chinese
Vietnamese guy his teacher specializes in
YiJing YiJing is the Chinese wisdom they can
look at the phenomena in nature and they can
tell you what's going to happen in the future
for example someone was so good that they're
a bunch of Vietnamese guys sitting together
gabbing away and drinking Vietnamese coffee
anyone Vietnamese coffee okay so they are drinking
coffee and then and the guy says oh okay okay
guys I needed I need to take off so the guy
who's specialist in YiJing okay uh
you might want to remember this if you find
those people who know YiJing they're incredible
the YiJing specialist he just says oh watch out don't
get into an accident and the guy seriously
so he drove up not thinking much about it
and turned the corner and got in an accident
right away
that's YiJing for you and this is real they
can see you know like birds flying through
oh it's going to rain tomorrow something like
that okay that's YiJing wisdom believe it
or not so the the Chinese have such uh incredible
wisdom by the way those wisdom those those
techniques were invented by bodhisattvas
okay so that's why the Chinese culture is
very very profound they have they have all
these special knowledge that were taught by
the enlightened people who came to China to
help the Chinese people help the Asians okay
and now that the Asians becoming caucAsians
no one knows about them anymore you see so
it's more like an Asian thing yeah
we're born too late
so anyway so this is this uh so so this uh
this uh YiJing here is incredibly precise
so I know of another Vietnamese guy who also
uh is a believer in this guy who who practices
YiJing as well and what this Vietnamese guy
he used to be an engineer you might be interested
in this Qun he used to be a meChanical engineer
in los angeles this is about 20 years ago
okay like he graduated from UC San Diego or
something and worked as a mechanical engineer
in the area and then his older brother introduced
him to his his acquaintance who's a martial
arts teacher who specializes in studying the
YiJing and you know a martial arts teacher
XiaoTai they're not very rich you know you
know they don't have a lot of money all the
money is in the dojo and the clothes they
wear you know they buy from you know they
so anyway so this this guy here doesn't have
money but he specializes in YiJing so he says
you know what since you work for uh Qualcomm
okay Qualcomm okay do I yeah did I pronounce
it right
now yesterday you know Qun showed me this
app here in google app about how to pronounce
things properly and I'm so self-conscious
did I pronounce it right
so he he he says you have a little bit of money so
let me let's make a deal okay I will show
you okay the Qualcomm stock prices movement
so this guy here started borrowing money to
buy this Qualcomm stocks and then sell at
the right time and and then wait and then
buy them again and then sell more and he just
looked at one stock and just waited and waited
and waited until it drops and goes up up
and down up and down so what he did is this
engineer told us told my brother he says he
is so accurate he says it will go to get to
46 dollars and then it goes up to 52 sell
it because it's gonna drop and it drops okay
you walk you wait until it's uh uh 27 you
buy it because it's gonna go and start going
up that's how precise he was can you imagine
so that kid engineer mechanical engineer i
met him he retired at the age of you know
31 or 32. he's like worth a lot of money back
then he's worth like 15 million dollars
that's a lot of houses in San Jose nowadays
how about that so that that the instruction
are so precise the people with wisdom people
who really know they tell us exactly what
to do there's no ambiguity about it ambiguity
am I correct uh never mind so that's what
instructions are the enlightened people the
instructions say do this and do that okay
uh do it right now okay so you see it is so
precise instructions to get there and your
cultivation is very detailed very very precise
there's no ambiguity and then furthermore
that's instruction and lead you what is leading
leading means that
two things they know the way okay they know
the way and number two they encourage you
a leader is a person uh uh is it is
it fair to say as leader as person who knows
how to encourage her people her follower her
employees subordinates oh no
it's not about arguing it's not about proving
you are right about encouraging leading them in
the right direction
okay so this is what this is what a good knowing
advisor does he has the detailed knowledge
accurate knowledge on how to do it and they
know how to lead you encourage you and and
and guide you to see your nature
okay and you might wonder why they want to
do this okay if you have someone become enlightened
your blessings are incredible okay you you
incredibly rich they have incredible blessings
that's why okay they do not only for you but
ultimately first of all they do it for you
but ultimately once but if they do it selflessly
their rewards their blessings are out of this
world so that's why these people when they
help us it's a it's uh really selfless they're
not they have no ulterior motives okay it's
like when I look at you especially Vietnamese
people I come near you and look at me say
what are you up to sound familiar you know
what are you trying to do
nothing okay
you find out little girl when you get older
okay 184 sutra text if you're one who enlightened
himself you need not seek outside if you insist
that it is necessary to seek a good knowing advisor
in the hope of obtaining liberation you're
mistaken why
okay 185. so the great teacher continues he
says if you are the one who can figure out
how to become enlightened yourself
okay if you are able to do that then you're
not not you need not seek outside what is
not need no need to seek outside what does
it mean it means that you don't need to go
look for someone's help anyone else's help
okay you can if you're able to enlighten yourself
then you look inside you you will figure it
out by looking inside not going out and asking
someone else to help you
that is if you're able to enlighten yourself
all right on the other hand if you insist
that it is necessary to seek a good knowing advisor
in the hope of obtaining liberation you're
mistaken why and furthermore uh master HuiNeng says if you insist because you keep on hearing
from the Chinese from the people before you
said you should look for good knowing advisor
that's the Chan wisdom okay and that's how
you best can hope to attain liberation to
become enlightened obtain liberation means
you liberate from your mediocrity you liberate
yourself from your own self-imposed suffering
the suffering that you undergoing right now
you are doing right now are self-imposed did
you know that no one else is making you suffer
but yourself you did it to yourself you're
doing to yourself okay you don't realize and
what happens I talked to one of my disciples
recently and she says you know it's uh my
partner's fault you know she keeps on talk
telling me uh what her partner does wrong
okay so it's always someone else's fault and
she doesn't realize that the
she's the one who's making herself endure
all the suffering it's no talking to her okay
and that's what happened to you
people who are too smart too educated okay
you only you only believe in your own mind
okay and and you in particular you can't even
see that you are tormenting yourself you're
creating all this suffering yourself all the
suffering again are self-created
okay that ego of yours is a real culprit the
ego of yours the existence of a self is the
source of all the suffering in your life
until you wake up to that you will not be
able to attain liberation so Buddhists pursuits
Buddhist wisdom Buddhist training is about
knowing how to get rid of that ego of ours
that is the cause of all our suffering and
the question a fair question to ask is once
you get rid of your ego what happens to you
what happens to you
then you're going to get married and be happy
right Daniel
if you put an end to your own ego you will
never suffer again you only know bliss and
peace in your life people keep on telling
me I keep hearing about this he said I would
like to have a I really appreciate it when
I have a moment one moment of peace during
the day sounds familiar the whole day for
us is all turmoil it's all it's so turbulent
it's one worry another after another excuse
me and and the turmoil the turbulence are
created uh by your egos you you constantly
are grabbing this and grabbing that okay you
cannot help yourself you greedy for this you
greedy for that you upset at this person
upset at the other person upset at the kid you
know and so forth
because they're not the way you expect them
to be okay you remember notice that expression
you expect them to be who expects them to
be your ego expects them to be and what you
do you keep on blaming others for your own
misery
when are you going to wake up to that
okay and and that's your problem you cannot
you don't realize that you don't know how
to rein in your ego to rein in your desires
to rein in your
your arrogance okay and and so that's why
you you suffer so liberation is a concept
it says uh the different types of liberations
as you practice the spiritual practice whether
it's Buddhism whether it's Daoism whether
it's Catholicism as you increase your skills
level concentration level you naturally will
have will experience certain different types
of liberation so in Buddhism it's very precise
when you reach different levels of concentration
each level is associated with a degree of
liberation until you reach the highest level
of samadhi that's when you are totally free
you attain total liberation you'll never suffer
again
even though when your wife yells at you
not funny oh yeah it's possible okay so he
says if you think it's necessary uh to seek
a good knowing advisor remember he says he said
go look for a good knowing advisor but he says now if you insist
it's necessary to look for good
new advisor in order to attain liberation
to free yourself and put an end to all your
suffering you're mistaken why 186. within
your own mind there is self-enlightenment
which is a knowing advisor
okay why are you not supposed to seek a good
knowing advisor because he says within your mind
right now the mind you have right now nowhere
else okay not in mine not in hers it's your
mind now okay uh there is self-enlightenment
that mind of yours contain uh
enlightenment this mind of yours can enlighten
yourself which is a knowing advisor meaning
it knows how to enlighten yourself
go ahead it says I don't believe
anyone has any problems with this
yes yellow
[Question in Vietnamese]
amituofo master, so everybody in each of our self all
have something called the conscience mind
and when that conscience mind when we do something
wrong that conscience mind will be um we will
feel ashamed and we will feel regret so if
a person who lives fully completely within
their own conscious mind doesn't mean that
they can become enlightened
it's possible but very unlikely most likely
a person who lives in in with a guilty conscience
will end up being depressed
okay so enlightenment is a lot more than just
a guilty conscience
okay but having a guilty conscience is definitely
very helpful towards becoming enlightened
okay and so uh what he's talking about here
what master HuiNeng is talking about here is
that when you become enlightened
the moment you become enlightened when you
become enlightened how does it happen
how?
microphone no color uh you listen to your
inner good knowing advisor you listen your inner
enlightened thing very creative how you listen
your inner enlightened nature
clearly this person doesn't know what she's
talking about because you know when you say
something you have to do say emphatically
you say you listen your own nature you say
you you you recognize it and then you follow
it
you recognize and then what the and then follow it
and then follow it
trying to google
[Laughter]
okay follow it okay
so you listen your enlightened mind you follow
it are you sure
um
it doesn't quite work like that okay
who recognizes your enlightenment
who recognizes it
who who sees his own nature her own nature
what happened at that moment
well I have all day I am have nowhere else
to go go ahead Wei mountain
the Korean got up this early
and then they said I don't know master I'm so
sleepy can you just speed it up a little we
we're trying to stay awake here
yeah Wei Mountain go ahead
four o'clock on sunday morning they're listening
to sutra lectures Koreans are weird
yeah master I don't I don't know what happens
because I'm not enlightened but I've heard
you say that when someone becomes enlightened
there's an earthquake but no one gets hurt
by the earthquake
an earthquake that hurts no one
well that's why it hurt too that's all I did
is I regurgitated that
any anything else
okay suffice to tell you this okay when
is your turn to become enlightened this is
what's going to happen and if it doesn't help
please uh doesn't happen please don't sue
me okay it's just it's just a free a free
offering okay like google hey I could be wrong
too when you become enlightened how
do you see your nature
your self nature sees itself it's that simple
who else can see it right it's no one else
it's not like one of them say hey I can see
you your self-nature no at that very moment
you become enlightened your self nature sees
itself am I making sense to you
who else gonna see it for you some kind of
short Asian guy
huh of course not you have to see yourself
so at that moment here's what happened at
that very moment you become enlightened and
the technical jargon means at the moment you
see your nature what it really is talking
about your self your own self nature sees
itself
okay
that's all it means
it sees itself and what does it mean when
you see itself when your self nature sees
itself
hm what does it mean oh god you don't know
anything do you oh how can you live like this
huh
yes sir what happens when he says the self
nature sees itself yes
[Master XianChi Speaking in Vietnamese]
amituofo master, um so I have been applying this
to me I feel that it is not hard it is not
easy just like venerable HuiNeng taught venerable
HuiMing is this um
I don't know how to translate that Ping Xin. At that
moment, there's no the mind of non-discriminating
the mind of non-discrimination
at that moment there's no thought of evil
no thought of goodness so right at that time
it is your own original mind and venerable
HuiMing asked venerable HuiNeng again is that is there
any other secret and venerable HuiNeng and say
no the secret lies within you so if you practice
to the point that you can sustain the thought
of no evil and no goodness for a long time
then your good knowing advisor will certify
you as becoming enlightened and if you still
have this mind of good and evil it's just
like the banner the float with the wind and
this is how I perceive it okay very good let
me explain the process for you so that it
removes a little a little bit of the mystery
from all these Chinese talk about enlightenment
and so forth or other caucAsians or Westerners
talk about enlightenment and will help you
understand what is plausible what's not okay
the Westerners you talk to a lot of people
or not just the Westerners also a lot of uh
quack Asians who says I'm enlightened okay
especially a lot of monks and nuns who says
I'm enlightened I've seen enlightenment i
know about enlightenment okay and they don't
know what they're talking about because that's
not how it works okay the way it works is
that for you to become enlightened look at
the history of how master HuiNeng became enlightened
how master XuanHua become enlightened all the
people before them became enlightened Buddhas
how Buddhas became enlightened what are the requirements
there's one requirement
what is it hmm what is that one requirement
that's a one common denominator all to all
of them
now the Vietnamese are excited yes
[Answer in Vietnamese]
amituofo master, to me there's the the only
requirement that happened at that time is
you let go there's no such discrimination
okay old monk what do they all do? at that moment
no thought arise
no thought arise, very good. Wei Mountain.
no Wei Mountain uh uh backed out anyone else
Koreans would you like to join the party
are you too sleepy I thought I helped you
wake up and say hey what happens what is the
same common denominator that you Koreans also
must do to experience that moment
go ahead short uh Vietnamese amituofo
master, I think one condition is that look
in yourself not outside look yourself not outside
very good anyone else Koreans we were waiting
for some kimchi input
yeah come on Koreans master Z represent all
Koreans
don't let them down now
[Laughter] don't let your people down
yeah what happens as a common denominator
they
one word
only one word not one one phrase not one sentence
one word they is a verb
they sleep no no look [Laughter] yeah what
they what did they do XianEn what did they do
huh
what do they do they oh my god you forgot
already we told you so many stories
[Answer in Korean]
stop thinking, very good.
they I want one word not stop thinking that's
two
huh I told you I gave you a clue already one
word not two huh
no false thinking no false thinking no false
thinking that's three words okay who else
one word uh China girl
huh listen [Laughter] how are you listening
we're looking at looking how do you come
how you go from listening to looking okay
orange uh drop they drop drop the ball okay
they come on one word one verb at the very
the requirements for any of us to become enlightened
or Buddha what do you need to do
very good but wrong
look at how excited I know I know
yes back there what do they do
no self no self that's two faith master faith
they pay oh yeah that's right huh what
faith is not a word what is the matter with
you faith is a noun
amigo you can't do that okay what do they
do they
stopped
stop
in the name of love
you guys are too much it's so obvious when
are you gonna know when when are you gonna
wake up to the the the the the thing we've
been repeating for you over and over and over
again every single master every single every
single year I've been talking to you you keep
on hearing that like virtually every month
yeah I've been beating into your brains and
what is the matter with you master Z have
you figured it out
Koreans yeah forget about Koreans yeah
yeah orange accept
accept cryptocurrencies
god what is
huh they cultivate which you don't do [Laughter]
anyone else, Korea, ok Korea.
three words they are in samadhi enter samadhi
excellent enter samadhi is two words what
is this the Koreans don't they can't even
count now Guan-Ho
master I think unmoving unmoving
what I'm getting at okay I'm sorry it's not
clear to you look at how the Shakyamuni Buddha
become a Buddha what was he doing yes meditate
what megitate that's a new word
don't help her
very good
in order for you to open your wisdom you must
meditate
isn't that wonderful that's what we've been
teaching you you do ceremony you call it chanting
we call it actually it's a form of meditation
you see that meditate okay so this
is key this is why in Buddhism we put so much
emphasis on teaching you about about meditation
how to meditate because ultimately when you
get there at the moment you you become a Buddha
you have to meditate okay and then you will
have no thought you would drop it you stop
and so forth but that is a state of meditation
is it clear you have to meditate this is why
you meditate meditate meditate and one day
say boom at that very moment what happens
your self nature recognize itself oh
wow that's my self nature and how do you see
it because your self nature sees itself you
know that and that moment what happens that
why why is that moment is very important this
is so critical this is and I don't know why
the Chinese or Koreans didn't teach their
disciples
huh see he's so excited see I'm so excited
he's so excited too here's what happens okay
what happened is that you meditate meditate
meditate that moment your self-nature says
wow hey that's that's mine that's my self
nature right there so that very moment because
your meditation your self nature
sees itself and what it means is that because
of meditation you have the technique on how
to activate your self-nature to see
so it's not something haphazard at all the
Buddha when he became a Buddha he sat
on the bodhi tree for 49 days right he says
if I don't become a Buddha I will not I will
never get up from this from from from uh from
my meditation he will never get out of here okay
so after 49 days he who is meditating all
sudden he saw something uh a light you
know a a a star flying by okay in the sky
okay and boom at that moment there his self
nature saw itself it's oh that's it and because
of that okay because of that he developed
he remembered how to do it whereas now you
have you do it occasionally you know you do
it like Vietnamese says []
okay meaning that you know Vietnamese has
a very very uh ex expression that says []
meaning a dog catches the fly uh by Chance
you know he was yawning and then he's yawning
and then whoop and he catches the fly so what happens is
you he'll never be able to do it again
you see that's what it means it's a haphazard
thing and whereas in Buddhism you develop
you train you day in day out train you help
you and cajole you and encourage you and
threaten you and beat you up and insult you
you know and praise you and all those things
are called leading we talked about earlier
remember he says will instruct and lead you
all that's called leadership you understand
sometimes you yell at them sometimes you smile
at them sometimes you have to cry sometimes
you have to give up sometimes whatever all
those are called leading
and it gets you going going and then one
some point in time boom you see it and say
wow I know how to do it now
and that's why it's so important that's why
this meditation things here you don't understand
you don't realize what we are doing is we
are leading you to develop the skills for
you to do it consistently not like a []
you have to remember this expression
Vietnamese expression the dog that catches
the fly
through yawning
got that Korean did your sunims teach you
that that's what happens this is why you have
to go to the come to the temple that's why
you have to meditate every day because you're
developing the skills to do it consistently
understand now
it's a skill it's not something haphazard
something by chance it's a skill that you
need to develop the ability to do
consistently
okay right now you're able to occasionally
do that but you don't realize it's you whereas
because through meditation training you go
through this training process you meditate
meditate and then say wow it happens oh that's
how I did it
so the moment you see your nature that moment
there you recognize it oh wow that's me i
did it whereas now when you use your nature
and you see you know part of your nature and
you see a partial picture you have no clue
what it is you cannot tell the difference
is that clear it's not you cannot do right
now you can you can do it too but you
cannot do it consistently and you cannot do
it at will
after you become after that moment when you
see your nature you're able to do it consistently
so meaning that when you need to to liberate
yourself and rise above suffering boom you
can do it at will
whereas right now you say I don't know why
I'm crying I don't know why I'm suffering
so much if you have that skill you say
what suffering instantaneously
you're
free you rise above all this suffering
all these nonsense
instantaneously
what happened to the applause sign wait a
minute this is like
one person
this is a state secret
okay Jumi now you go back to sleep okay
look at that poor women oh my god I'm so sleepy
I'm so sleepy can I go back to bed please
okay all right oh god yeah it's just like
trying to explain to you this is so hard I'm
so tired now look at all your really really
stop uh uh no thought uh
after all these years I've been doing this
for 16 years and this is all you got
okay next should we continue or should we stop
I'm tired
if
you are one who enlightens himself you need
not seek outside oh why am I still here okay
next uh next who is moving my slides within
your own mind there's self enlightenment which
is a knowing advisor okay remember this is where
why I explained to you that very moment when
you meditate when you see your nature that's
what he's referring to is that clear when
you get there you know that very moment that's
why at that very moment you know these people
who are enlightened they know
what happened is the people below that level
they are not enlightened but they falsely
think and that's why it's very dangerous
i met too many people who are mistakenly in
the belief that they are enlightened they
haven't seen your nature yet okay you can
tell immediately from their comportment yes
master is the definition of meditation here
beyond just sitting since I think some in
some of the stories meditation is to learn how to concentrate
when we teach you meditation we start by teaching
you to cross your legs sitting meditation
but eventually you understand that meditation
is 24 hours a day you can do it anytime you
don't need to cross your legs anymore okay
but crossing your legs is the quickest way
to develop your meditation skills so you cannot
say that I don't I don't need to cross my
legs because it's not necessary it's not true
it's necessary for you
you have to have the skills to cross your
legs first okay
188 but if you give rise to deviant confusion
false thoughts and perversions although a
good knowing advisor external external to you
instructs you he cannot save
you
okay now he's giving us a caution a warning
he says you may have a good knowing advisor here's
the danger you have to be careful and this
is what happened to uh XiaoTai is here cover his
ears up happens to the word begins with an
"L"
lion there you go very good
okay here's what happens you may have a great
teacher like master XuanHua or master
HuiNeng okay okay but if you give rise to deviant
confusion false thoughts and perversions what
are they these are very important words of
warning to caution you because these are the
aspects that will lead you astray and doesn't
matter who you learn from where you are who
you are how far you got okay you will get
in trouble
okay if you still harbor give rise to means
harbor you still have it in your heart in
your mind you still believe these things okay
that's how they give rise they give rise meaning
it comes from you you believe you believe
it what do you believe you have you have deviant
beliefs you have you have false thoughts you
have perversions okay deviant meaning that
you don't believe in cause and effect okay
people who do not believe in cause and effect
they will get in trouble eventually they cannot
become enlightened cannot it's hopeless okay
confusion uh Xie Mi, confusion is that your
mind is dark you cannot recognize uh things
that they are you mistaken about things perversion
perversion meaning that there are different
perversions
perversions meaning that by definition perversions
are you are in contradiction to the
principles the proper principles okay what
are the proper principles uh the four of them
number one okay there
this body is impure don't be so attached to
this body of yours you so attach to your body
is upside-down view
know anyone who has upside-down views
all of you
attachment to the body okay yeah uh number
one and number two uh feelings your feelings
uh you cherish your feelings
okay you think feelings are cool for example
you seek feelings of pleasure you seek feelings
of pain for some people
okay so Jumi you seek pleasure you seek pain
she's sleeping
do you seek pain or you seek pleasure
[Jumi answer in Korean]
I thought about what I'm attached to and I
I found out that I am attached to the comfort
and nothing happened okay so she's attached
to pleasure okay therefore she is upside-down
okay very good
anyone attached to pain in Korea
no one in Korea is attached to pain
they would never admit it how about us Americans
anyone of you attached to pain
[Laughter] XiaoTai attach to pain seriously
[Laughter] uh okay so uh that's uh that's
what is feelings you attach to feelings and
that's uh uh you you you you seek feelings
of pleasure you seek feelings of pain and
that's upside-down number three
you think that your your mind is permanent
meaning for example you say I love my husband
and we will be forever it's so untrue yes
no
okay so the mind is impermanent and yet and
yet you think the mind will be forever
okay and finally there's no self, dharma has
no self, meaning everything has no self whatsoever
everything is um is uh yes it has a has no
self everything is empty okay so if you can't
violate those four things then you are considered
upside-down all right false thoughts the false
thoughts are the thinking that arise when
you meditate for example you're meditating
you reciting the Buddha's name also one other thought arises
that's called a false thought okay so the
caveat the warning here is that if
you give rise to deviancy false belief confusion
you're confused by marks by external things
you have false thinking okay and you are have
perversions okay then here's what happens
if you do that you still have that although
there's a good knowing advisor outside of you
instructs you he cannot save you
is that clear the good knowing advisor may have
wisdom may be a Buddha but if you insist on
harboring deviancy confused about external
things you keep on you cherish thinking and
you are confused about principles then no
one can save you no matter how wise and smart
they are no matter how hard they try they
cannot save you
and this is a fallacy of spiritual cultivation
people they cultivate they recite the Buddha's
name for 20 30 years okay for a lifetime after
lifetime what they failed to do is to get
rid of deviancy get rid of confusion get rid
of false thinking and rid of perversion that's
why they will never become enlightened you
can meditate all you want
but you don't get rid of these things you
will never be able to do it you may have may
have the greatest teacher but you eventually
will fall off by the wayside that's it and
that's why what I've been watching for the
last 16 years so many of these people okay
give an example first newcomers they first
come and
they are deviant they said I don't believe
in cause and effect I believe in the power
of money I believe in I believe in the fact
that this life once it's life is uh is is
over it doesn't matter everything returned
to dust okay all those are deviant beliefs
such people who came they are gone very very
quickly
all right be careful and then furthermore
there are a lot of people who came to our
temple who practice for years but deep down
they harbor these beliefs okay they are uh
looking for for example spiritual penetration
they said oh my god I can see this I can I
can see that okay I love to see I'd love to
see see this I'd love to be able to do that
okay and they're confused about the fact that
all those things are not never the goals of
meditation
and therefore they get excited because with
meditation they're able to to do it
better to see things more things you see it
more frequently okay and they believe more
and more in themselves it's called confusion
the more they improve the more they can see
and the more they really think that they are
so special
okay so they came with these beliefs that
they learn all these things so that they are
become even more special than before so the
ego becomes bigger
and that's confusion go ahead JMT
people are depressed are they looking for
pain pain repeat the question
uh when people are depressed uh are they looking
for pain when they're depressed are they looking
for pain attac-attached to pain are they
attached to pain
I don't know I'm never depressed anyone's
depressed help me out please when you depressed
what happens huh you when you depressed are
you looking for pain
are you depressed
before you were depressed before once depressed
always depressed
don't think you're free from it it'll come
back like alcoholism like drug addiction it'll
come back
okay are they looking for pain are you looking
for pain when you're depressed she says no
what about the rest of you? No, two Nos. Daniel
you're depressed too? No
no or yes I cannot tell your movement now is
so subtle
there is uh I think there's some attachment
to attachment to pain
to yeah to the feeling of getting depressed
you're weird anyway anyone else huh Wei Mountain
what happens when you're depressed are you
attached to pain oh oh thank you master, I
thought he said are you attached to a pen
[Laughter] because when I've been depressed
I find a pen is very helpful it helps me write
things down and kind of get them out of my
head you know if I can't find a pen then uh
okay let's not muddy up the water again you're
not helping okay anyone else uh Wei Mountain
go ahead good lord
go um I think depressed people are not attached
to pain they just want to get the pain over
so at that dependency you feel pleasure about
feeling pain come on man come on Daniel be
assert yourself don't be so Catholic say don't
say don't say I don't start with "I think". no just
say No, they don't. No, they aren't, okay? come
on let's be a macho man yeah are you attached
to pain when you're depressed I actually experienced
depression last year oh no not not attached
but suffered from depression suffer from depression
I guess the reason was I was so obsessed with
get rid of the feeling of being depressed
right and the process of trying to push it
away make me actually more depressed yeah
that's my yeah personal experience but you
know attached to pain no I guess I'm attached
to get rid of pain right right maybe okay
that's more not too much not like depends
what is that huh okay no no depressed
people are not attached to pain in general
of course they always uh uh uh exceptions
okay in Korea okay there will be exceptions
but in America most people who are depressed
they're not attached to pain at all actually
they're in pain they don't like it they hate
it but they cannot do anything about it they
don't know what to do about them
sounds familiar
okay remember when you're depressed and you're
in such great pain you feel so in pain and
you just don't know what to do to snap out
of it so they're not attached at all they
just are totally
under the spell they're victims of the state of
depression this is why I'm reminding you if
you know you have severe depression you better
go get help because you won't be able to handle
it that's a typical case where when you are
in a state of depression you will find reason
for you not to do anything and and so forth
and you have to pre-program yourself and before
you get depressed then you need to go seek
help because it's way beyond you I'll give
an example when I I'm sorry I bring it out
right now okay uh you know I've been uh trying
to fix uh the uh temple in San Francisco we
do remodeling okay finalizing the you know
little things here and there and uh it's a
lot of it's a lot of things a lot of you know
things to take care of small things and it
turns out I have a very a group of very dedicated
people who are trying to help and one of them
is Master XianJie Master XianJie is really among them
a few who are very very key uh to the efforts
okay they all took pieces of the work and
they are working together to make it happen
and we really appreciate that what what happened
with Master XianJie in particular is that he's
had severe depression his entire life okay
debilitating depression and was very bad before
he became a monk okay and and uh it's getting
better and better nowadays okay however I
I declared a long some time ago he's a fourth-stage
arhat okay meaning he's way up there in terms
of Gongfu but every time he under severe
depression he's totally not himself
you can tell right away you want to look at
him I didn't say anything oh boy you're depressed
again okay and that's what happens because
of the importance of the kind of work I do
we do in San Francisco they will come and
try to stop us slow us down and because if
your work is important if you're doing something
important that towards that effort they will
come and attack you as well because they cannot
attack me okay so what happened is that I
noticed that these people either they get
injured themselves or they become depressed
they become manic uh and so forth and that's
how they stop me okay they slow me down okay
so so that is to tell you I'll tell you two
things number one even fourth stage arhats
are helpless against depression if you're
not even fourth stage arhat you really have no
chance at all
okay
uh and uh and the other thing is that um is
that uh
when you are in that state okay you need help
and so I have been watching that and I decided
to give the order it's okay to lift them up
immediately yesterday I decided to do that
Master XianJie came to Gold Forest a changed
man did you notice
I wanted to
let you know that depression can be helped
okay and you need to seek help because even
for very strong people very high highly skilled
people have some some real GongFu like fourth
stage arhats they still are helpless against
depression
is a very serious issue and it's not something
that the medical profession should take lightly
but they do because they don't know what to
do with it prescribing medication uh counseling
is not gonna help because you're fighting
an invisible enemy and ghost is so powerful
they pull your strings and they create confusions
in your mind there's nothing you can do that's
the truth yes thank you master I have a quick
question
the depression is contagious yes I heard a
lot of people say that but I don't know it's
true or not yes
you spend a lot of time near you spend you
are near depressed people like you married
to a depressed person you end up end up most
likely getting depressed yourself because
it's ghosts and it goes from this person
to the next very easily
so my next question is what can you do to
prevent contagious you get help
you know the reason I bring it up in Buddhism
every time bring you and bring up a problem
is because we have a solution we're not merchants
of doom we're not telling you those things
in order to make you more depressed and we
all tell you this problem because there's
solutions for it it's not easy but it's the
only thing that works right now that is far
better than meds than medication than therapy
and counseling because you're dealing with
invisible beings the the so-called the yin
beings the ghosts and the demons therefore
you must know a way develop a way to deal with
them okay as you get higher levels of samadhi
of wisdom then it's a lot more manageable
a lot like become negligible but at low levels
it's debilitating you cannot function you
cannot you are not yourself there's nothing
you can do that's why you need to get help
and and I'm I brought up master XianJie as
example is to tell you that even with very
experienced and skilled people they still
need help
that's how serious it is how difficult it
is okay
and so going back to slide 180 in our temples
I've seen all sorts of people remember I said
the newcomers who come with a bad attitude
okay thinking you know it all they're special
they're lawyers doctor and so forth I know everything
I'm successful okay and therefore therefore
they are they leave very quickly they cannot
last because they can never they are not seeking
wisdom they are seeking to reinforce the ego such
people don't last very long around us okay
and there's some people who last a lot longer
years and so forth but they harbor these deviant
thoughts these confuse thoughts about the process
and and as uh recently there's some people
who you know who I declare they have some
you know a arhatship range and so forth and
they're able to see this and see that and
so forth and they still fall off by the wayside
because of their deviant confusion
they harbor these they cherish these these
false beliefs that are not Buddhists
okay and therefore they have to leave ultimately
okay because their ghosts pull them out before
they can no longer control them before
they leave they would they say oh master is
probably possessed by a ghost
it's the ghost who told them to say so
and they're very proud of it oh oh have you
seen the 50 skandhas demons read it master has
got one of them one of those 50 skandhas demons
it's not the first time even master XuanHua's
uh glorious monks also said the same thing
about me
and guess what they're the one who are possessed
by the skandhas demons
okay so if you have all these things be careful
if you insist on these things you say oh master
I believe in Buddhism I want to be your spice
and so forth so forth I really believe in
you you know please teach me 42 hands and eyes
give me a lot of mantras that I can you know
I can help you in the future okay and then
they say I'm going to be a big shot I want
to be you know I'm going to be better you
know I'm I'm gonna uh uh oh oh I'm gonna be
glorious and and and open my spiritual penetration
so forth uh because I'm better than him already
okay
they fall off eventually
okay this is what happens
180 190 although there's a good knowing advisor
next to you who's trying to teach you he cannot
save you you doing it to yourself
you know such people
those are the ones who left and the ones who
are leaving
because they secretly harbor deviancy confusion
false thinking and perversions and they put
on a facade
you cannot fool yourself
you're shooting yourself in the foot that's
all
so watch out you see these people that's why
we don't keep on insisting to you you look
we do Chan meditation do not look for spiritual
penetrations all this is to reduce your ego
not make you ego bigger
okay all there are you watch those people
the people the "L people" so we call "L people"
from now on okay those "L people" they this
is what describes them
this is their downfall
and you don't need to do anything there's plenty
of people like that just watch them you don't
believe me watch them if they fit this description
they will fall off
questions comments
yes
master, you you you said that we are all uh
we all fall into the category of having upside
upside-down views right so uh what you just
said about is that include yeah everybody
of course you will have deviancy of course you
have some confusion you have false thoughts
you have perversions of course we all do okay
but the difference is that such "L people"
they cherish it and they say I don't buy what
master says master says don't be so attached
to your visions don't feel so attached to
your knowledge and especially don't be so
attached to your ego there they say yeah masters
you know I disagree that's what happened and
they disguise it okay they say oh yes yes
yes yes yes you're right you're right you're
right but deep down inside they said nah you
don't know what you're talking about and they
shoot themselves on the foot
it's not about me knowing whether I know or
not doesn't matter this is about you if you
harbor deviancy harbor confusion false thoughts
perversions and you that make you disagree
big time with my instructions you'll get in
is trouble clear okay not just these generals
of course we all have we all make mistakes
but these people really believe that they're
right that I'm wrong and they find excuses
they find proofs that's called deviancy it's
called confusion it's called perversions
it really believes in those things and guess
what their ego is so big that they fabricate
plenty of reasons and excuses inside this
sutra and that sutra 50 skandhas demons
and so forth this is what the especially my
master's disciples like to do when I was a
novice over there and they they claim already
among the monks that I was possessed by the
demon therefore decided 50 skandhas demons
say this guy is possessed by a demon
okay that's how they get rid of me and try
to get rid of me
and because of that such people who tried
those things are actually possessed by the
demons [Laughter] I don't need to do anything
to retaliate they possess by demons by their
own doing what do we care
and that's dangerous so to summaries to
summarize for you if you're not enlightened
yet and you insist on your ways okay you fall
into this group
you insist that you are right
and it cannot be explained to you because
you are, remember? stupid. you don't understand
you don't realize your deviant beliefs you're
confused you have perversions you don't even
realize it
go ahead Wei Mountain thank you master um does
depression increase your ego increase your
ego because since everyone has the ego or
is a different thing yes and no, it depends.
but depression is caused by the ghost taking
over and playing this program in your head
it says I feel bad I feel bad I feel bad i
feel bad I don't feel like doing anything
I don't want to do this I don't want to do
that and that's a depression that's a program
like computer program keeps on playing that
same thing whatever it does it ends with I
don't want to do this whatever it is I don't
want to do it whatever it is I don't want
to get up I don't want to address I don't
want to take a shower I don't want to eat
I don't want to sleep whatever okay I don't
want to I don't want to that's depression
because I don't want to means I want to continue
to feel this bad
but I want to continue to feel this bad is
not even detected by depressed people they're
not aware of it that's why they need help
yes
master that's why I was saying there's some
attachment that's what you were saying about
i don't want to stop feeling better no no
it's the program that's loaded onto
by the ghost in your brains it's not you
it could be as simple as get the heck out
of there and the ghost is gone if you do that
though there is a problem where does it go most
likely your mother you want that
that's why it's delicate you cannot brute
force it youtube
from Vicky master how do we check ourselves
to see our false thoughts and thoughts of
this disagreements you can this is why
remember you are stupid there's no way to
explain to you I don't know how else to put
it
explain to you you don't get it that's called
stupidity it's stupidity because no matter
how hard we try you don't get it because you're
stupid okay if you're stupid already stupid
people think they know more than a good knowing
advisor then it's time for them to leave
people who are stupid don't deserve to stay
Wei Mountain
master, does our Wei Mountain Daniel have a
depressing ghost? if it does, what is this depressing
ghost doing to Daniel or what Daniel is doing
reflecting that presence?
I don't know it's a Catholic thing we're Buddhists
why do we need to worry about the Catholic
stuff
there's a problem and you know you know you
I know I know you think I'm joking but here's
what happens to me
you come to me and you say master I'm depressed
I need help I say okay do this he said but
can I do something else don't like it can
I do something else
and that's a problem with you
if
I try to help you and tell you to do something
and you don't why should I continue to help
you
you're helpless you need my help you ask for
my help I try to help you and you say oh can
you give me something else I like
if I give you something you like that is not
true help the help usually is to do something
that you don't like
so Daniel's problem is that to be blunt
with you that was probably that yes I like
this I like this about this guy I like this
about this temple I like the fact they respect
me I like the fact they never pressure me
I like the fact they uh joke with me around
and so forth uh but I don't like this I don't
like that I don't believe this I don't believe
that so you it's like you you pick from a
menu I like this I like that I like this I
like that and that's not how we cultivate
the cultivation is you need to take things
that both you like and the ones you don't
like you have no choices if you pick and choose
you won't make it
that's a difference
so Daniel says oh I really like you know
the things that talk about how great I am
I have the same Buddha nature as their Buddhas
and so forth but you know I go back to my
god when I feel uncomfortable and that's his
problem that's where his ghosts hide in the
areas where he disagrees that's why they all
gather they all build their build headquarters
over there so as soon as he's uncomfortable
he retreats back to his let's say Catholic
areas Catholic headquarters and that's what
the ghosts are and that's off limits to us
remember we will never try to convert a Catholic
Wei Mountain
thank you master so people who are uh who
are suffering depression uh what would you
give them your first instruction
what's the question again
for people who are suffering depression uh
what would be your first uh instruction to
give them how to start it depends on who it
is on their samadhi level on a lot of factors
each person is different no one solution for
everything and when you go to a see a therapist
they give you what is it prozac or whatever
medicine there is a limited number of medication
they will prescribe to you for us we have
unlimited number of tools to use so each person
is different it's not the same thing so each
individual has different dosages different
medication uh different approaches depending
on the time of day the time of the year and
so forth and so forth there is no hard and fast
rule to deal with depression because each
time each case is different
sometimes we let them just like I gave you
the example of master XianJie I let him suffer for
a while okay sometimes a long long time
and that's part of the treatment
because like most Westerners they full of themselves
they think they know they think they understand
they think they know everything
that's why they need to suffer and they need
to exhaust all the resources until they realize
that they're helpless they truly are helpless
then they believe then they listen same thing
in Daniel Daniels hey I have my Catholic I
have my god here I come back to my god when
I'm uncomfortable go back to your god and
ask him to help with your depression and see
what happens don't come to me and pick and
choose when I tell you to do something do
it you don't do it I will not tell you anymore
I have no time to waste Wei Mountain
thank you master, um I'm feeling depressed
because I you know I lost my job and I'm
continuing to look for a job, do you have any
instruction for me?
why you have to feel depressed many people
lost their jobs and they need to look for
a job you don't have to take it personally
it happens
okay that's called being an adult
we find a job we work and we lose it
that's part of professional careers
why should you let that make you depressed
that's normal people have to look for jobs
constantly and even right now it's difficult
to look for a job so be it keep looking and
that's part of cultivation cultivation is
that you keep going no matter how difficult
it is
to feel depressed about the situation is not
necessary of course it's difficult and when
you get after you get a job it's also difficult
now you have the more pressure and you know
and and and a lot more pressure right now
you have no responsibilities put your wife
to work
seize your opportunity you see and that's
that's what cultivation is about you adapt
the circumstances and you don't ever sink
into negative emotions why do you have to
be depressed it's not you they convince you
you should be depressed but you should not
be depressed at all it's just life
professionals will lose their jobs whether
you are CEO or COO Sheryl Sandberg had been a
coo for facebook for a long long time she
lost her jobs she got pushed out Steve Jobs
got pushed out from apple he came back 10
years later you see gloriously okay so it
happens you roll with the punches that's all
it's nothing to be depressed about and life
is about we try our best that's all that's all
we have don't be so attached to results all
we have is try our best that's it
I really appreciate it okay a common
place it's not just you this is this is quite
a common mistake that professionals make okay
I speak from experience I lost my jobs too
I was depressed too I lost my wife I was depressed
too I mean jeez there is plenty of fishes in the
ocean excuse me
you know it's such a common common thing and
it's normal to feel depressed and that's why
one thing you can do is speak out speak up
and say hey this is how I feel whereas us
Asians we try to deny it we pretend we say
I'm tough I'm not depressed
okay and and you sink deeper they sink deeper
that's all
okay speak up and and it helps you become
more humble okay we all have our moments of
weaknesses we all have our vulnerabilities
uh it's okay it's okay to share them don't
be afraid okay you cannot be strong unless
you're vulnerable believe it or not Wei Mountain
master follow-up question so does that mean
Daniel needs to take care of the depressing
ghost in order for him to increase in samadhi
or to maybe take refugee with triple jewel
is possible for him
it means that my hands off it's a Catholic
issue I would not deal I will not venture
into no man's land where uh I can he'll you
agree to go along with me until you disagree
then when I when when that's what your original
plan is then I will not touch you you understand?
it's a waste of my time
because you don't understand
it's like fighting a war dealing depression
is like fighting with a war you don't understand
it's not as simple as uh take a medication
you'll be over and done with no you have to
make moves you have to position your army
fighting one battle after another after another
after another it's not that simple you don't
understand enough and that's why you you're
helpless you're helpless because you don't
know what to do you don't know how difficult
it is to deal with it
it's just like I'm depressed make it disappear
yes it can be done but I told you I make it
disappear from you where is it gonna go your
mother your daughter your wife you want that
okay we stop here today thank you everyone
[Audience clap]