we respectfully request,
the sangha of great virtues
for the sake of this assembly and all living beings
please turn the wonderful dharma wheel to teach and guide us
how to end birth and death
leave suffering and attain bliss
and quickly realize non-birth
恭請大德僧聽，
為此法會及一切眾生，
請轉妙法輪教導我們，
如何了生脫死，離苦得樂，
速證無生。
homage to the blessed, noble and perfectly enlightened one
the unsurpassed profound subtle and wonderful dharma,
in a hundred thousand million eons is difficult to encounter
now that I'm able to see and hear,
I will receive and maintain it,
I vow to fathom the thus come one's true and actual principles
無上甚深微妙法,
百千萬劫難遭遇,
我今見聞得受持,
願解如來真實義
Buddhism Buddhists great master HuiNeng great
master XuanHua, all good monks and nuns and all good
knowing advisers amituofo.
hello everyone today is the 20th of august
2022. we're here to continue discussing the
second chapter of the six page rate track
sutra here on slide 200 he's in the midst
of explaining teaching us about practical
wisdom tragic wisdom refers to again the
supreme wisdom that [Music] [Applause] [Music]
[Applause]
impressive uh several seconds that you have
to hold my breath and tell you about this
ultimate truth here you know wonderful that's
what it says if it's important enough they
come and stop you and and uh distract you
um what was it about again okay so the strategy
wisdom is the kind of wisdom that you supreme
wisdom you have we all have not just the Buddhas
we all have this wisdom and the Buddha realizes
that because of that
all of us can be much better off so he came
to our world and taught us about the spiritual
wisdom here and trained us how to
access it how to activate it and how to manipulate
it okay and so that's um uh the purpose of
this uh this sutra the sutra is the sixth
page taught us about the spiritual wisdom
and this is designed its instructions are
designed to um help us uh connect with that
prajna wisdom and utilize it all right
okay so the context for your context uh the
text says uh let me repeat it for you what
is meant by no thought no thought means to
view all dharma of the mind undefiled by attachment
the function pervades all places but is nowhere
attached okay so he explains that when you
have this project wisdom you when you are
in the state of wisdom your mind is free of
thoughts it's no thoughts okay in contrast
your mind now is constantly filled with thoughts
this is our natural state of mind when we
wake up in the morning we start we we start
thinking and it goes like that thank you it
was like that non-stop until we fall asleep
and we really are uh not trained never learn
how to help go on sit down guys take photo
photo master and the kids smile remember the
smile huh okay
okay so the uh yeah the camera captured already
thank you
so we uh our heads are filled up with thoughts
and we have no way of stopping them okay so
the Buddhist practices are designed to help
us develop this ability to stop thoughts uh
first and then after you are able to stop
your thoughts then you'll be able to wield
this project wisdom access its fracture wisdom
okay suppression wisdom is a little bit more
advanced than no tarts advanced no thoughts
if you will okay um now so what does it mean
no thought no this the way he explains that
mata haeng the sixth page I've explained is
it's so beautiful so practical okay what does
it mean no thought okay you hear about this
quite often from the Chinese literature the
mayan literature is that uh Buddha has no
thoughts and so forth they referring to the
fact that the Buddha when he's in the state
or you're in a state of Buddhahood then your
mind is free of thoughts okay what is if your
mind is free of thoughts how can you live
anyone knows how can you work
is that possible that you have no thoughts
in your mind at all even when you work they
have no thoughts when you eat have no thoughts
you talk you have no thoughts you create you
have no thoughts
you believe is it possible
yes or black
I'm it for I think it's possible because
when we drive I don't think we we have much
talk but we do drive uh properly is that why
you got re-ended by a truck like a couple
years ago
you went into a no-talk thing and boom they
hit you in the rear
were you an old hot state yeah I think I i
i don't think much when I drive that's what
happened you should stop it
anyone else what is no thought here yes green
[Music] master I think that increase the volume
for example when we eat the food entering
our mouth we know that it is good taste it
tastes delicious or not but we don't follow
the thought after to attach to whether I want
it more or not so no attachment to the flavor
in that case I think this is no thought so
for example today at lunch you enjoy the pizza
did you enjoy the pizza anyone
she ate pizza she liked it
and describe your state of no thought
[Laughter] oh [Music]
no translation hello can you hear me
hello Amituofo master um I realized that pizza
this time is very delicious better than many
other times however I only take one piece
i don't take the second piece that's no thought
and how did you decide you not to take a second
slice of pizza
yeah I have no thought at all naturally i
just stop I don't take the second piece how
many slices of pizza do you normally eat
yeah don't take
master normally too
so why today all sun you normally have two
slices of pizza and today only one slice of
pizza how do you explain that the difference
a foreign master at that time it just naturally
in my instant is that way I don't know how
to explain it but it's just natural instance
so for example uh does that mean that in the
event does it also mean that you used to love
your husband twice as much as well now you
love him 50 less naturally [Music]
i don't know how to compare that analogy it's
not about comparison it's about I'm trying
to get you to tell us how you did it you know
you can go from two sizes pizza to one size
visa without doing anything okay okay okay
that's what you say I'm asking you uh does
it also mean you also love your husband one
slice less
without thinking
okay never mind the husband okay let's talk
something more real how about your son your
precious son does that also mean that you
also can love your son 50 less without even
thinking
you think about it here while you were the
green one this question applies to you okay
which is what she's talking about all of a
sudden she says I just decide not to take
it and I don't have to think about it and
does it mean you two can love him less you
know naturally without even thinking I think
so he says don't don't tell him mommy [Laughter]
don't hurt me yeah you you buy into that
all right I don't know the context completely
but no the context never mind okay going back
to the orange one so how do you arrive at
it it's the same process since you don't even
have to think all of a sudden you decide I'm
going to love him less I'm going to eat less
how does it come about
no answer
so that means you stop loving your husband
100 without thinking now this is a lot more
serious than I thought
without thinking you just stop
like you see an accident when you're driving
you say oh I better stop same thing you see
your husband I better stop
how does that work
okay let me explain to you um never mind by
the slice of pizza and the husband that's
too personal let's not talk about it which
is curious that's well that's all but uh we
uh uh uh we gotta let you get off the hook
here for a while uh no thought he mean to
view all dharma with the mind undefiled by
attachment meaning as it says okay here's
what happens when you look at a slice of pizza
yes
okay and you say good pizza or bad pizza something
like that happens naturally yes we all know
we took a bite as oh good pizza
pizza
okay it happens naturally is that clear okay
that is still no thought is that clear your
perception good or bad desire undesirable
and desirable is natural it's still no thought
okay
it's only when after that he says
let's have some red peppers pepper flakes
anyone today I took a slight pizza and flex
what happened to bad foot legs happen to anyone
it's just me just only me huh
why do I feel so lonely I mean am I the only
one with each pizza who expects buffer flex
with my pizza
seriously
okay so that is what he's referring to uh
to view all things all dharmas here's mean
all things look at everything with the mind
okay the mind right there undefined my attachment
if I look at the slice of pizza and I say
good pizza bad pizza it's a fact okay the
mind is perception of the facts we condition
the field is good we condition a few is bad
that's how we train so far so good that's
how we function normally that's still no thought
okay however when the thought arises it says
uh red buffer flakes what happened to the
flakes what happened to the parmigiano cheese
what kind what kind of outfit is this yeah
eat pizza without pepper flakes without parmigiana
cheese okay what what is that called
a mind defiled by attachment to buffer flakes
or parmesan cheese is that clear then is no
longer no thought
so if you have a slice of pizza you say oh
it's good pizza and you eat it okay naturally
it's still no thought but when you have a
thought that arises after it says
i want more cheese
anyone seriously I was the only one
you guys are weird you said are you dishonest
okay uh so that is
to have thought is that clear this is distinction
here is very precise you need to be clear
about this it means that in a state of no
thought doesn't mean you're dead you still
experience flavors to experience the the you
are still able to process the facts properly
but you don't give rise to demands okay or
rejection is that clear he said this is good
pizza that's not hot that's natural a statement
of a fat this is good pizza this is bad pizza
this needs more cheese this needing more cheese
no thought or with thoughts
they have to think [Music] you guys are weird
my god where have you been you are just too
yellow-faced
huh
okay never mind about pizza what about what
about you have some some some stir-fries
okay
and and you eat it and you say more soy sauce
okay is that we thought or without thought
huh
thought
who says thought one two three four five
no no it's not for you it's for the you know
the soy sauce people
[Laughter] you like Chinese food too oh me
too no talk because it's state of fact because
your pellets are used to a certain balance
of flavors right so the food has to be salty
enough for you otherwise you say okay this
is not salty okay it's not hot it's still
not attachment it's a it is a statement of
facts that this dish here is not salty enough
that's a statement of fact it's when you have
thank you
he's tough isn't he he doesn't get startled
that easily okay he has no thoughts
you got that so you see and you see you interact
the world okay that's a natural state of no
thoughts but when you have something like
rejection or like that is thought right he
said I would like another slice of pizza that
is thoughts because it's called thought because
how does the thought arise from something
called
greed
doesn't make sense the pizza just pizza is
good but you were greedy for more flavors
therefore he said I want more that is called
a thought
does it make sense to you
okay that is what it meant here in this sentence
no thought means view okay all dharma everything
with the mind that undefined by attachment
if you see you say oh it's white this is black
this is a pale face this is blackface and
so forth that's a statement of facts there's
no defilement there is no attachment there
just a statement of facts okay but it says
i don't like you I'm out of here okay that
is uh those thoughts arise because of the
three poisons greed anger stupidity then it's
called thought so what is the engine behind
the thought arises that's what differentiate
between what's called heart versus no thought
is that clear that's a distinction that's
a definition
so do not mistake the fact of when we talk
about no thought that you don't have any thoughts
at all in your mind it's not true okay the
thought that arises from the lack of greed
anger stupidity is called no thoughts
so that's why you can still function every
day normally as long as you're not motivated
by greed anger and stupidity then you have
no thoughts
okay so attachment in other words this attachment
word here okay the attachment is formed by
greed anger and stupidity that's all is that
simple
and the way the paycheck put it is very eloquent
very precise but it still causes
misunderstanding okay it's very precise it
says mind undefined by attachment attachment
if you take a step further attachment is created
by greed anger stability that's all does it
help
so when she says I have sliced visa I have
good this is good pizza and I stopped I didn't
take a second slice is that we thought or
without heart
without thought someone says without thought
no thought how about the rest of you
go ahead uh green it depends on why only take
one if she only take one because [Music] the
thoughts of great anger and stupidity that
still saw yes by definition I'm asking you
when she stopped this morning I should stop
this morning
maybe she really wanted but she's like okay
i want to lose weight I i I'm worried about
eating too much then say that I stop here
because I want to lose weight is that we thought
or without thought so we sought with heart
right we agree right I stopped here because
I'm uh overweight no no no
sorry how can we describe her never mind okay
okay so the way she described is that I didn't
think I should stop that is exactly no top
very good applause
see that's how you function naturally you
don't have that so at mo at times you can
do that too a time you say I should stop here
okay uh and and and uh that's called no thought
however however the difference in you in those
states versus her she's that she's constantly
in that state when you stop is good you think
him eating something else
she just stopped is that clear okay and and
how can you tell the difference you cannot
tell that's the problem is it clear this is
what happens the Buddhists by the way the
practices get to the point where they think
they have no thoughts actually they cannot
see that the driving force behind that state
that's all themselves you know fascinating
that's why the the Buddhists even the advanced
practitioners they're mistaken to they can
be mistaken they jumped to conclusions prematurely
so it's not uncommon for people low level
they would think they have no thoughts actually
it's driven by greed anger stupidity
you see how beautiful definition is he says
the mind free from attachment caused by greed
anger stupidity between in parenthesis okay
yes black media for master then I think then
our [Music] our knowledge about Buddhism or
if we we pick up a sutra and we chant through
it or we read through it we can be misunderstanded
because vuonim we are thinking that we have
no no false thinking but actually this this
explanation that the we are not being defiled
by by the attachment by grid anger and stability
so much more accurate yeah I added breathe
anger stability without it you're still confused
so most of us who who who try to study Buddhism
with our teacher without um real really then
we can be we can misunderstand the whole thing
absolutely her colleagues you know the co-cultivator
they have a hundred of them uh practicing
uh together and they all think themselves
having no taught and so forth but actually
uh they're all full of greed anger stupidity
how can they possibly have no thoughts they're
always fighting each other arguing out there
and so forth right so you cannot tell me they
have no no three poisons and yet they say
i have no thoughts
okay and that's a fallacy you don't decide
it to yourself
go ahead way mountain
master I have a question between a rising
a thought was the translation to Vietnamese
as fact or it just say is there a difference
between the two sorry
i have a question in regards to the English
to Vietnamese translation when we say the
thought arise in Vietnamese does it mean that
e or is mean
where the thought arises
um I'm trying to translate to the word that
we have a thought what does that mean in English
yes when we have a thought where the thought
when you're trying to explain that does it
mean in Vietnamese mean papi or it means kind
it means neim koi
thank you master okay
these are important distinctions because there's
certain jargon in Buddhism very precise unless
you know what you're doing you will be mistaken
very easy to translate improperly just like
this morning when I explained to you about
the song enlightenment the translation to
English is incorrect and that causes problems
serious problems okay [Music]
that's okay let them be don't worry don't
worry let that don't be it's okay uh it's
uh it's us too we need to bear with it and
uh we don't let him eat tonight that's all
it's okay don't worry let them be let them
play it's okay because because if it bothers
you what is that called we thought
okay we have to pretend we have no thoughts
okay uh next uh is it clear does it help okay
it is so commonplace for the Buddhist disciples
the Buddhist researchers and to understand
what it means by no thought because it is
very fairly easy to misunderstand this process
why because they had they haven't got there
yet they only read up on things they haven't
got to the state of no thought that's why
they don't know what they're talking about
someone just tell you you reached northart
then ah that's no thought that's when you
know yourself but others still don't know
others have still have no clues okay now you're
saying why some occasionally I said oh you
you are there because because then then you
know I'm telling you that your state is real
it's accurate not your imagination until that
happens until someone tells you you should
not believe yourself period way mountain
master thank you um I'm used to thinking a
lot about pizza but what's a good example
of a thought of stupidity thought of stupidity
uh I'm sorry I can't think of anything stupid
someone help me out daniel give me some example
star stupidity
very good the guy is learning very fast
anyone else would like to tell me an example
of thought of stupidity
you could say I have no more stability
[Music]
master I saw that these people are greedy
for gambling there there's a verse in Vietnamese
saying that the um gambling is the uncle of
the poor so the people who doesn't believe
they just think that these poor people is
their own problem so they just keep playing
in the end they ended up losing everything
so I think that is the example of stupidity
okay exactly yeah that's correct especially
the people who are addicted to the gambling
you know they cannot help themselves okay
it's true it's very good very good example
excellent so thoughts thoughts stupidity are
they in general the thoughts that are
for a general thumb for your reference a thought
for example that denies the connection between
cause and effect
that's stupidity
for example you say
if I steal from someone and she doesn't know
it's no harm is that correct that's called
thought or stupidity just because you're not
caught doesn't mean it's okay and and you
may be laughing but this is how people the
world operate sounds familiar we steal from
the companies we steal from our friends it's
still our own families it's still from our
acquaintances as long as you're not caught
it's not harm done right that's so wrong that
very stupid behavior
and you don't need to be caught you don't
need to be judged uh the fact that that you
steal when you teach someone in the future
you have to pay it back it's a matter of time
you cannot avoid it no one can even Buddhas
cannot avoid it
is that clear it's for everyone so such thoughts
are really really stupid and yet and yet that's
i use how I use the function I use the thing
that you know I can do anything I please and
it's law I'm not caught what's the big deal
okay that sheer stupidity
okay
you see you see and that's that's why that's
why we are exercising not having thoughts
stupidity okay by bearing with all the kids
screaming and throwing things at you
because you have no attachments right
you can do that I don't throw my microphone
okay
okay and last last week we talked about eyes
contemplate sound forms outside there's nothing
inside and we always talk about ears here
the dusts and phenomena mine do not know okay
so we talked about that extensively we're
going to skip that the next the fast the last
sentence the function pervades all places
but is nowhere attached meaning what okay
function here refers to what pervades all
places
function here means
whatever you do to do something is called
function why is it called function function
of your nature your nature is going to do
something okay and that's called function
function is to do is utilized for something
nature decides to eat nature decides to sleep
the nature decides to go to work okay that's
called function the function of the nature
is to produce for eight hours a day at work
okay is that clear that's a function function
of yours being of your self your function
right now is to sit and listen that's a function
your nature yes the function of the kids is
to run around make noises and play because
they're kids okay our function as adult is
to bear with it okay and not complain
all right now so the function pervades all
places meaning that you do that everywhere
but it is nowhere attached and and yet you
can be like that without depending on anything
for example people say I can bear with the
noise and bear the kids running around as
long as master uh allows it sound familiar
okay is that is that considered nowhere attached
the functions I would put up with the noise
i would not flinch okay I will not complain
i will not get afflicted as long as master
tolerates it master says it's okay okay does
that mean in that state there you are nowhere
attached no it doesn't because you are attached
to the fact that I allow it if I didn't allow
you say sit down
right so I'm your attachment and say I don't
know but if he says okay the voice okay so
this funky here that's why I'm training you
that you can be here with without me the kids
can run around make noises and you say okay
make noises see if I care is that clear so
so what is the implication that when you think
about it why do people put on facades why
do people pretend because of attachments right
i said Vietnamese example they said I'm not
going to lose face I'm not you know I'm above
this sounds familiar I'm going to keep my
cool and that is attachment two faces yes
so prashia he have wisdom yeah you don't make
pretenses you don't pretend at all there's
no need to pretend does it make sense so whatever
you do the function pervades all places whatever
you decide to do okay it's not based on pretending
or put on a facade or trying to look good
avoiding looking back and so forth okay no
need for all those
or for monks and nuns we do this so that we
look impressive and people give us more money
more donations sounds familiar okay yeah as
soon as you leave I will put my feet up and
on the table and oh my god such a long day
oh I'm glad now I can relax don't need to
pretend to look you know and sit in full loaders
and look so adorned and cool so tiring
to be like that
okay and so so that's why that's why uh that's
why when you understand this process you don't
need to put on facades you don't need to judge
people actually you feel sorry for the people
who put on facades don't judge them because
they are
latent with attachments they have so many
attachments they need to feel compelled to
put on facades
okay they they are so
seeking people's approval it's sad it's a
set state of mind
you know in particular and I'm I admit to
you particular verse monks and nuns we full
pray to that we need to put our facade for
you I need to look magnanimous generous and
cool and you know I'm always unflustered and
always speak the nice and kind words and smile
to you oh how are you today I'm so glad you're
here
okay yeah and uh and and we are guilty of
that we're guilty of the fact that that we
saw especially amongst the nuns we are so
worried about how we are perceived that we
need to go cultivate this image of being magnanimous
and kind and compassionate and so forth so
we cease to be real okay and you like that
you're doing a disservice to Buddhism you
doing this service to your followers I feel
[Music] okay for the sake of getting more
donations okay so it's funny because uh because
i have been training a lot of monks and nuns
and now and we're going to in the second phase
where I asked them to stand up and say you
know the old monk here should be the front
man for northern California you know he'll
uh people know to come come to the temple
and see him in the face with the uh with the
temples here and so forth and and and so people
ask him can I take your photo to attach a
photo to dharma tertiary temple to go for
his temple he says no leave me alone is that
note heart or with heart
hmm
we thought right because I don't want to take
a photo I don't want my photo taken because
I'd only be known right okay on the surface
is a good thing because they've been trained
too well either they're lazy like me or they
decided they are not going to look for fame
and profit which is a good thing okay so but
why do I say it's we thought
um
Amituofo master I think that it is still a thought
that say I don't want this and this is the
thought of rejection there's still it is still
a thought
that's right he says I don't want recognition
i don't want attention to myself okay that
thought there okay it's a thought because
again because it goes against what
my instruction
basically he says I may agree with master
i may respect him but I'm not looking for
fame a prophet okay whereas my instructions
go and be a representative he says no I'm
gonna do it because I'm not like that
okay yeah so it's called it's called attachment
to the dharma is that clear yes they understand
they're not attached to fame they're not attached
to profit okay it's strong to be attached
to fame it's wrong to be attached to profit
okay that is correct okay however if I say
it's okay and you disagree with me then you're
attaching to the concepts
you understand the subtlety in Buddhism is
called attachment to the dharma the you attach
the concept of no fame no prophet seeking
that's still concept and he's attached to
it if he refuses
doesn't make sense this is a common place
it's a very subtle attachment that unless
i pointed out to him he would not be able
to see it
he's very subtle it's called
attachment to the dharma far tree
and that's what you are have a problem you
don't even know this is your attachment you
don't get it yet
so each level you have your attachments
okay so this function here meaning that you're
able to be like this to work or to be yourself
uh everywhere anywhere in the u.s in canada
in the pure land and so forth but is nowhere
attached that's called practice so when you
have prajna wisdom you can work and behave
and live normally and it's free from any attachments
that's the beauty of prajna wisdom you can
do anything and yet you're not attached at
all
it's called
total freedom
okay and that's practical that's prajna wisdom
and that is again I stress for all of you
who are new here this fashion wisdom here
you have it you just don't know how to use
it that's all and the nature of the teaching
is that we need first to remind you it's yours
it's nothing that you need to develop or build
or invent or create it's inside you bury deep
inside of you that's all I need to dig and
dick or clean and wipe it off until you can
see it then say oh that's mine then you can
use it is it clear it's not something new
at all it's not anything new it's something
you always have and you just need to learn
how to see it so that you can use it you yourself
have to see whether I see it or not is your
irrelevant you have to see yourself
is that clear you all have it by way I need
to emphasize it it's nothing new to you you
have it you just don't know where it is in
a you know manner of speaking he just don't
know where it is that's all he is like an
old person I don't know I put my car keys
master amito for master I remember master
xinhua has a saying that everything is okay
is it because he has attained the function
um function is at ease that is why he's saying
this
that's a state of mind that I cannot explain
to you if I say yes or no it doesn't mean
anything to you what we try to do what I try
to do for you is for you to help you [Music]
enter the state whether I say yes or no to
you just okay
just like to use like okay so the pizza uh
tastes good but you don't really cannot express
more than that and that's the
nature of Buddhist teachings the Buddhist
teaching is that somehow bring you there instruction
bring you therefore you experience it experience
a state of no thoughts the state of freedom
from depression freedom from from attachment
freedom from afflictions okay you have to
answer yourself otherwise it's no way to explain
it to you no way you have to experience it
so Buddhist things Buddhist uh in Buddhism
the emphasis has always been since when the
Buddha first came to our world and started
teaching his disciples the objective has always
been to tell you what you ought to do in order
to experience that
that state called first iana the state called
fifth samadhi that state called fourth stage
aha a state called first ground bodhisattva
it's not meant to this to be described to
you it's meant for you to get there okay that's
our job to bring you there okay and when you're
there okay the Buddha's instruction the Buddha's
description what it is will make sense to
you then until that happens there's no point
telling you about it because you don't know
anything you don't understand it you can yeah
the words make sense to you but it's not about
words it's about whether you can do it or
not
that's why masha shinhoa my late Chinese teacher
is the only monk I know who stressed that
he stressed giving us instructions how to
be there to get there instead of giving us
knowledge on what it's about he says you know
the the monks who don't know they read from
the books and they said okay the production
is this is that it's no thought the function
pervades all places there is nowhere attached
it's from the the text okay is it obvious
isn't it and they you ask them what is no
target well that's what this is what the Buddha
says north heart is uh look at all dharma
with uh my undefined attachment what's not
clear to you and this happens everywhere all
places and uh but it's nowhere attached what's
not clear to you is it's it's great English
to me
and that's what happens to Buddhism nowadays
amongst the nuns especially I met a lot of
bontes from sri lanka from from thailand so
forth and and they they keep on and especially
professors they keep on bringing up these
words from sutras when I look at them so you
don't even know what you're talking about
and that's why that's what was the comment
we made earlier is very important it sounds
casual but it's very important in that all
these sutras here are the general principles
to describe to you that state but I cannot
describe everything because you won't be able
to understand everything therefore we explain
to you this state there like in this slide
198 and then people like marsha shinhua will
have to come and teach you how to cross your
legs how to meditate how to how to listen
to suture lectures and how to uh be a nicer
person a kind of person so forth until you're
able to experience it yourself
it's not meant for you to understand you have
to experience it and so the instructions from
the monks and nuns are designed to push you
and push you and push you and push you until
you get there
so each monk and none has their own ways of
pushing you and masha xinhua one of the best
I've seen only surpassed by this sixth major
in my personal experience not so
okay yeah questions or comments
okay tool one that is a prasha samadhi in
freedom and liberation and is called the practice
of no thought
borders
okay very good so he says he went through
a lot of explanation he says this brazilian
here is it's brazilian or your transcendental
wisdom is a form of samadhi in other words
when you enter this project somebody your
branch wisdom is operational naturally you
don't have to do things so that's what happened
to these advanced being they can enter this
rashnya samadhi and naturally they'll the
wisdom comes to the fore that's all it functions
with how anywhere attached okay and that's
freedom uh it's not freedom but self mastery
okay can you change it the English translation
is like made a long time ago and they didn't
quite have the vocabulary that we agreed to
nowadays suicide is not it's not freedom okay
suicide here is called self-mastery at ease
it has nothing to do with freedom freedom
is American
or
Chinese like to think it's freedom but actually
it's American it's a Chinese it's suicide
okay Chinese self-mastery it's not freedom
American is freedom what about hispanics what
is your
danielle is too busy translating
okay so it's self-mastery it's called cell
mastery because you are under no influence
outside influence
okay
okay very good
when you are in this state of mind which by
the way it's something that you can flip at
this stage here you can flip into a confused
state like us and you flip it and go into
practice just like that
what about Buddhas do they flip no Buddha
is always in pressure that's why they call
Buddhas we're not Buddhas that's why we're
not that's who we are okay you can click i
I'm always there forget it wishful thinking
we are different Buddhas in that we cannot
always be there we because
karmic retribution
okay when we're not there we suffer we're
miserable we are making mistakes when you
like the Buddha you stop making mistakes you
stop creating offenses okay if you're not
Buddhas you will continue to create offenses
you can't help it that's who we are yes you're
very special but you create offenses left
and right
okay so you're on this the end of this rashima
but remember these people these like the bodhisattvas
they can flip the switch just like that and
we while we cannot we don't have that ability
they can they can flip once a moment they
confuse flip they enter the sparse you think
it's kind of cool okay and when you're there
you're there then you have self-mastery so
mastery refers to the fact that you [Music]
inside you at peace okay
you're at peace with yourself you don't think
yourself as short if someone calls you shorty
you say yeah
someone bullies you is it okay
you're not affected okay so inside cell mastery
has two parts one part is internally you are
you are totally cool unafflicted okay and
outside the outside part self mastery is that
you are at ease everywhere you are no matter
what happens an earthquake happens as a fire
happens too hot anyone okay you still
that's for self-mastery no matter what happens
outside you as cool as a cucumber
okay how about liberation liberation refers
to the fact that what we we like to deny for
us ordinary people we deny what what do we
deny what what kind of denial are we practicing
anyone
what are we denying
this is a biggie you don't see this are you
in trouble
malcolm what are you denying
the existence of god existence of myself
yourself
he doesn't know what he's talking about he's
in denial anyone else what are you denying
anyone this is so fundamental yes sir
use sign language black
in denial of we are in a confused state we
have [Music] thoughts of
greed and anger and stupidity okay we deny
this is what happens to us we deny that we
are suffering
deep down in our psyche and say I'm not suffering
I'm happy and in hell it's bad but I still
happy my life I love my wife
and of course the wife don't believe it ask
them and say no he doesn't don't I don't believe
him you shouldn't either
no
okay so uh your denial that we are suffering
therefore uh when you just enter this we have
this practice samadhi you are liberated from
your own suffering your own misery
okay so for example let's talk about something
real specific real practical let's say you
have depression anyone have depression daniel
okay anyone else just me and daniel okay a
few people oh it turns out a lot more than
people would like to admit they're all denial
those who didn't raise their hands are all
practicing denial okay
so um [Music] so here's what happens let me
let let me tell you this so that you understand
uh the connection between that and and the
spiritual practice okay let's say you're depressed
okay never mind don't raise your hands I don't
don't bother I know you're depressed please
please but experience you you okay okay so
let's say you're depressed okay yeah you you're
feeling depressed what can you do nothing
right not much you can do it's all I'm not
feel good I don't feel good okay if you have
disprajna wisdom you realize you're depressed
what happens flip no more depression instantaneously
that's called liberation from depression
sounds good wouldn't that be cool to be able
to do john can train you to do that that's
a great news okay but then that woman there
says but I want money right now
okay no promises I heard too many promises
from my husband already
okay so can you give me something real liberation
okay
actually occurs at many many levels not just
at practice level at low levels you liberate
from certain types of depression as you improve
the next level there you are even less inclined
to be depressed about certain things your
wife leaves you next
that's liberation from your wife
and the girls are giggling and saying yeah
good luck [Laughter] wishful thinking
okay so that's what happens when you enter
when you improve in Chan meditation your
depression becomes more and more manageable
so you don't need to be all they have all
the way to the level of creative wisdom where
all depression stopped 100 but as you improve
in your meditation practice your depression
gets lighter and lighter and lighter and lighter
and lighter until zero so there's a progression
naturally there's hope think about it that's
a great news without any medication without
any counseling it's like dui do it yourself
type of treatment
they don't have applause signs here do they
too late yeah
it's called the practice of no thought okay
and that's that's what this thing is so the
reason I'm telling you is that there actually
is a lot of hope for many of you are suffering
all sorts of mental illnesses in particular
okay this is the solution this is the the
cure for them all meditation
for mental illnesses yeah cool and that's
the only to fix them the only way to fix them
is through meditation not with chemicals with
counseling because counseling is on and off
you cannot turn it off whereas meditation
you can turn it off by entering into somali
you turn up a certain pain and suffering and
then next level of somali even more even less
pain and suffering until zero pain and suffering
whatsoever
that's the big picture the clarity of mind
comes from not being affected by your own
pain and suffering
we confused because we can't handle it
it behaves this
way mount
master uh what about the sense of guilt i
was recently attacked two times for this problem
was it a depression or
something what at what level can we be able
to deal with this issue better could you repeat
the question please
um sense of guilt it is a kind of depression
at what level can we deal with it better
the sense of cue guilty
I'm torturing her and tormenting her
so a sense of cue
yeah being cute yeah they're cute and I looked
up google cute uh I cannot find it
so the question is the acute is that depression
or something else right
yes and at what level can we deal with it
better what level can you do with it better
and go into prajna samadhi and you can
deal with zero guilt
below below that you always have little guilt
which is very healthy for you
how else are we going to control you
and you expect me to teach you how to be free
from out control
ah you find out it's amazing these people
tell me when I'm gonna happen they're not
excited at all about the fact they can be
eventually free of guilt or cue but they said
tell me when and what level are we talking
about and instead of saying I want to go there
i want to get there no they say tell me where
where I can handle it
you understand you always want to know instead
of getting so excited that tell me what to
do how do I get there you say uh where is
that level
you are so worldly okay next two or three
not thinking of the hundred things and constantly
causing your thought to be cut off is called
dharma bondage and is an extremist view
okay two or four oh this is juicy I'm gonna
have a good time now are you are you all set
are you ready now to be tormented yeah yeah
yeah okay not thinking 100 things okay okay
remember we he just explained about no thoughts
right you look at things and and and and there's
no thoughts that arises at all now he says
he specifically says not thinking a hundred
things and constantly causing a thought to
be cut off is called dharma bondage
what does it mean that is an extremist view
what does it mean it is very very critical
for you to understand this and this is the
difference between Buddhist wisdom and ordinary
people
if you don't understand this that's ordinary
people you can call yourself Buddhist disciples
you can sell bodhisattvas and so forth okay
you still
or not
what is it
anyone can can you almost explain to us can
massachee explain this to us to and his uh
Korean followers let's give the Korean a chance
uh let's give uh uh light blue thank you
foreign
[Music]
if the thought make us attach expect that
we don't want it to attach to the freedom
um to the liberation of the thought itself
doesn't mean that you are being bondaged you
are bound by the thought of yourself instead
when the thought arise you don't get afflicted
because of that thought then that is freedom
from the dharma bondage if you are still expect
the thought to be suppressed or cut off the
thought that it won't uh afflicting us then
you're still being bound by the thought of
yourself
massive
he's gonna say I agree
we arbits hang together we stand together
the brotherhood of habits
what's that let me talk about that now what
do you say
i don't have any talk about that now
okay god these guys there's just so many tricks
i did a [ __ ] don't believe him okay he
has to think you know the proof is that i
don't have any thought about it it should
come out right away it's fake
jumi is it clear you saw him right you watch
him he said no I don't have to thought about
it
he's cheating okay don't believe him yes orange
here I hear the [ __ ] yesterday and today's
uh
amit of a master um back in the day I know
that there's a group of cultivations they
specialize in um uh non uh sad renouncing
the false thought and every time the false
start arrives they just keep renouncing the
thoughts and I think it creating a discrimination
is that they trying to look for the uh true
they're trying to look for the truth and they
keep renouncing the false thought so I think
that they're still having an attachment endowment
bondage about that because they keep continuing
continuing renouncing the false thought okay
very good you see I have to ask you because
I'm really baffled why the master shanghai
disciples didn't ask him at all his explanation
is one of the best in the marketplace in the
world for this sutra but the sutra is very
very precise it's very very good it is so
helpful for the cultivation I don't know why
they didn't ask for details what is meant
here and the proof is that he cannot explain
masters he pretended not to understand this
woman here uh is complaining and so forth
okay
but what he's saying is here's what he's talking
about and this is a proof to you that the
Buddha talked about these big principles that
very few people understand then the pay charts
came and said okay this is what he meant and
then this is what the sixth wage trial said
and still with this my proof to you is that
now you get it right you see Buddha's level
we don't get it of course it's a Buddhist
level and the sixth paycheck says I'm here
to explain things to you and we still don't
get it
now we're talking about low level okay let
me explain to you here's what happens to you
and the reason they didn't ask because they
don't know this is happening the undercurrent
happening to you and you don't realize it
is that clear okay unless you know exactly
what is the trigger of all these things happening
you will not be able to fix it agree you don't
know if you don't know the cause of all these
problems you have how are you going to fix
your problems
oop sorry time is up
okay okay okay I will not taught her to torture
you anymore okay not thinking 100 things and
constantly causing your thought to be cut
off it's called diamond bondage he's referring
this fact that people like her okay uh
like him sometimes like master Z sometimes
here's what happens to them okay they know
they're not supposed to have thoughts but
they keep on rising so what happened is that
i have ability to cut them off I've been trained
to cut them off she can cut them off he could
cut him off the fake monk in Korea can cut
them off okay they can't they develop an ability
already
they've been trained it's not about you anymore
I'm talking about a high level okay that they
they they can cut off these thoughts okay
at will
he can do better than she can for example
okay and mass is even better so what happened
is they can cut them off and what happened
is that when they realize they have these
thoughts arise they cut them off then the
great master says it's called dharma bondage
so they them piss themselves and say oh oops
I'm not supposed to be attached to this I'm
not supposed to have this thought thought
be gone done and next time it happens again
chop it again so what are they doing they
trimming the trees like the old monk does
every now and then he goes to the side here
and trim the trees in front of the stop sign
otherwise the city gives us a ticket
and you think it's funny but that's what we
do you see it's very practical if it's not
desirable trim it off right if the thought
is not desirable trim it off
what's wrong with that it's called dharma
bondage beautiful
I'm helping you appreciate that don't think
you understand everything there's many levels
of understanding these dharmas
so unless you practice unless you have people
like him and like the one in Korea and so
forth I would not bother explaining this to
you
okay so it's called dharma bondage it's an
extremist view meaning they are subject to
it as well and they don't realize it and the
master master HuiNeng the sixth wave track says
boy are you in trouble you have extremist
views and you don't even know and you hide
it behind your monk's frock
that's what happens when you realize in principle
you're not supposed to have thoughts those
sides are thoughts and these people are trained
to cut them off so they say that keep on cutting
you know cut cutting my cut and cutting off
and the sixth patriarch says it's wrong to
do that it's called dharma bondage it's called
extremist view just because you know the thoughts
are are not supposed to happen that happen
you cut them off it's still wrong it should
be a temporary fix not a long-term fix if
you don't fix it then it's called dharma bondage
you why is it called dharma bondage you are
bound by cutting off thoughts
you know fascinating they think is they supposed
to do that
they know they're supposed to do that and
they keep on doing that and they are dead
in the tracks this is the only thing that
hurts them the master says I don't care you
got a mock good for you but what it does is
that yes it frees you it also
bind you put you in shackles
so what do you want do you want me to train
them people you to tell people hey I have
no thoughts sure I i swear to you okay as
soon as the thought arises nice pizza [Music]
[Laughter]
[Music] that's called dharma bondage
is it clear to you and life unless I explain
it to you you wouldn't know what I'm talking
about nor do they
that's folks this is how precise we are when
we look at your mind how it functions we know
that's what happens he knows what happens
in a fantastic name a psychologist named a
neural uh whatever researcher who can describe
this is this level of details they have graphs
they have mri scans they have colors they
have red red blue and all sorts but you know
hues of one billion different uh hues but
they lack this kind of accuracy
because unless you know what really is happening
inside your little head
you'll never be able to fix it
questions comments yes even microphone move
closer
uh I made it for master so so this is what
he does is I said move closer it cuts off
that thought no I ain't moving closer
yes I mean for master so so in real life uh
as well as in the um meditation hall the when
foss come up we just ignore it or just let
it be we don't need to do anything but from
the teaching from exactly
so when I first started teaching I learned
meditation learning meditation one of the
big disciples masha sheikhoun says as taught
by the Chinese China as well is that when
the thought arises use of our trustworth and
drop off nip it okay much sure even thought
that as well they all they all repeat the
same thing at the Chinese paycheck including
my shanghai or did that I also had that said
that in my childhood book okay and that's
fine but at the advanced level it is extremely
detrimental to their practice
so China book number five I will start discussing
this we are channel handbook number two
okay I will not the bottom line is that you
probably don't know how to ask but the bottom
line is I'm not telling you how to fix it
none your business
okay because what happens we explain too much
to you like that woman who asked which level
I'm going to be before I'm free that's why
i explained to you so and say master I just
do this it's not a big deal
it's not knowledge it's about can you do it
don't say don't tell me I know I know I know
don't tell me I know I know I feel guilty
just tell me when I'm gonna be free of it
okay next 205 yeah a few more minutes should
we continue just see how detailed that knowledge
of john really is you don't know how to navigate
through a lot of these things you see it's
incredible the precision and detail level
that that this Chan teacher can provide us
and this is why these are important you may
not know you may not be able to do it but
in the future when you're there I can tell
you ah remember this section that's where
you are and you say ah now I can do it okay
it takes that that's why uh boys and girls
especially people to the spies who stop asking
me which level I'm going to be free at that
bro up that okay I told you it really means
nothing it doesn't help you at all that's
why I don't tell you 205 good knowing advisors
one who awakens to the no thought dharma completely
penetrates the ten thousand dharmas one who
awakens with no talk dharma sees all Buddhist
realms one who awakens through no thought
dharma arrives at the Buddha position
one
okay it's very very good okay uh I i admit
to you that I didn't appreciate this as much
when I first explained this section uh three
four years ago four years ago because I uh
started with this mind the frame of mind says
i only need to explain it to the extent of
my chair I explained and that's good enough
so never the adventure out of what he did
not want to explain I'm telling you that it's
not something that that that he doesn't understand
he understands is probably better than I do
most likely better than I do because he decided
not to explain it why not because it's his
disciples weren't ready
okay so he says here uh when you understand
this no thought dharma this practice of no
thoughts that we've been trying to explain
to you completely penetrate the ten thousand
dharmas means that what is completely penetrated
ten thousand dharma ten thousand dharma refers
to ten thousand things what are the ten thousand
things ten thousand things to the indians
to the Chinese is everything they don't have
a number like gazillion like we do nowadays
okay they only have ten thousand and beyond
ten thousand oh this is too much okay so they
completely penetrate the ten thousand dharma
everything what is completely penetrate everything
meaning that you see through everything you're
not attached to anything
okay yeah so uh when you uh what does it mean
awakens in no thought dharma
huh
foreign
[Music]
by the way it's not depression
depression was this morning this is something
else
but I let him torture her for a while
translation a myth of a master during the
time that I entered the retreat I read um
flour a dormant sutra it is said this a thousand
dharma doesn't have its own self if you understand
this then your dharma eyes is inconceivable
meaning if you understand this way it this
way your dharma eyes is inconceivable
okay no
stick to this
it has no the reference that doesn't doesn't
apply here what he's talking about is the
person whoever awakens the no thought dharma
what does it mean awaken the no thought dharma
meaning that you say ah I can do it that's
what awakens I'm awake it's no longer a dream
to me now I'm awake okay you suddenly realize
that whatever you saw before now is was just
a dream was not real and when you are able
to uh completely have no thought okay and
you're capable of having no thought okay you'll
be able to completely penetrate the ten thousand
dharmas you can see through the ten thousand
dharmas you are not attached to anything whatsoever
fame profit
nothing whatsoever
is that clear that person then sees all Buddha
realms now we're talking about a state of
Buddha
okay this is quite different who we are where
we are
you have this is a special being a special
state of mind that again says remember one
who awakens to meaning when you awaken to
it when she awakens it when he awakens it
you can all do that
the assumption here the suggestion here is
very important do not stop yourself don't
say no it's not for me no it's too far-fetched
no it's too yellow-faced
is that clear this is such an important distinction
don't say that no it's too far-fetched for
me
this is certain dharma certain teaching meaning
that if you don't stop yourself because i
can tell you all I want but inside yourself
say yeah it sounds good but I'm not sure i
can do it
i know you traders especially the guy in Korea
he says I don't think I can do it but he said
let me think
okay
got that the reason that you can't do it you
cannot awaken to because you really don't
trust yourself you don't have faith in yourself
you really don't think deep down you don't
think you can do it like that lady who just
came today and said yeah right I'm the Buddha
i have the Buddha in me yeah right
right that's what you go through your head
yeah yeah these people yeah you know they
believe anything these Asian faced
doubt is what stops you
they don't see the Buddha realms meaning what
the Buddha describes us this is what the six-page
chart describes us they cannot see it and
if you can see the uh you're able to to awaken
the no taught dharma you arrive at the Buddha
position you become a Buddha
okay he's talking about not enlightenment
you're talking about Buddha now
still have some time shall we get going
why you've been busy too you know the the
the children huh oh wow all right 207 in this
way it should be transmitted from generation
generation is silently transmitted and conferred
more transfer
in
this way it should be transmitted he says
we should help in what way
what way is he referring to it should be transmitted
in what way
um
Chinese person you have a problem with translation
or not what should I call you Taiwanese
ranchi chuansho
is a translation
correct hmm
is it you agree Chinese uh uh Chinese speaking
people you agree with in this way as a ranch
you try and show it should be transmitted
or not
uh
hmm
people
what does it mean
come on
plus
hmm
Chinese specialist I just looked up my Chinese
dictionary
huh anyone see the Chinese are cautious he
said if I say anything I claim a Chinese expert
he's going to jump on me again
too bad that it's like early in China what
time is it in China
5 30 in the morning on
sunday good lord who gets up that early on
sunday not in China okay so what does it mean
okay
sorry
i think it means still needs to be transmitted
signature transmitted anyone else
huh
okay it should not say in this way because
in this way here is confusing in what way
did he say you should tell them so and so
no you should be transmitted
accurately
he's more concerned about making sure that
you teach the next generation properly instead
of doing it this way does it make sense he
says when you teach this do it right convey
the message right don't do it this way he
never meant this way this way is ordinary
people thinking his concern primarily is convey
it accurately convey it properly does it make
sense have one Chinese person who agrees what
about the Taiwanese
okay so I don't know how to translate it it
should be appropriately transmitted properly
transmitted but not in this way in this way
is wrong to me this can is not his intention
at all because when a teacher teaches you
something it's for your own understanding
it's up to you to do whatever you want with
it the teacher never expects you to do the
same exact same thing okay as the way he did
that's why I'm very offended when people do
all they do is regurgitate you know my teacher
says my teacher says that okay if you're stupid
yeah I agree he said I don't have any wisdom
therefore my teacher says so okay but if that
is the case then you didn't understand the
teacher this would be so disappointing the
sick patriarchs I spend so much you know time
explaining to you the sutra and you simply
repeat what I said seriously
why did I come here I could have you know
my mind was sent send a an android a robot
over
okay it should be
probably transmitted how is it fix it from
generation to generation
hey
or you can ask of course goran okay of course
you must transmit it this must be transmitted
but that's that's too familiar I should say
the emphasis here I'm interpreting a little
bit differently I said it should be appropriately
properly transmitted because of his importance
not just for uh for us Asians also to the
non-Asians to the Americans to the hispanics
to you know and so forth properly transmitted
for future generation generation generation
meaning that it's your responsibility if you
understand it you must transmit it
that's implied it's very heavy responsibility
okay so far the first two you agree with that
right uh you would like me to get out okay
refresh so far so good it affects us folks
it's not about them Chinese anymore it's about
us future you know this generation and your
children's generation your nieces generation
it affects them we don't do it right okay
we're failing our mission
okay silently transmitted and conferred mo
okay
silently meaning this transmission here is
mind to mind meaning that a certified the
teacher says yes you understand yes you understand
and has nothing to do with anyone else it's
person to person mind to mind that's it it's
not meant for you come up here huh would you
turn on the cameras please okay and report
the whole world that I confer this to him
and we appreciate your support and donations
we planned new maha stupa half a billion dollars
uh uh uh uh uh uh uh easy so it's the opportunity
for us to
raise awareness of the importance of the dharma
okay because it's useful for you and your
future generation think about your children
you don't get it how about your children okay
not that it's silently transmitted it's very
quiet it's no big deal okay it's it's a certification
and conferred confirmed meaning it's given
the responsibility if you understand that
it's transmitted to you now you have the responsibility
to transmit it to others you don't hide you
don't say ah I don't have to do this if it's
given to you it's conferred upon you you have
the responsibility to pass it on properly
silently and convert to next generation
i don't get it we parents when you're a parent
you worry about your children you want to
take care of them you want to educate them
properly yes having a good good education
and and uh good nutrition and so forth okay
make sure that before you let her out you
teach her about
money management
you know that the kids when they go to college
and they get out of the house they have no
idea they don't take care of their health
they don't worry about their diet don't worry
about the finances they keep on spending money
okay do you see it takes responsibility before
we spring them loose they need to be prepared
same thing here for these people this paycheck
it says I'm confirmed give me a silent uh
conferring of this knowledge here this transmission
here now it's your turn to do it as well
you yourself have to live with it
right because your kids fail and blow up the
budget and ruin the healthy because you didn't
prepare them properly
anyway um and so uh this is the responsibility
to make sure that we pass on our knowledge
to the future generation that's called love
that's called caring it's not money
alone money helps
unless you want to give them to the temple
okay time is up thank you everyone
[Music]
better
uh
because the boy