foreign
you
[Music]
we respectfully request the sunger graver
truth for the sake of disassembly and all
living beings please turn the wonderful dharma
will to teach and guide us how can birth and
death leave suffering
[Music]
oh
the blessed noble and perfectly enlightened
one
the unsurpassed profound subtle and wonderful
dharma in a hundred thousand million neons
is difficult to encounter now that I'm able
to see in here I will receive and maintain
it I vow to fathom the dust come one's true
and actual principles [Music]
[Music]
for
hello everyone today is the 13th of august
2022. we are gathered here to continue discussing
the sixth patriarch sutra we on slide 191 chapter
2. it talks about Russia this Buddhist wisdom
that we all are endowed with and were are
learning how to unveil it and wield it for
ourselves suit the text if you give rise a
genuine practicing contemplation illumination
in a kasana all false thoughts are extinguished
if you recognize yourself nature in a single
moment of enlightenment you will arrive at
the stage of a Buddha
guantanadine
okay uh not sure why we have a highlighted
bora guan chao okay but translation is is
okay um the debate track says if you give
rise to genuine press and contemplation illumination
in a kasana all false thoughts are extinguished
okay what is he talking about he's talking
about the fact that if you're able to use
your prajna wisdom okay what for the prajna
wisdom is for two purposes to contemplate
and to illuminate
what does it mean using your prajna wisdom
whatever Buddha wisdom you have you already
have okay now you don't know what it is you
don't know where it is but you have it already
okay you're we all like having this priceless
pearl our parents sewn up in our clothing our
parents gave us and we are not aware of what
it is we don't know where it is we just know
there is some something precious priceless
okay that we are so wealthy we're so rich
and yet worldly people they seek outside instead
of looking at themselves look at their own
treasure they go outside looking for treasure
from the outside in terms of treasure island
in terms of fort knox okay in terms of gold
ingots in terms of mining the precious metals
especially nowadays you know when you have
rare earth metals you are very very wealthy
and so you know what rare earth metals are
for to make EV batteries without those ingredients
those raw materials you can not make EV uh
EV batteries for example an ounce of gold
is two thousand dollars an ounce of rare earth
element I forgot the element name is worth
how much
Billy how much is rare with this one this
one rare earth element give me a number
use your imagination
give a hint hey hey tick-tock girl give a
hint to your dad don't give it to me
what did she say
see he defers to his precious daughter how
much
10 ten dollars
is it ten dollars ten what
ten what huh let's see how good is her arithmetic
how far can she count
10 what
oh no she just says 10 because she only had
10 figures
oh I asked her is it 10 she said yeah yeah
okay close enough it's more than ten thousand
it's fifteen thousand dollars a pound
i mean an ounce I'm sorry an ounce is fifteen
thousand gold an ounce of gold is 2 000.
because what they call a rare earth elements
anyway we're not talking about money here
talking about something a lot more precious
than money so see you have this prajna wisdom
which is priceless okay and no money uh in
this world is enough to pay for it okay and
yet you own it okay so it's called your genuine
prajna wisdom and what you just do this
who uses wisdom for to contemplate and illuminate
okay so the translation is correct it's a
good translation okay you use your genuine
wisdom inherent wisdom you already have your
prajna wisdom your Buddha wisdom you will
okay to contemplate and illuminate that's
the nature of prajna wisdom to contemplate
to illuminate
okay why contemplate why illuminate?
this is how you use the prajna wisdom you
have to contemplate okay so it means to contemplate
is that you focus single-mindedly on something
is to contemplate is it clear so for example
you think of let's say what happened to all
the boys they're all helping carry some display
cases and now they all disappear
we lost some only A-Hung and Francis came
back because they had to work well I thought
of taking the afternoon off I was pooped i
only used one arm if someone forced me and
said master you're the master you can only
use one finger and say okay I ended up using
one arm I'm really exhausted imagine I use
two arms I'm pretty probably have to lecture
lying down
anyway so we lost all the strong men only
the weak men are here
okay so your prajna wisdom your wisdom
uh in order to use your prajna wisdom what
you do you need to contemplate contemplate
means that let me see you see what I mean
that's contemplation right there let me look
that's what you do you naturally contemplate
when you must notice that
okay and let's say you remember me and say
let me see
familiar okay so that's contemplation right
there let me see I mean let me focus
that is contemplate at the exclusion of everything
else is that clear so you to contemplate is
to look at something single-mindedly at exclusion
of everything else that's what definition
of contemplation I don't care wherever you
go whether it's Hinayana non-Buddhist it's
the same thing contemplate is to do that that's
why when we teach you time we teach you to
hone and increase your contemplation skills
is that clear and when you contemplate okay
then you also illuminate that's practical
wisdom prajna wisdom is to be able to focus
single-mindedly this is why Mahayana we teach
you Chan and we stress the concept of being
single-minded we don't stress mindfulness
and all those things that other people teach
because that will not bring your prajna wisdom
will not activate your prajna wisdom is
that clear in order for your prajna wisdom
to be activated you need to be signal-minded
not mindful
is it clear you can be totally unmindful but
as soon you need to you single-mindedly look
at something that's your prajna wisdom in
action no mindfulness crap
no smiling no hugging trees
is that clear what all those things do the
smiling hugging trees is for fun for the Kodak
moment
something odd okay
oh weird okay so the contemplate to contemplate
is being single-minded is that clear? single-minded
and when you are single-mindedly use it and
you have your prajna wisdom your prajna
wisdom will naturally shine light upon what
you're contemplating okay that's why when
you have prajna wisdom is always two things
you contemplate and illuminate as a result
of your contemplating
is it clear now the question is why didn't
the great teacher say if you contemplate
and forget about illumination or how about
just use if you use genuine prajna to illuminate
and forget about contemplation why has to
be Guan Zhao not just Guan or Zhao she might
understand the nature of my question the question
here is you have contemplation and illumination
why not just either one of the two
why not yes nine from Diego when you contemplate
you see the dark spots when you illuminate
you dissolve that darkness
okay
so so what he's saying is that you
contemplate alone you still have some blind
spots some spots you things you cannot see
that's why you need to illuminate what about
if you illuminate alone you shine a bright
light on everything why did you contemplate
the only answer half give half of the answer
what about the other half of the question
can't you simply illuminate and forget about
contemplation
hello everyone anybody out there
oh it's just another break in the wall
never mind you guys are so unmusical yes six
hello sorry about that um geez what was what
was it about oh um contemplation sorry uh
you have to contemplate because then you're
you're focusing on the item not just illuminating
and why can't simply illuminate and forget
about contemplation
you are not answering the question I don't know
you don't know is the answer okay
nine from Alta-D contemplation makes the illumination
specific
okay he's touching somewhere close enough
from Diego both go together contemplation
will show you a single-minded view of what's
contemplated illumination will give you a
deeper view of the object then both grow exponentially
together it's hard to explain with words master
when you don't get it you cannot explain what
words you don't you you don't still don't
understand
okay you need to contemplate illuminate number
one your contemplate and without illumination
then you still have some dark areas you cannot
see clearly so you need to illuminate so what
happens is when you contemplate your prajna
wisdom also illuminates naturally okay so
far so good however what if you only illuminate
forget about the contemplation illuminating
is like you turn on bright lights everywhere
but you really lack focus you really don't
understand the details of the depth you lack
the details and the depth of concentration
or contemplation okay just like tell me what
you see and you you write a whole essay instead
of all they want you to focus on is one single
point you him that's it okay so you need contemplation
to provide focus to provide a focal point
okay otherwise you become scattered illuminate
alone is not enough so far so good next 93
uh commentary if you recognize yourself nature
then okay sorry we're not done yet in a kasana
all false thoughts are extinguished okay this
is the secret people keep on asking me when
they learn they came and learn uh came to
our Chan classes or they came to our pureland
training session they said master I recite
the Buddha's name but I still have a lot of
thoughts they come in between or people would
say master I've been meditating for a year
now and for for two months now I still I'm
discovering that my head is full of thoughts
i keep on thinking and thinking and thinking
i ask only during or during meditation he
says come and think of it I'm like that all
day long not just during meditation I said
bingo okay so that's what happens your
our heads are full of false thoughts okay
false thoughts refers to the the thinking or
the thoughts that arise naturally in spite
of ourselves the will arise
okay and just like what are them are they
it's take look at it this way when we talk
about false thoughts it's like you're sitting
here and all of a sudden your neighbors turns
on the music okay you have no control over
it that's the nature of false thoughts they
hit they get into your head and you cannot
help yourself
okay now so therefore the two kinds of false
thoughts one that not that's involuntary meaning
is not your fault and number two is voluntary
is that clear the two kinds of false thoughts
the Chan people don't teach you that I'm I'm
dissecting it for you the false thoughts there
are one is uh involuntary okay the other is
voluntary meaning involuntary meaning that you
did not generate the false thoughts okay not
intentionally okay and voluntary is intentional
you think about it you involuntary meaning
you didn't think about it they just pop into
your heads
and voluntarily is that you actually consciously
are thinking about that generating those thoughts
that's the nature of your false thinking and
your false thoughts
okay there's a question in the back too
master, I
have a question when when you talk about false
thought is that that the mind um Pan Yuan
um climbing on conditions climbing on the
condition or the mind itself generated the
false thought
that's why I just talked about voluntary and
involuntary I don't need to use big words
anyone else anyone else has an idea or some
comments or suggestions okay okay now the
two false thoughts are involuntary or voluntary
involuntary is that you had nothing to do
with it it just came in to your head somehow
shows up in your head like that music right
there in your neighbor or the car noise right
there the drive-by and the noise is perceived
by you you didn't do anything it just came
to you it's called involuntary so the thoughts
come to you in a involuntarily that without
you doing anything so far so good okay
so for example you sit there all sun a thought
arises it says Gelato!
ever happened today
i don't know about gelato but one thought
that comes to mind yesterday afternoon
watermelon
no well it's so hot you know when it so hot
so when I was younger I was so hot I said
the ocean
okay because I used to live by the ocean okay
so those come naturally okay you don't even
you don't even think they just came okay and
that's called even involuntary and then after
the involuntary thought then you
say oh yeah gelato bulgarinis not just any
gelato because many gelato we find shops out
there in southern california are fakes they
they call themselves gelato but actually it's
not really true gelato gelato gelato if i
may give you a very short lesson on gelatos
okay it's condensed ice cream it's uh flavor
is more intense than ice cream it's a hell
a lot more expensive oh excuse me boys and
girls and it's a lot more expensive than ice
cream you can tell right away okay ice cream
scoop is like four or five dollars gelato
is twice as much
anyone thinking of gelato [Laughter] see what
i mean okay so they come to you naturally
okay uh okay not of your doing okay that's
called involuntary but for me it's voluntary
because I'm thinking of it you see that that's
what happens the thought comes you it arises
naturally and you follow the thought that's
called voluntary thinking you chase after
it so Chan meditation is you look at the
involvement involuntary thoughts and not chase
after them that's all
what happens to ordinary people is that they
cannot discern the difference between involuntary
thoughts and voluntary thoughts so to them
they're all the same
okay in particular especially for those some
of you present today who are depressed severely
depressed you wake up in the morning within one
minute you have a thought that arises immediately
it says I don't feel good
I'm speak from speaking from experience boys
and girls I'm this is not imagination this
is not from a movie this is my own life huh
i don't feel good
what happened to a Texas guy he disappeared
to Texas is he still alive or dead anyway
go ahead nine no okay so the thought that
i don't feel good okay
that's involuntary you know why this depression
ghost he says don't feel good
nine is boredom the depression ghost
wait wait, is that my alarm
someone goes with her
videotape go videotape
that's not my alarm it's not um should I um
yeah I asked the question okay um I also have
a second question
oh wait here's the first one I have a question
about contemplation and illumination we have
to exercise our will to choose what we contemplate
but the illumination is done by our Buddha
nature is this correct repeat the question
please
we have to exercise our will to choose what
we contemplate but the illumination is done
by our Buddha nature is this correct that's
correct who asked Alta-D okay very good
that's how it works you have to say I want
to look at this
oh that's my alarm it was yours okay and then
and then naturally your prajna light will
illuminate it
okay yes okay Alta-D also has a second question
master this week I was reading Master XuanHua's
commentary on the vajra sutra he said that
we should constantly all day turn the light
and illuminate within even during other daily
activities is there a way to illuminate without
like illuminate while we work or walk around
or talk to people
you've well it's a process where when you
return the light to illuminate within refers to
a process you need to practice to be you know
in order to open your wisdom once you open
your wisdom then you can illuminate outside
okay so what happened to ordinary people is
they never learn to illuminate inside that's
why when they illuminate outside they cannot
see clearly because they are confused in order
for you to see clearly you need to remove
confusion in yourself first inside yourself
first before you can see clearly outside of
yourself so ordinary people their emphasis
is different they they are messed up they
mess up the order the order of things is that
you make sure you are clear-headed before
you look outside that's why we are you are
taught to illuminate inside return the light
and illuminate inside
yes this question is from Heidi master
which false thought which false thought is
easy to get rid of first thank you master
there's no easy thought that needs to get
rid of okay they all need to be removed whatever
the way that I will teach you is whatever
kinds of false thoughts that keep on arising
frequently okay those are the one you need
to focus on to remove otherwise they're the
errant thoughts that don't come back uh it's
just not something you need to worry about
okay good questions anything else
[question in Vietnamese]
Amituofo master, I have a question is this the
false thought arise is because of our discrimination
or it is on itself nature it is that way and
why is it that our prajna wisdom
why is it
go ahead why is it that our prajna
wisdom if we we are confused and false thinking
how is that cover up this prajna wisdom
okay and the question is not worth answering
because the more I answer such questions the
more you have questions okay that will lead
to nowhere it's not about recognizing the
the false thought how it came about is about
knowing what to do with it knowing recognizing
where it comes from doesn't matter is irrelevant
and that's what people spend their entire
lives doing chasing after knowledge why why
why? but they never learn how to get rid
of the false thoughts how to deal with the
false start they only want to know why they
arise it's like the same way asking why am
i hungry why am I depressed I can give you
one reason and then you ask another and you
ask another and ask another there's no end
to it that's why I don't answer such questions
that's why if you ask me such questions i
i can't answer you he asked me how do I put
an end to this particular thought that I can
teach you if that's not what you're looking
for you come to the wrong place I have no
interest in telling you and discussing you
the events of the world what's going on in your
head and why it's not enough time for that
there's no end to it you're so confused and
you want to know why am I confused instead
of learning how do I put an end to my confusion
because if you confuse I tell you why you
confuse it does not end your confusion
i can only I'm willing to tell you how to
put an end to your confusion what you need
to do put in your confusion I'm not willing
to discuss you why you're confused
because if I discuss it with you you ask more
questions which is has happened already because
my telling you why would not end your confusion
will only create more confusion for you that's
the truth this is why I don't indulge in explaining
to you why
it has never worked in the history of buddhism
the last 3000 years
what we focus on teaching you is what you
need to do to how
you go about putting an end to your confusion
putting an end to your false thoughts not
why you have false thoughts
[speak in Vietnamese]
master, our people people like me how can they know
about stopping the ego stop being the false
thought if I don't know about the fundamental
on where it comes from the source of it master
only taught us how to stop the thought but
it's only temporary I just want to completely
cut off all of the false thought false thought
from the source itself that's why I asked
the question where's the source of the false
thought came from
tim one talked to her where is she confused
hmm she's totally confused why
this is her particular problem she's always
had which you don't have
that's why I doubt that any of you will be
able to point out what her problem is
but give it a try what's her problem
go ahead Q&A, let me see your level of wisdom
here
very good she wants to do it her way
it's like a sick patient says I want to get
well but doctor you have to treat me my way
i have to agree to your treatment otherwise
I'm not willing to do it
you ask a surgeon you are sick you need to
be operated upon you ask the best surgeon
there is in the world would you come to him
and say I want you to operate on me but will you
do it my way please
you have to tell me exactly what you're gonna
do and I have to agree to everything you do
to me before I let you operate on me
you're an idiot how can you tell a surgeon
what to do what are you doing wasting time
the surgeon's time and tell him what to do
you want your life to be saved then you should
put your trust in him that you have faith
he can do a good job and save your skin you
don't believe him don't have to come to him
you're confused and you insist on doing things
your way because I can figure it out exactly
Q&A this is a problem with stupid people the
thing that can figure it out the reason you
call stupid is not me the Buddha calls you
stupid I simply repeat the words I'm not I'm
not I'm not adding any more spices on top
of it Buddhas call us stupid because we don't
know
what we want we don't know what to do and
we insist on having it our way
that's why it's called stupidity because you
insist on your stupid ways there's no way to
explain to you
and that's why you remain stupid lifetime
after lifetime of the lifetime because you're
so full of your stupid self
it's the ego who says do it my way do it my
way otherwise I won't believe
you [Speak in Vietnamese]
i apologize I think you mistaken my intention
i don't need the answer in that way I just
wanted to understand is that I've heard from
the perfect enlightenment sutra that a human
we have three doubts and I just regurgitate
the verse and I just wanna understand the
original source of my confusion the false
thought where that where do they come from
but if I offended you I apologize sincerely
she doesn't get it, does she? I tried to tell
her that if I explain to you why it will not
end your doubts and your questioning you keep
on asking why if you explain that to me why
do you say that and I explained I said that
because of this and he said why do you say
that you keep on asking and asking and asking
there's no end to it because your stupid mind
is Changing looking for an answer it's not
the way to solve your stupidity
that's why that's why I don't answer I don't
answer because it will not put an end to your
suffering an end to your questioning because
you want to know more and more here's what
happens let me paint it for you in a simple
way for you the problem you have is here i
can explain to you why the cause for that
and then you understand the cause and then
next you say why was this the cause of it
i explained to you again I'll give you another
reason and then you say okay I understand
i agree with you can you tell me why this
is a reason and on and on and on and on there's
no end to it that's why we don't engage in
doing those things that will not put an end
to your
lack of clarity
i think I make myself pretty clear but she
doesn't seem to get it okay I'm afraid I cannot
help answer your questions nothing personal
go ahead eight from Lio how can we get rid
of false thoughts is there a difference between
the way of eliminating false thoughts when
it's involuntary or voluntary when I meditate
i try to recite the Buddhist name constantly
but most of the time I'm interrupted by false
thoughts clearly I have intention to focus
on reciting but out of nowhere involuntarily
I'm on the false thought yes it's just a simple
fact there's a false thought you will arise
okay when I discern voluntary versus involuntary
involuntary is for the advanced levels okay
at your level Lio, you don't need to
worry about involuntary voluntary when I explain
involuntary is in order to tell you right
now there's a reason for that is in order
to tell you that it doesn't matter you understand
or not okay if you understand I give you an
example of depression the depression ghost
it says few bad they plant the thought in your
head okay and you most for most people they
think it's their thoughts like people like
Daniel who says I don't feel good I feel depressed
okay he never realizes that it's not his thought
that heart is planted in his head by depression
ghost that's the example I gave okay so does
it matter if I point out to you that's depression
ghost right there it's doing it to you and
then he says let me you know let me worry
about the depression ghost but you don't realize
it's more depression ghost so to worry about
the cause but that way it's not going to solve
the problem so what do we teach you at your
level Lio is not worried about voluntary
and involuntary yet at higher level you'll
be taught how to handle it lower level right
now what you do is you learn to resist the
temptation to follow to think about it that's
all if for example you talk about it's hot
right now your body feels hot the thought
is a natural thought it's reaction to the
natural phenomena around you the environment
is hot therefore your body feels hot so therefore
you aware and the thought of being hot is
naturally generated okay that's involuntary
involuntary however for ordinary people which
they used to they said it's so hot my god
i would love to have some gelato I will have
i love to have some watermelon that's voluntary
so all you're doing right now is not to think
about it that's all and that's how you first must
learn must do in order to learn how to deal
with the false thoughts it's not understanding
it's not understanding why but it is you need
to first start do that and then you begin
to understand why you need to do that okay
and then you can be taught but there are a
bunch of people who would come to my temple
and say could you explain to me why I need
to understand I looked at them and say you
can't understand now I explained to you you
can't handle it
that's why I don't explain to you
it's not I cannot I can but I refuse to because
you can't handle it
you remember that movie
justice for all you remember that movie huh
and so you see
there's no need for you to understand too
much all you need to do right now Lio okay
is one thing do one thing instead of trying
to understand why just need to look at yourself
and says I will refrain myself from pursuing
those thoughts if it's hot the thought arises
i want to have some ice cream some watermelon
cut it out you stop right there don't generate
another thought don't generate a second thought
okay yeah and then next time around when it's
hot you won't even generate the thought of
gelato or ice cream or a drink or whatever
then that's how you break it you break it
from at this stage here stop and stop them
as thought number three thought number one is
it's hot thought number two is I want something
cool okay number three is I want some gelato
for example you stop at number three as soon
you aware of thought number two you start number
three okay and that's how you meditate that's
all you need to do know right now you can
do that you make it you don't need to understand
uh anything you just need to know what to
do understanding is not gonna help you this
guy comes to my temple trying to understand
everything and it's letting leading him nowhere
that's perfectly okay
okay those of you who have been with me who
are certified to have reached levels of wisdom
is because you successfully
did what I told you to do that's all but
people like him like her insist on I want
to know I want to understand good luck I can
answer you every now and then but I'm not
interested in answering you all the time sometimes
i answer sometimes I don't answer you see
the pattern it's so fun I answer to have a
laugh but when it's useless I won't even get
a laugh out of it I won't answer this is a
waste of time knowledge is not going to help
you
knowledge you can pick it up from a book you
don't need me why you come to my temple asking
for knowledge I am only willing to help you
put an end to your false thinking not to know
you want to know go somewhere else Q&A go
ahead
[Unintelligible question]
okay now you talked about you now you brought
it up depression is a very difficult thing
to learn to deal with at lower levels like these
people who would like to know uh they are
totally helpless nothing they can do okay
when they go into the depression mode that's
it they're dead meat they use totally useless
okay there's no talking to them okay at your
level on your particular level you begin to
be taught and when you talk you understand
that's why I would spend time explaining to
you to begin to explain to you a little bit
because you that knowledge will be helpful
to you in your dealing with the depression
but low-level people like you in particular
I'm talking very personal now I'm talking
about you you you you I'm not talking theory
at all because I know what you're capable
of doing
okay in your particular level you'll be taught
at a very superficial level for you to see
to see how to cope with it but it's very
involved you need to improve a lot more before
you're able to be totally out of the woods
is that complicated to imagine for me to explain
to you how to deal depression at his level
at her level it's like I would take me 10
years to describe to you and I still no end
to it it's useless okay at your level similarly
i could also spend a lot of time explaining
to you as well okay but it's useless as well
the difference between you and them is that
you when I explain now you can understand
so I will start explaining to you things you
can do
okay whereas at their low levels I don't bother
explaining to them because if I explain to
them they still can't do it it's useless for
me to spend time explaining to these people
okay but for you I waited until you get to
this stage here and we started explaining
to you how to handle your depression and you're
able to snap out of it on your own without
any help their levels is totally helpless
they cannot do anything without our help good
luck they think they can do something about
it let them try until the day they die they
will not be able to I know how strong they
are okay I know I know how tough the problem
is because I was severely depressed myself
i went through all these phases myself
she depressed I see the depression I'm not
even teaching you how to deal with it yet
that's how difficult it is okay so at each
level
you will be taught how to handle it
but no more than that because if your elementary
school what am I doing explain to you uh the
course work of a PhD level it's useless to
you
it's useless knowledge okay
the good news is that when you get the level
where you are Qun okay and when you get higher
you'll be better be able to learn how to be
in control until then the people below you
they need help desperately not much we not
much they can do themselves that's the way
it is. unless they drug themselves up unless
they're locked up it's not a whole lot they
can do for themselves
that's the way it is this is why they need
people like shrink and the therapists and so
forth because they need some outside input
in order to better cope with it if they think
they can figure it out themselves they can't
they need drugs they need medication they
need some outside help because explaining
to them is not going to help them solve the
problem that's how far depression is concerned
but you we can begin to teach you how to handle
it but it's nothing yet there's still a lot
more you need to learn before you can be on
your own that's how difficult it is okay because
these beings they plant thoughts in your head
it's nothing you can do about it they're that
powerful
yes eight um masters some of us have been
here for a while and if we still don't understand
why if we still don't understand we're still
looking at it from the wrong perspective is
it because we're lacking blessings
yes you're lacking blessings and because
they are a lot stronger than you are
the enemy's stronger you need help that's
all you have to become stronger before you
can handle them it's that simple
and there's a fallacy in people thinking they
can handle it they can figure it out the proof
is that look at all the depressed people they're
depressed because they can't figure it out
they can't figure out this one thing called
depression which is nothing yet compared to
the rest of their confusions they're depressed
they manic they can't even figure out how
to handle their manic depression okay and
now they're paranoid as well okay and all
these problems they have and I'm just bringing
brought out one problem the depression they
can't even handle it let alone the other things
look at the boy one look at him you tell he's
depressed right away he says I am not feeling
good leave me alone
don't touch me
that woman the same thing look at her I'm
depressed don't you dare look at me
this guy is different he's depressed they
said I don't feel good but I don't talk about it
I'm a professional I'm not supposed to be
depressed I'm depressed like hell so I can't
talk about it
yes you're supposed to help depress people
you're so damn depressed you can't help people
I'm telling you at lower levels you need help
it's nothing you can do that's how difficult
it is you cannot figure it out at higher levels
i can teach you so much it's still so much
more you need to learn before you can handle
it before you can be on your own only
only handful people I know can handle it can
be taught I haven't been able to teach them
yet
because the time is not right yet
that's how difficult it is but they'll be
out of the woods you won't you think you can
handle it good luck
I'm out of the woods okay
i went through all these levels of attacks
you haven't how do you know could you can't
even tell how they manipulate you
okay so when false thoughts going back to slide
192 okay when you use prajna wisdom to
contemplate illuminate that's what you do
naturally with your prajna wisdom you don't
have to think about it if you focus on something
using your past your mind and there's a way
to do that I'm not teaching you okay because
you're too stupid to be able to do it okay
but when you reach a certain level you'll
be taught how to use a practice quantum contemplation
okay I'm looking at you spy number one you
too stupid to be taught how to do prajna
contemplation
okay but when you do that when you do it you
naturally will contemplate illuminate naturally
and when that happens
in a split second all false thoughts would
stop that is exactly what happens
what Master HuiNeng did
here he says if you reach this level this
point here this is what's going to happen
and this is important for you to hear about
this because when you're there then you know
exactly this is the case
okay so it means that you may have thoughts
of depression you may have thoughts of all
sorts of thoughts in your head
if you're able to wield your prajna wisdom
to contemplate illuminate instantaneously
everything stops
all the false thoughts will end will disappear
will dissipate instantaneously you don't need
to know why
you only need to be told how
who cares why
you have a lot of garbage in your house you
say why do I have so much garbage wouldn't
you rather know how do I get rid of my garbage
so that I have a clean house how does understanding
why I have so much garbage gonna help you
and for those of you okay do not make the
same mistake do not ever come to learn about
prajna and insist on your way you should
be so grateful I tell you what to do you do
it you understand you don't do it it's your
life
he's been here for a year and a half he said
I'm gonna do it my way what do we care how
does it help your depression you'll never
help your depression
and that's a problem with people in the world
i said I want to do it my way I figure it
out good luck there're plenty people who are smarter
than you they are therapists they're professors
they're researchers they have yet to figure
out how to deal with depression because they
don't know enough about depression how to
put an end to it you keep on looking for tricks
here and there
that's all that's why they will never be able
to do it because they solve the the problem
resolution is wrong
he cannot solve the depression problems like
that okay you cannot solve it by looking at
symptoms you have to look at how to cut off
the root of all these false thoughts and he
just described to you right here that moment
it happened it will happen and you recognize
oh I know about this before okay so you believe
this okay then you should do what you told
and you should be so grateful you told about
these secrets to bring you to this point you're
not grateful good luck you figure it out yourself
what is it to me I don't need to help you
it's your life
next 193 if you recognize your self-nature
in a single moment of enlightenment you will
arrive the stage of Buddha this is referred
to the fact that Chan school says see your
nature and accomplish Buddhahood this is what
he's referring to however it is a little bit
misleading okay what he said is a lot more
accurate he says in a single moment of enlightenment
you will arrive at a stage of a Buddha the
ground of a Buddha doesn't mean you're a Buddha
so that's why for the Chan school especially
Zen school to say see your nature and accomplish
and become a Buddha is misleading to me i
don't like to talk like that you understand
when you see your nature doesn't mean you're
Buddha yet you're on the Buddha ground you
arrive at the ground of the Buddha it's not
a stage of the Buddha Di here the ground okay
Change it this is wrong
when I first explained it okay I didn't dare
Change much okay now I'm a lot more blunt
okay I have no time to waste okay I don't
want to waste your time nor my time so what
he means here is very precise he says you
are no Buddha you only
in the neighborhood of Buddhas that's all
you are member of a very exclusive club called
called ground of a Buddha but you are no Buddha
don't be so full of yourself
again fixed here the stage of the Buddha
the Buddha ground not the ground of the Buddha
and it arrived at the Buddha ground this is
very precise Master HuiNeng is very very
precise he doesn't mince words
see Fo Di it's Buddha ground it's not ground of
Buddha even
fix it
go ahead eight from Diego master I wanted
to do it my way until one day I heard you
speaking about you don't know where to see
from the sixth patriarch that really moved
me because all my life I've been looking but
in all honestly I didn't know where to see
and I'm so grateful to you master because
now I know where I know I where I can see
and is following the instructions of master
YongHua the great good knowing advisor amituofo
that's why you need prajna to be able to
look at the problem when you have depression
yourself you have no prajna wisdom that's
why you look at it you cannot see how to fix
it and each one of you is different
therefore you need you need depression to
look at you long enough to be able to illuminate
everything and then come up with a solution
what happened is that unless you have prajna
wisdom you cannot fix the problem that is
why even fourth stage arhats cannot fix the depression
problem they cannot see how the what the problem
really is they need practical light practical
wisdom
i repeat four says arhats have no production
wisdom yet they cannot see how to fix it but
they can be taught they they can begin to
be taught as part of the progression towards
opening the wisdom and so in you know in other
words at the high level or four stage or higher
okay when they have depression actually that
helps them progress even quicker the reason
i don't tell people is because I wait for
those high level people to be attacked then
i show them it's a lot faster
okay can we go back to the slideshow
where were we
which slide number were we at
192 193 okay so uh
if you recognize your self-nature meaning you
being able to see your Buddha nature that
moment right there at very single moment that
very moment right there you will arrive at
the Buddha ground you don't accomplish Buddhahood
okay bolongni that's cut it out okay I want
you generation for future generations you
special English Chan teachers in the future
or you teaching your own languages do not
ever use accomplished Buddhahood that is what
the Chinese use some of the uh especially
the Japanese they are they are rampant with
such expression okay that's wrong you're not
a Buddha not at all you're far from being
a Buddha even Master HuiNeng are so far from
being a Buddha and you you think you're close
dream on so when you Shi Zi Xing when
you recognize yourself nature
at that moment at that moment enlightenment
okay you will arrive at Buddha ground that's
all it is
okay I'm telling you this because in the future
i want you lay people or left home people
who hear people use the word Cheng Fo accomplish
Buddhahood see your nature accomplish Buddhahood
run okay they are sales people there's no
such a thing it's contrary to what Master HuiNeng
teaches
okay he's
i don't know for sure but I feel because I've
listened to many of the great patriarchs i
feel he's like a Buddha already I don't never
met anyone who has the kind of precision and
the power he has when he teaches and he's
so precise here okay
go ahead Q&A
[Unintelligible question]
he's different Shakyamuni Buddha became a Buddha
then under the bodhi tree he's different from
us we are no Buddhas yet this is special case
he accomplished Buddhahood that's why he became
a Buddha that's why we call him Buddha but
we never can call ourselves Buddha even though
we become enlightened we cannot we are not
Buddhas we cannot call ourselves Buddhas
that's all okay
and so to say accomplish Buddhahood is misleading
is overselling our process and I don't like
it don't you dare talk like that okay I will
slap you in the face
who are you trying to sell who are you trying
to con 194 good knowing advisor when you contemplate
and illuminate with the wisdom which brightly
penetrates within and with how you recognize
your original mind
[Read sutra text in Chinese]
okay I will Change the text a little bit here
because I don't like it the way that these
people did and they combined concepts because
they don't understand what he's trying to
teach them at least not as well as I do
let me explain to you and be prepared to fix
this good knowing advisor when you contemplate
illuminate with wisdom okay
that's correct that's he's referring to the
Guan Zhao the Zhi Hui Guan Zhao that we talked
about earlier when you contemplate illuminate
okay when you do that then inside and outside
everything is clear thoroughly that's what
this phrase means it has nothing to do with brightly
penetrates okay
okay it's not necessary this is not a good
way to translate when you use when you use
your
wisdom when you use wisdom Change it the Chinese
is very very precise he does not he does not
waste a single Chinese character in his instructions
when you contemplate with your wisdom you
contemplate and illuminate with the wisdom
oh that's what it has right here okay comma
then
inside and outside everything is clear and
penetrating
Ming Che meaning you can see clearly through nothing
can stop you nothing whatsoever
it's very powerful statement if you use your wisdom
to contemplate illuminate okay you can see
everything clearly without obstruction inside
and outside
Shi Zi Ben Xin you uh
thus recognize your original mind
okay Change it
for the commentary
so far so good let me explain to you
you
okay let me elaborate for you
because
he's very precise okay he uses the words for
a reason that's why we don't want to mess
with it you don't need to combine it to make
it more fluid and whatever no no no here is
where it says this is what I mean okay there's
no need to be literary here at all can you
shrink this so that it belongs to the frame
the line here Buddha mind here that's outside
of the frame
shrink its size
there
you go thank you okay let me explain it for
you okay
remember earlier someone asked me uh how do
i uh look outside and this is the answer right
here okay when I explain I want to give the
answer it's consistent with this now when
i said if you want to look outside okay then
you must learn to look inside first because
until inside is clear outside cannot be clear
okay this is what worldly people don't realize
this is what the monks and nuns don't realize
because they're not there yet and they or
they don't know how to help people get there
yet okay
so when you use your prajna wisdom to illuminate
okay the wisdom here refers to your prajna
wisdom uh but to contemplate illuminate okay
then it doesn't matter whether you look at
yourself or you look at outside
okay when you do that whether you look at
yourself okay then you can see how the depression
ghost is attacking you for example
in theory or you look at outside in theory
you can see how they are attacking someone
else in theory only okay that's what he's
saying okay so inside and outside everything
you look at is clear
Ming Che, Ming is clear you understand clearly
Che is thoroughly
okay and I Change it to penetrating because
it's not about clear thoroughly I want to
separate clear and thorough clear refers to
the fact nothing can be hidden from your prajna
wisdom your Buddha wisdom nothing can escape
that light penetrating okay refers to the
fact that you can look at the whole thing
instead of partial
nothing can stop you
okay you thus recognize your original mind
why because when you're able to see inside
and outside clear everything is clear and
penetrating and then you realize that's how
your original mind really functions how your
original mind can operate can do for you
okay yes eight from Jesus should it should
not it be penetrated instead of penetrating
penetrated is okay penetrating is uh is maybe
a little bit of a sales pitch
but it's the same concept
penetrated
i prefer penetrating it's more active
okay you thus recognize your original mind
then you then here refers to that you are
able to see the extent of your Buddha mind
how far it can go how you can depend on it
to understand without having anyone to tell
you
because this is the kind of knowledge you
have to develop yourself no one can tell you
this is the kind of wisdom that you must unfold
yourself so that you understand yourself
without needing any help from anyone so that's
why in order for you to get here knowledge
is not going to help you you need to know
how to get here
not why
all right next 196. the recognition of your original
mind is the original liberation the attainable
liberation of samadhi is no thought
[Read sutra text in Chinese]
very good okay now he made the connection
that's not clear for most Chan masters okay
this is this is uh his superior wisdom
that we don't normally have what is he talking
about he's saying the recognition your original
mind is the original liberation is the what
he's talking about is that once you can recognize
your Buddha mind your inherent Buddha mind
your fundamental Buddha mind that is your
natural state of liberation okay your original
your fundamental state of liberation meaning
what when you see that what does it mean to
you when you're able to see original mind
you have no more suffering
all sufferings will vanish
that's called liberation liberation is a state
of absence of suffering you liberated from
suffering so that's why originally Buddhas
have now there's a there's an ant that climbs
on my eyeglasses okay the Buddha originally
Buddhas have no suffering whatsoever so you
come home to your own original Buddha nature
okay when you see a Buddha nature you in the
bull in the Buddha ground therefore at that
moment right there all sufferings cease you
are liberated that's the fundamental liberation
of Buddha ground
okay and furthermore he gave us more details
on liberation how do you attain this liberation
another way to look at this liberation he
says is how you achieve this liberation is
you enter the prajna samadhi so until you're
able to enter prajna samadhi you don't know
what this Buddha liberation is it's not knowledge
you have to enter that samadhi
now you go back to the same concept why we
don't want to explain to you too much because
you cannot explain to you what is this prajna
samadhi
we all need to bring you there tell you how
to get there that's all and if you're not
willing to cross your legs and endure the leg
pains why should I tell you about this prajna
samadhi how to get there you got to be kidding
me you can't even handle one hour half an
hour of leg pains and I can't take this is too
much pain it's too much suffering
just tell me quickly how can I enter this prajna
samadhi
happy your way right good luck you want to
be Catholic way good luck man go ahead Q&A
this is Buddha ground when you're there you
know the wood through the ground is not where
you stand how's that for definition
that helps right you're nowhere near it by
the way and for these people
they're like light years away yes nine master
it's amazing to think that at some point we
will be somewhere where there's absolutely
no more suffering because all we do in this
world is just suffer the Buddhas the bodhisattvas
can instantaneously put an end to their suffering
that's why they no longer are afraid of suffering
why do you think the Buddhists come to our
world and the bodhisattva comes to our world
if suffering bothers them they would not come
to our world does it make sense
they're not stupid
we are stupid they're not
so they come to our world to suffer with us
in order to help us it's called Tong Shi
in order to help people who are suffering
they choose to suffer the best way for them
to help the people who are suffering is they
suffer along with them in order to help people
who are severely depressed they need to be
severely depressed themselves
severely manic themselves severely paranoid
themselves it's called Tong Shi doing same work
that's a bodhisattva's work they're not
afraid of it they said you are suffering you
have cancer I have cancer with you that's
what Master XuanHua did okay
I'm not afraid your cancer you were dying
cancer I would take on it on on my body so
that you free from your suffering I suffer
on your behalf they're not afraid of suffering
at all
because
they can enter this prajna samadhi and free
from it all however they choose not to they
choose to suffer in order to help you to help
us
that's why they're different from us you run
away from suffering you bitch and moan
it's too much I'm too depressed I'm so bad
i don't feel good they say give it to me give
me your pain give me your suffering I'm
not afraid of it I can carry you on my back
that's Master XuanHua for you
okay I haven't met anyone like that he's the
only one I met alive who's like that I tell
you no one else I've met is like that not
second patriarch no one else no one comes
near his level
they attained liberation and prajna samadhi
so that state liberation of all suffering
is prajna samadhi meaning they can handle
it they can enter any time they they want
to but they choose not to
and that is that state of no thought you want
to be free from suffering you want to be free
from depression pay attention you enter this
branch of and you have no thought so see how
it makes sense if you depression is a form
of I don't feel good that's hard I don't feel
good you enter prajna samadhi that thought
is no longer so depression is
what do you want out of life more more temples
more money more recognition and you're depressed
like hell
so confused yes nine. master, is there a cultivation
level where we can reach this or this is way
beyond that of course many people can reach
it already
when I explained this to four years ago very
if only a handful of people could now it is
a lot so I don't I don't brag
i talk about it because others have reached
this Buddha ground already 198 what is meant
by no thought no thought means to view all
dharma of the mind undefiled by attachment
the function pervades all places but is nowhere
attached
[Read sutra text in Chinese]
okay so he explains further what is this no
thought samadhi
i have an ant that dances in front of my
eyes
no thought means to view all dharma through
the mind undefiled by attachment it's right
there is definition of no thoughts to view
meaning to perceive to look at to smell you
smell the fragrance of Chanel number five
and you say this looks like Chanel number five
okay I don't know why people seeing it and
why they pay so much for it can you believe
how much you're paying for something poison
you know why would you put poison on your
skin a stupid marketing thing
doesn't even bother you sir you you want to
buy some nice perfume for your girlfriend
and the saleswoman says uh can I recommend
some poison I just say what can I recommend
some poison for your wife
i was shocked I heard about the names they
chose you girls don't seem to be bothered
by the for me and say oh wow it gives me ideas
you know yes sir actually now the light goes
up oh wow no um perfumes at all because it
gives me allergies um but my question is um
you have a lot of problems son
uh my question would be um how do I let's
say stop depression how would I do that
you can't
you better learn Chan that's all it's a very
simple answer learn Chan and shut up
no thought okay to view all dharma so look
view all dharmas means that look at everything
okay hear everything taste everything with
the mind undefiled by attachment okay when
you get in contact with things you are not
giving rise to a thought of attachment precisely
okay attachment here refers to a thought of
being attached to for example you say oh i
like this I like to have more of this that's a attachment
yes okay it's perfectly okay to say this is
nice because your body enjoys it your taste
buds approves of it okay uh that is is not
attachment it's called being alive but for
you to say can I have three scoops of gelato
I'm afraid that two is not enough
what you want to go to have some gelato
after
okay that is attachment the thought that arises
can I can I okay i'd like okay that's an attachment
okay
and and and that's why the Chinese this is
very famous expression you keep on hearing
about it over and over again until someday
it will it will click in you it says
Yan Guan Sheng Se Nei Wu You
when the eyes contemplate the sound the form
inside there's nothing when you hear a sound
when you see a form okay inside there's nothing
what does it mean
how can there be nothing I don't know why
his disciples my show disciples or the Chinese
never asked that we American would ask immediately
what do you mean nothing I mean like I look
at that as nothing inside then what am I how
can I see anything if it's nothing I'm seeing
what is the matter these Chinese people they
never dare ask questions and when they ask
questions only stupid questions
yeah what does it mean is not inside there's
nothing the the eyes contemplate the sound
the form inside is nothing yes Q&A
it says You here You what
the translation in English doesn't do justice
Nei Wu You
You here is to have have what
there is nothing inside
if there is nothing inside how can you see
anything
might as well be invisible might as well
be hallucination
huh what is he talking about yes sir could
he be talking about emptiness when you look
at something or even
if it's emptiness then how can you see anything
you know and you know that that ant is just
saying give me the earth says could you stop
moving please
yes one
so you see clearly when the ant the ant is
moving clearly I'm not seeing nothing inside
there's something moving
six
[Master XianChi speak in Vietnamese]
amituofo master, when the six sense perceives
the six dust our mind do not react to such
things as false love or attachment no love
or hate or discrimination like we hear people
arguing we ourselves don't get afflicted it's
just like the mirror um we don't give rise
to thought of discrimination just like but
we're not a rock
okay
anyone else want to try yes eight
so like when you're angry you have this tension
inside of you it's amazing to me how ants
live they pace back and forth on my eyeglass
lenses for no real purpose
they clearly have no attachment whatsoever
yes eight so like when you're angry you have
this tension or pressure inside of you when
you contemplate and illuminate it that pressure
disappears that energy disappears and then
and then it becomes empty is that okay to
express it in that way no let me explain to
you what it means okay when you see something
you hear a sound or form inside
there is nothing okay
inside there is nothing inside there is nothing
okay not nothing inside and it's just too
abbreviated when the ears hear the dust and
the phenomena the mind does not know
okay ears hear the dust and the phenomena
okay can you Change it please this translation
is important I don't know why his uh disciples
master XuanHua's disciples will never ask him that's
why I have to explain it for you
got that
okay goodbye hope you die
okay so uh
what he's saying here uh he's saying here
that with your eyes we we perceive
the word with our eyes hey it's still here
that's another one there you go
i hate ants
so attached
what do you want number five
master this room um right there's the things
that when we you know we the Daoist we like
to burn those paper money and paper clothes
and paper I don't know for the ancestor if
we do that does it cause any damage from them
to come down does this cause any damage for
them to come down it does yes you got to tell
my mom master kind of damage I don't know air
pollution
and they come down they suffer so this is
does it do anything bad to them for real master
does it they have to inhale a lot of polluted
air probably live in Beijing or something
what about that pureland blessing their rebirth
blessing they are Daoist they don't they don't deserve
to go to the pureland and what are you talking about
the Daoist we don't want we don't want Daoists
said at least amitabha Buddha have
standards he doesn't just take anyone you
think he's like a Buddha and he should see
i take you Daoist too wow he's not that desperate
okay
forms and sound
sound and forms eyes contemplate sound and
forms outside there's nothing inside the ears
hear the dusts and phenomena let me fix it
for you oh god
you wanna do your way uh
do
it
phenomenal
okay I explained to you my god this English
killed me
the eyes when with your sense organ especially
your eyes when you
see the sounds contemplate the sound uh
not view
contemplate
okay and that's why I asked you a trick question
no one caught it okay when the eyes see the
sound and forms outside which is totally incorrect
eyes cannot see the sound the eyes can contemplate
the sound and forms outside is that clear
so the the Chinese very precise
i threw at you none of you pay
attention because none of you really uh understand
Chinese and the Chinese are so in awe with
my Chinese which they should never be that
they don't dare question my translation anymore
okay the eyes can contemplate the sound and
the forms on the outside nothing inside there's
nothing inside meaning that inside there's
no attachment being formed for example they
hear
good music you know they hear a uh o fortuna
anyone likes that
that's the very famous and the famous choir
o fortuna
i do it offline because this is all copyrighted
o fortuna okay we send you the links later
to all the branch temples meaning all three
branch temples okay and for you to go on online
look at what the o fortuna that sound the
sound of the choir great sound of the choirs
or the forms outside the side the eyes contemplate
the objects outside the forms okay there's
no attachment being formed inside of you that
it also includes rejection as well right rejection
is just the opposite of attachment right rejection
is attachment too because rejection is attachment
to the opposite
is that clear so inside there is no attachment
whatsoever or rejections is that clear so
we do inside we don't say oh he's Catholic
therefore let's ignore him we simply say there's
nothing there it's even more insulting when
you think about it just kidding okay you see
that inside there's no attachment when the
ears hear okay the dusts and phenomena the
mind does not know so for example when you
listen to your ear organ and whatever it is
that produces sound okay or any sort of
vocal things you can hear it's vocal or sound
phenomena the dust is what you can associate
okay with the sensor organs phenomena something
you don't necessarily have a clear clue as
what they are just see it just happen outside
the same thing still outside the mind does
not know
this is important why is the difference between
nothing inside versus the mind does not know
if you can answer this I will give you gelato
right now today
interested? hey woman spy number one
are you interested
Catholic go ahead you answer right I will
pay for gelato today up to five dollars not
eight uh let me try so um
maybe whatever you see or any any phenomena
you see just um uh you may not comprehend
so far so close and yet so far away anyone
yes old monk say it right I will pay for
gelato
because he says I don't care he says I'm above
gelato because the mind is empty when something
happened my my reflected like a mirror reflects
so it means something happened it means formed
my empty so something empty though like that
one record and I know that will quickly reunite
no gelato anyone else this is so precise
hey the other Vietnamese
you have the answer master Z he's the last
Vietnamese alive what does it mean explain
mind does not know Xin Bu Zhi what does it
mean
the two you can discuss I allow the two abbots
to join forces go ahead you can speak together
yes go ahead six but because
the mind [Master XianChi speak in Vietnamese]
Master Z speak up
don't let me down
the mind does not know what does what does
it mean the mind does not know how can you
hear the dust and the mind does not know how
is it possible
not bad still Vietnamese okay anyone else
let's try the Mexican Catholic Vietnamese
Buddhist failed yes maybe you're not grasping
no yeah the last Vietnamese in the block master
does that mean that that person is deaf it's
definitely this guy is brutal he says [Laughter]
when I hear something okay I would take a
screwdriver and stick it in my ear so that
i go deaf
see I I started at the abbot level right
away I don't bother talking to you don't bother
you won't know
see you abbott still need me I can't retire
yet
so much work left okay vice abbots anyone
would like to say you low level forget it
i don't waste my time well anyone would like
to try okay let me explain to you okay this
is very important this is so important okay
when the ears hear the dust and the phenomena
okay the mind does not know here it refers
to the mind what does a mind do it
thinks
what kind of thinking does it do
what does a mind think I told you don't raise
your what does a mind think of
huh
it thinks Q&A
no I told you not to raise your hands
it thinks it knows
there's no knowledge
you are still attached to knowledge there's
no knowledge
nothing inside here refers to no attachment
is formed that's easy to understand what your
problem and his problem in Korea is that
you are both still attached to knowledge
do you think knowledge is important
that's your problem there's no knowledge
the low-level people they think they need
to know they need to understand they need
to have knowledge because they're confused
you are still attached to that concept that's
why you cannot answer this that's why you
don't know Xin Bu Zhi the mind does not know
the mind has no knowledge
the mind is no longer attached to knowledge
isn't that right do you attach to your knowledge
[Master XianChi speak in Vietnamese]
you are referring to nothing inside, you are not referring to mind not know
why do the Chinese say Nei Wu You and Xin Bu Zhi
because they're two different things Nei Wu You
here is low level where you are you got it
but a high level Xin Bu Zhi you are not there
yet he's not there yet in Korea
i have proof you cannot you cannot understand
this when you're there you understand what
i mean you still disagree with me you still
don't understand he still does not get it
because you deep down you are attached to
knowledge
you tell yourself how can master know so much
i know nothing
before I come here I don't know what I'm going
to be talking about I want to talk because
of you because of her because of these idiots
without you I don't know what to talk
about every time I prepare for lecture you
know what I do I look at the screen my mind
goes lying as a what should I talk about today
and if I don't deliver today they will leave
me and go to DRBA temples that's how i
know there's constant pressure every day every
time every weekend you know I have spies coming
in here and says see let's see what else he's
got to give us today he doesn't give it to
me I leave and for 15 years he's been coming
in my temple and he says the same attitude
okay what have you got for me if you don't
give me something knowledge some new knowledge
i will leave
right huh spy number one huh master doesn't
know anything why should I come right
see he still doesn't get it
Z do you get it
see he's thinking he's thinking he's thinking
no attached to knowledge Zhi here is knowledge
no he doesn't get it I'm very specific the
mind has no knowledge
only stupid people ask to know why ask for
knowledge if you get a high level like a little
bit higher than yours they have no more knowledge
the first level is Nei Wu You which is your level
you have no attachment you can let go easily
but your mind used to seeking knowledge that's
where you are right now that's why you are
where you are right now the Chinese are very precise
they never if it's not it's not for a reason
they would not bother composing these this
couplet okay Yan as opposed to ear okay
eye is opposed to ear Guan is supposed to Ting
okay because basically it's all outside outside
knowledge is it clear it is so precise it's
so beautiful everything it makes sense one
is inside this requires wisdom okay Sheng
here is is is the the uh the physical event
here is all sorts of physical events okay
that pertains to knowledge so here refers
to form okay it's low level you have attachments
at the sound and the form high level you attach
to the Chen and the Shi the dust and the
phenomena and the mind okay is no longer concerned
with such knowledge
you're not there yet don't bother raising
your hands I'm not going to entertain your
thoughts I'm way beyond beyond my my time
time slot yes eight from Jane Xin Bu Zhi should
it be translated to mind does not know
uh is that what you wrote down right there
mind not know mind does not know
this is my Vietnamese English you don't like
it tough luck
okay I can't believe these Chinese people
how do you how dare you question my Vietnamese
English you at best English
different levels of wisdom
you don't understand that's why you don't
get it yet he doesn't understand in Korea
either that's why you still need me I'm hoping
you understand so that I can retire don't
think I don't want you to know I want you
to know but you're not there yet
you don't get it yet someday you will but
there's a reason why they have two of them
there's a couplet here this is low level where
you are you understand here you don't understand
that's the nature of your ignorance and his
ignorance
you don't mess with these Chan people they
look at you and they ask you I ask you a question
okay and now you understand why these people
never asked master XuanHua if I were there
i would ask him master why is there Nei Wu You and
and Xin Bu Zhi why muscle why don't
simply say uh combine everything into one
sentence and then they yo they're totally
different
that's why there must be two sentences one
is the first level and next is
for high levels okay we stop here today thank
you everyone we're over time way over time
[Audience Clap]